[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的。
This is CS50, and this is finally week 6.
这是 CS50，终于到了第 6 周。
And this is that week we promised, wherein we finally
而这正是我们承诺的那一周，我们将最终
transition from C, this lower-level older language via which we explored
从 C 语言过渡，这种低级、古老的语言，我们通过它来探索
memory and how really computers work underneath the hood,
内存以及计算机在底层是如何工作的，
to what's now called Python, which is a more modern, higher-level language,
到如今被称为 Python 的语言，它是一种更现代、更高级的语言，
whereby we're still going to be able to solve the same types of problems.
我们将仍然能够解决相同类型的问题。
But it's going to suddenly start to get much, much easier because what
但是它会突然变得容易得多，因为 Python
Python offers, as do higher-level languages more generally,
提供的，正如更高级的语言所提供的一样，
are what we might describe as abstractions
就是我们可能描述的抽象
over the very low-level ideas that you've been implementing in sections
在你们一直在各个部分中实现的非常低级的概念之上
and problem sets and so much more.
以及习题集等等。
But recall from week 0, where we began.
但是回忆一下第 0 周，我们开始的地方。
This was our simplest of programs that just printed "hello, world."
这是我们最简单的程序，它只打印了“hello, world”。
Things escalated quickly thereafter in week 1,
随后，在第 1 周，事情迅速升级，
where, suddenly, we had all of this new syntax.
突然间，我们有了所有这些新的语法。
But the idea was still the same of just printing out "hello, world."
但想法仍然是一样的，就是打印出“hello, world”。
Well, as of today, a lot of that distraction,
嗯，从今天开始，很多这种干扰，
a lot of the visual distraction, goes away entirely
很多视觉上的干扰，完全消失了
such that what used to be this in C will now be quite simply this in Python.
这样，在 C 语言中曾经是这样的，现在在 Python 中就变成了这样。
And that's a bit of a head fake in that we're
这有点像是障眼法，因为我们
going to see some other fancier features of Python.
将会看到 Python 语言中的一些更花哨的功能。
But you'll find that Python's popularity in large part
但你会发现，Python 的流行程度在很大程度上
derives from just how relatively readable it is
源于它相对容易读懂
and also, as we'll ultimately see, just how exciting
以及，正如我们最终将会看到的那样，它有多么令人兴奋
and filled the ecosystem among Python programmers.
并且在 Python 程序员之间充满活力。
That is to say there's a lot more libraries.
也就是说，有更多的库。
There's a lot more problems that people have solved in Python
人们用 Python 解决了很多问题
that you can now incorporate into your own programs
你现在可以将它们整合到你的程序中
in order to stand on their shoulders and get real work done faster.
以便站在他们的肩膀上，更快地完成实际工作。
But recall, though, from C that we had a few steps via which
但请记住，在 C 语言中，我们有几个步骤可以
to actually compile that kind of code.
真正地编译这种代码。
So we got into the habit of make to make our program called hello.
因此我们养成了使用 make 来创建名为 hello 的程序的习惯。
And then we've been in the habit of running it with ./hello,
然后我们习惯了用 ./hello 来运行它，
the effect of which, of course, is to feed all of the zeros and ones that
这样做的效果是，当然，将组成 hello 程序的所有 0 和 1 传递到计算机的内存中，进而
compose the hello program into the computer's memory and, in turn,
进入 CPU。
the CPU.
CPU。
We revealed that what make is really doing
我们发现 make 实际上是在做
is something a little more specific, namely running clang, the C language
一些更具体的事情，即运行 clang，C 语言
compiler specifically, with some automatic command line arguments so as
编译器，使用一些自动的命令行参数，以便
to output the name that you want, link in the library that you want,
输出你想要的名字，链接你想要链接的库，
and so forth.
等等。
But with Python, wonderfully, we're going to get rid of those steps,
但用 Python，美妙的是，我们将摆脱这些步骤，
too, and quite simply run it as follows.
同样，只需按如下方式运行它。
Henceforth, our programs will no longer be in files ending in .c,
从现在开始，我们的程序将不再是扩展名为 .c 的文件，
suffice it to say.
就足以说明问题了。
Our files starting today are going to start ending with .py,
从今天开始，我们的文件将会以“.py”结尾，
which is an indication to the computer-- macOS, Windows,
这会向计算机——macOS、Windows，
or Linux or anything else-- that this is a Python program.
或者Linux，或者其他任何操作系统——表明这是一个Python程序。
But unlike C, wherein we've been in the habit of compiling our code
但与C语言不同的是，我们一直习惯于编译我们的代码，
and running it, compiling our code and running it, any time you make
然后运行它，编译代码并运行它，每次你做出
a change, with Python, those two steps get reduced into one, such
更改时，使用Python，这两个步骤会合并成一个，这样
that any time you make a change and want to rerun your code,
只要你做出更改并想要重新运行你的代码，
you don't explicitly compile it anymore.
你就不用再显式地编译它了。
You instead just run a program called python, similar in spirit to clang.
相反，你只需运行一个叫做“python”的程序，它在精神上与clang类似。
But whereas clang is a compiler, python will
但clang是一个编译器，而python会
see as not only the name of the language, but the name of a program.
被视为不仅是语言的名字，也是程序的名字。
And the type of that program is that of interpreter.
这种程序的类型是解释器。
An interpreter is a program that reads your code top to bottom, left to right,
解释器是一个程序，它从上到下、从左到右读取你的代码，
and really does what it says without having this intermediate step of first
并且真正地执行它所说的内容，而不需要像编译器那样首先经历一个中间步骤，
having to compile it in zeros and ones.
将代码编译成0和1。
So with that said, let me do this.
所以，让我做这件事吧。
Let me flip over here to VS Code.
让我切换到VS Code这边。
And within VS Code, let me write my first Python program.
在VS Code中，让我写第一个Python程序。
And as always, I can create a new file with the code command within VS Code.
和以往一样，我可以在VS Code中使用“code”命令创建一个新文件。
I'm going to create this file called hello.py, for instance.
例如，我将创建一个名为“hello.py”的文件。
And quite, quite simply, I'm going to go ahead and simply do print("Hello,
非常简单，我将直接执行print("Hello,
world").
And if I go down to my terminal window, instead of compiling this,
如果我切换到终端窗口，我不会编译这个程序，
I'm instead going to interpret this program by running python, space,
而是通过运行python、空格，来解释这个程序，
and the name of the file I want Python to interpret, hitting Enter.
然后输入要解释的文件名，最后按下回车键。
And voila.
瞧！
Now you see "hello, world."
现在你看到了“hello, world”。
But let me go ahead and compare this at left.
但是，让我将它与左侧的代码进行比较。
Let me also go ahead and bring back briefly a file called hello.c.
让我再将一个名为“hello.c”的文件调回来。
And I'm going to do this as we did in the very first day of C,
我要像在C语言的第一天那样做，
where I included standard io.h.
我包含了“stdio.h”。
I did int main(void).
我写了“int main(void)”。
I did inside of there printf(), quote unquote, "hello, world," backslash n,
我在里面写了“printf()”，引号、“hello, world”，反斜杠“n”，
close quote, semicolon.
关闭引号，分号。
And let me go ahead in VS Code.
然后让我在VS Code中继续。
And if you drag your file over to the right or the left,
如果你将文件拖到右侧或左侧，
you can actually split-screen things if of help.
你可以实际使用分屏功能，如果这有帮助的话。
And what I've done here is-- and let me hide my terminal window--
我在这里做的是——让我隐藏一下终端窗口——
I've now compared these two files left and right.
我现在比较了这两个文件，一个在左侧，一个在右侧。
So here's hello.c from, say, week 1.
所以，这是来自第一周的“hello.c”。
Here's hello.py from week 6 now.
现在，这是来自第六周的“hello.py”。
And the obvious-- the differences are perhaps obvious.
显而易见——差异可能是显而易见的。
But there's still some-- there's a subtlety, at least one subtlety.
但仍然存在一些——至少存在一个微妙之处。
Beyond getting rid of lots of syntax, what
除了摆脱了许多语法之外，我
did I apparently omit from my Python version,
在Python版本中明显遗漏了什么，
even though it didn't appear to behave in any buggy way?
即使它似乎没有出现任何错误？
Yeah?
是啊？
Sorry?
抱歉？
Say one more time?
再说一遍？
AUDIENCE: The library.
观众：库。
DAVID MALAN: The library.
戴维·马兰：库。
So I didn't have to include any kind of library like the standard I/O library.
所以，我不用包含任何像标准 I/O 库这样的库。
print(), apparently, in Python, just works.
显然，在 Python 中，print() 可以直接使用。
AUDIENCE: main() [INAUDIBLE]
观众：main() [听不清]
DAVID MALAN: So I don't need to use main() anymore.
戴维·马兰：所以我不用再使用 main() 了。
So this main() function, to be clear, was required in C because that's what
为了说清楚，这个 main() 函数在 C 中是必需的，因为这就是
told the compiler what the main part of your program is.
告诉编译器你程序的主要部分是什么。
And you can't just start writing code otherwise.
否则你就不能直接开始写代码。
What else do you see?
你还有什么发现？
AUDIENCE: No semicolon.
观众：没有分号。
DAVID MALAN: So there's no more semicolon, wonderfully enough,
戴维·马兰：所以，没有分号了，真是太好了，
at the end of this line, even though there was here.
这行的末尾没有分号，即使这里有。
And things are getting a little more subtle now.
事情现在变得越来越微妙了。
What else?
还有呢？
So the new line.
还有新行。
So recall that in printf(), if you wanted to move the cursor to the next
请记住，在 printf() 中，如果你想将光标移到下一行
line when you're done printing, you had to do it yourself.
你必须自己动手。
So it seems as though Python--
所以，似乎 Python--
because when I interpreted this program a moment ago,
因为我刚才解释这个程序的时候，
the cursor did move to the next line on its own.
光标自动移到了下一行。
They sort of reversed the default behavior.
他们有点颠倒了默认行为。
So those are just some of the salient differences here.
所以，这些只是这里的一些主要区别。
One, you don't have to explicitly include standard library, so to speak,
第一，你不用显式地包含标准库，可以说，
like standard I/O. You don't need to define a main() function anymore.
像标准 I/O。你不用再定义 main() 函数了。
You can just start writing your code.
你可以直接开始写代码。
You don't need these parentheses, these curly braces.
你不需要这些圆括号、这些花括号。
printf() is now called print(), it would seem.
printf() 现在似乎被称为 print()。
And you don't need the backslash n.
而且你不需要反斜杠 n。
Now, there is one thing that's also a little looser,
现在，还有一件事也比较宽松，
even though I didn't do it here.
虽然我在这里没有做。
Even though in C, it was required to use double quotes any times you--
即使在 C 中，每次你使用--
any time you want to use a string, a.k.a., char*, in Python,
无论何时你想在 Python 中使用字符串，也就是 char*，
as with a lot of languages nowadays, you can actually get away with just using
就像现在很多语言一样，你可以实际上使用
single quotes so long as you are consistent.
单引号，只要你保持一致。
Generally speaking, some people like this
一般来说，有些人喜欢这样
because you don't have to hold Shift, and therefore, you just
因为你不用按住 Shift，因此，你只需要
hit one key instead of two.
按一个键而不是两个键。
So there's an argument in terms of efficiency.
所以，在效率方面存在争议。
However, if you want to use an apostrophe in your string,
但是，如果你想在你的字符串中使用撇号，
then you have to escape it.
那么你必须转义它。
And so in general, stylistically, I'll use double quotes in this way.
所以，一般来说，从风格上来说，我会这样使用双引号。
But things are getting a little looser now with Python,
但 Python 现在变得越来越宽松了，
whereby that's not actually a requirement.
这实际上不是一项要求。
But what's especially exciting with Python,
但 Python 特别令人兴奋的地方是，
and, really, a lot of higher-level languages, is just how much real work
而且，实际上，很多高级语言，就是你能完成多少实际工作
you can get done relatively quickly.
能够在相对较短的时间内完成。
So you've just spent quite a bit of time,
所以你刚刚花了不少时间，
daresay, implementing your spell checker and implementing
可以说，实现了你的拼写检查器，并实现了
your own dictionary of sorts.
你自己的字典。
Well, let me propose that maybe we should have asked you
好吧，我想建议，也许我们应该让你
to do that in Python instead of C. Why?
用 Python 而不是 C 来做。为什么呢？
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
好吧，让我来做这件事。
Let me close these two tabs and reopen my terminal window.
让我关闭这两个标签，重新打开我的终端窗口。
Let me go into a directory called speller
让我进入一个名为 speller 的目录
that I downloaded in advance for class.
我之前为课程下载的。
And if I type ls in here, you'll notice that it's
如果我在里面输入 ls，你会注意到它
very similar to what you spent time on with problem set 5.
与你在问题集 5 中花费时间的内容非常相似。
But the file extensions are different.
但是文件扩展名不同。
There's a dictionary.py instead of dictionary.c.
有一个 dictionary.py 而不是 dictionary.c。
There's a speller.py instead of a speller.c.
有一个 speller.py 而不是 speller.c。
And there's the exact same directories, dictionaries, and texts
而且有完全相同的目录、字典和文本
that we gave you for problem set 5.
我们给你的问题集 5。
So let me just stipulate that I spent time implementing speller.c in Python.
所以，我想说，我花时间用 Python 实现 speller.c。
And so I gave it a name of speller.py.
因此我把它命名为 speller.py。
But I didn't go about really implementing dictionary.py yet.
但我还没有真正实现 dictionary.py。
And so why don't we go ahead and actually implement dictionary.py
所以，为什么我们不继续实现 dictionary.py 呢？
together by doing this?
一起做这件事？
Let me clear my terminal, do code dictionary.py.
让我清除终端，执行代码 dictionary.py。
And let me propose that we implement, ultimately, four functions.
我想建议，我们最终实现四个函数。
And what are those functions going to be?
这些函数将是什么？
Well, they're going to be the check() function, the load() function,
它们将是 check() 函数、load() 函数，
the size() function, and the unload() function.
size() 函数和 unload() 函数。
But recall that in problem set 5, you implemented your own hash table.
但请记住，在问题集 5 中，你实现了你自己的哈希表。
And so while there isn't a hash table data type in Python,
所以，虽然 Python 中没有哈希表数据类型，
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我将继续这样做。
I'm going to create a variable, a global variable in dictionary.py,
我将在 dictionary.py 中创建一个变量，一个全局变量，
called words, and I'm going to make it a set.
名为 words，我将把它设为一个集合。
In the mathematical sense, a set is a collection
从数学意义上讲，集合是集合
of things that won't contain duplicates.
不会包含重复项的事物。
Any duplicates will be filtered out.
任何重复项都将被过滤掉。
So I'm going to now, after that, creating that one global variable,
所以，现在，在那之后，创建那个全局变量，
I'm going to create a function called check(), just as you did.
我将创建一个名为 check() 的函数，就像你之前做的那样。
And check() takes as input a word.
而 check() 函数将一个单词作为输入。
And if I want to check if a word is in that set of words,
如果我想检查一个单词是否在这个单词集合中，
I can simply do word.lower in words.
我可以简单地用 words 中的 word.lower 来做。
And that's it.
就是这样。
Let me now define another function called load(), which, recall,
现在，让我定义另一个名为 load() 的函数，回想一下，
took an argument, which was the name of the dictionary you want to load
它接受一个参数，即你想要加载的字典的名称
into memory.
到内存中。
Inside of my load() function, I'm now going to do this.
在我的 load() 函数内部，我将要这样做。
I'm going to say with open(dictionary) as a variable called file.
我将使用 with open(dictionary) 作为名为 file 的变量。
And in there, I'm going to go ahead and update the set of words
在那里，我将继续更新单词集
to be the updated version of whatever's in this file as a result of reading
成为这个文件中读取结果的更新版本。
it and then splitting its lines, whereby this file has
它然后将它的行分割，这样这个文件就有
a big, long column of words, each of which is separated by a new line,
一大长列的单词，每个单词都用新行分隔，
splitline is going to split all of those into one big collection.
splitline 将把所有这些分割成一个大的集合。
And then I'm just going to go ahead and return True.
然后我将继续返回 True。
I'm now going to go ahead and define a size function, just as you did.
我现在将继续定义一个大小函数，就像你做的那样。
But in Python, I'm going to go ahead and just go ahead and return the length
但在 Python 中，我将继续返回长度
of that set of words, where length, or len(), is a function itself in Python.
的那组单词，其中 length 或 len() 本身就是 Python 中的一个函数。
And I'm going to do one last function.
我将做最后一个函数。
It turns out that in Python, even though, for this program,
事实证明，在 Python 中，尽管对于这个程序，
I'm going to go and implement a function called unload,
我将实现一个名为 unload 的函数，
there's not actually anything to unload in Python,
实际上在 Python 中没有要卸载的东西，
because Python will manage your memory for you.
因为 Python 会为你管理内存。
malloc() is gone. free() is gone.
malloc() 不见了。free() 不见了。
Pointers are gone.
指针不见了。
It handles all of that, seemingly magically for now, for you.
它处理了所有这些，现在看起来像是魔法一样，为你。
So here then is, I claim, what you could have done with problem set 5
所以，我认为，这是你用问题集 5 可以做的
if implementing it in Python instead.
如果用 Python 实现。
Let me go ahead and open my terminal window.
让我打开我的终端窗口。
Let me increase its size.
让我增加它的尺寸。
Let me run Python of speller.py, which is the name of the actual program, not
让我运行 speller.py 的 Python，这是实际程序的名称，而不是
the dictionary per se that I implemented.
我实现的字典本身。
Let's run it on a file called holmes.txt because that
让我们在一个名为 holmes.txt 的文件上运行它，因为
was a particularly big file.
是一个特别大的文件。
And if I hit Enter now, we'll see, hopefully,
如果我现在按下回车键，我们将会看到，希望是
the same output that you saw in C flying across the screen.
你在 C 中看到的相同输出，在屏幕上飞过。
And eventually, we should see that same summary at the bottom
最终，我们应该在底部看到相同的摘要
as to how many words seem to be misspelled,
关于有多少个单词似乎拼错了，
how many words were in the dictionary, and, ultimately, how
字典中有多少个单词，最终，以及整个过程是多么
fast this whole process was.
快。
Now, the total amount of time required was 1.93 seconds, which was actually
现在，总共花费的时间是 1.93 秒，实际上
longer than it seemed to take.
比看起来的时间要长。
That's because we're doing this in the cloud,
那是因为我们是在云端进行的，
and it was taking some amount of time to send all of the text to my screen.
并且把所有文本发送到我的屏幕上花了些时间。
But the code was only taking 1.93 seconds total on the actual server.
但代码在实际服务器上只花了 1.93 秒。
And hopefully, these same kinds of numbers line up with your own,
希望这些数字与你自己的数字一致，
the difference being what I did not have to implement for this spell checker is
不同之处在于，对于这个拼写检查器，我不必实现的是
your own hash table, is your own dictionary, literally,
你自己的哈希表，是你自己的字典，字面意义上，
beyond what I've done using Python here with some of these built-in features.
除了我在这里使用 Python 使用一些内置功能所做的之外。
So why, you see, why not always use Python,
所以，你看，为什么不总是使用 Python，
assuming that you prefer the idea of being
假设你更喜欢能够
able to whip up within seconds the entirety of problem set 5?
在几秒钟内完成整个问题集 5？
How might you choose now between languages?
你现在如何在两种语言之间选择？
And I apologize if you're harboring resentment
我如果让你心存怨恨，我表示歉意
that this wasn't a week earlier.
这没有早一个星期出现。
Why Python or why C?
为什么是 Python 还是为什么是 C？
Any instincts?
有任何直觉吗？
Any thoughts?
有什么想法吗？
There's hopefully a reason?
希望是有原因的？
Yeah, over here?
对，这边？
Yeah?
对？
AUDIENCE: I always thought that Python was a little slower than C [INAUDIBLE]
观众：我一直认为 Python 比 C 慢一点 [听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Ah, really good conjecture.
大卫·马兰：啊，非常好的猜想。
So you always thought that Python was slower than C
所以你一直认为 Python 比 C 慢
and takes up more space than C. Odds are that's, in fact, correct.
并且占用的空间比 C 大。很有可能，实际上是正确的。
So even though, ultimately, this 1.93 seconds is still pretty darn fast,
所以即使最终，这 1.93 秒仍然非常快，
odds are it's a little slower than the C version would have been.
但它可能比 C 版本要慢一些。
It's possible, too, that my version in Python
我的 Python 版本也有可能
actually does take up more RAM or memory underneath the hood.
实际上会占用更多 RAM 或内存。
Why?
为什么？
Well, because Python itself is managing memory for you.
因为 Python 本身正在为你管理内存。
And it doesn't necessarily know a priori how much memory you're going to need.
而且它不一定事先知道你需要多少内存。
You, the programmer might, and you, the programmer writing in C,
你，程序员可能知道，而你，用 C 语言编程的程序员，
allocated presumably exactly as much memory
可能分配了正好和你上周在第 5 题中所需要的内存一样多。
as you might have needed last week with problem set 5.
但是 Python 必须尽力为你做到最好
But Python's got to maybe do its best effort for you
并尝试为你管理内存，这会产生一些开销。
and try to manage memory for you, and there's going to be some overhead.
我的代码行数少得多，
The fact that I have so many fewer lines of code,
这些代码行帮我解决了第 5 题，
the fact that these lines of code solve problem set 5 for me,
意味着 Python 或发明 Python 的人写了一些代码
means that Python, or whoever invented Python, they wrote lines of code
来给我提供这种功能。
to of give me this functionality.
所以如果你把 Python 想象成一个中间人，
And so if you think of Python as a middleman of sorts,
它正在为我做更多的事情。
it's doing more work for me.
它正在做更多繁重的工作。
It's doing more of the heavy lift.
所以它可能需要更长时间。
So it might take me a bit more time.
但是，我的天哪，看看它在编写代码方面节省了多少时间。
But, my gosh, look how much time it has saved in terms
而且可以说，这段代码更容易阅读，
of writing this code more quickly.
或者至少在今天，第 6 周之后，当你对 Python 的语法有所了解后就会变得更容易阅读
And arguably, this code is even more readable,
以及 Python 本身的特性。
or at least will be after today, week 6, once you have an eye for the syntax
除此之外，你还可以非常轻松地做其他事情。
and features of Python itself.
让我回到我的终端窗口。
So beyond that, it turns out you can do other things pretty easily as well.
让我关闭这个 dictionary.py。
Let me go back into my terminal window.
让我进入一个名为 filter 的文件夹，其中
Let me close this dictionary.py.
我存放着我们之前见过的跨越河面的那座桥。
Let me go into a folder called filter, in which
这是一座桥。
I have this same bridge that we've seen in the past across the river there.
这是这张照片的原始版本。
So here's a bridge.
假设我实际上想编写一个模糊它的程序。
This is the original version of this particular photograph.
你可能还记得，在第 4 题中，你可以用 C 语言编写同样的代码
Suppose I actually want to write a program that blurs this.
通过操作构成该文件的红色、绿色和蓝色像素。
Well, you might recall from problem set 4 you could write that same code in C
但让我试着提出这个建议。
by manipulating all of the red, the green, the blue pixels that
让我创建一个名为 blur.py 的文件。
are ultimately composing that file.
在这个文件中，让我尝试导入一个库。
But let me go ahead and propose this instead.
所以，从 Python 图像库 PIL 中，让我尝试
Let me create a file called blur.py.
让我创建一个名为 blur.py 的文件。
And in this file, let me go ahead and just go ahead and import a library.
在这个文件中，让我继续前进，并导入一个库。
So from the Python image library, PIL, let me go ahead
所以从 Python 图像库 PIL 开始，让我继续
and import something called Image, capital I, and Image Filter, capital
导入名为 Image 的内容，大写 I，以及 Image Filter，大写
I, capital F.
我，大写的 F。
So I'm going to do before = Image.open("bridge.bmp").
所以我要在之前做 = Image.open("bridge.bmp")。
Then let me go ahead and create another variable called after
然后，我将创建一个名为“after”的变量
and set that equal to before.filter, and then, in parentheses,
并将其设置为等于“before.filter”，然后，在括号内
ImageFilter, spelled as before, dot BoxBlur,
是“ImageFilter”，拼写与之前相同，然后是“dot BoxBlur”
and then we'll give it a value of 10.
然后我们会给它赋予 10 的值。
How much do I want to blur it, for instance?
例如，我想把它模糊多少？
After that, I'm going to literally call after.save, and let's
在那之后，我会直接调用 after.save，然后我们
save it as a file called out.bmp.
把它保存为名为 out.bmp 的文件。
And that's it.
就是这样。
I propose that this is how you can now write code in Python to blur an image,
我认为这就是你现在可以用 Python 编写代码模糊图像的方式，
much like you might have for problem set 4.
就像你可能在问题集 4 中做过的那样。
Now let me go ahead in my terminal window and run python of blur.py.
现在让我在终端窗口中运行 blur.py 的 python 代码。
When I hit Enter, those four lines of code will run.
当我按下回车键时，这四行代码就会运行。
It seems to have happened quite quickly.
似乎很快完成了。
Let me go ahead and open now out.bmp.
现在让我打开 out.bmp。
And whereas the previous image looked like this a moment ago, let me go ahead
而之前那张图片看起来是这样的，让我继续
and open out.bmp.
打开 out.bmp。
And hopefully, you can indeed see that it blurred it
希望你能看到它确实模糊了
for me using that same code.
用同样的代码为我。
And if we want things to escalate a little more quickly,
如果我们想让事情更快一点，
let me go ahead and do this instead.
让我继续做这个。
Let me close blur.bmp.
让我关闭 blur.bmp。
Let me go ahead and open a file called edges.py.
让我继续打开一个名为 edges.py 的文件。
And maybe, in edges.py, we can use this same library.
也许，在 edges.py 中，我们可以使用同一个库。
So from the Python Image Library, import Image and import ImageFilter.
所以从 Python 图像库中，导入 Image 和导入 ImageFilter。
Let me go ahead and create another variable called before,
让我继续创建另一个名为 before 的变量，
set it equal to Image.open("bridge.bmp"),
将其赋值为 Image.open("bridge.bmp")，
just like before.
就像之前一样。
Let me create another variable called after,
让我继续创建另一个名为 after 的变量，
set that equal to before.filter(ImageFilter.FIND_EDGES),
将其赋值为 before.filter(ImageFilter.FIND_EDGES)，
which comes with this library automatically, and lastly,
这是这个库自动提供的，最后
the same thing-- save this as a file called out.bmp.
同样的事情-- 把它保存为一个名为 out.bmp 的文件。
So if you struggled perhaps with this one
所以如果你之前可能在这方面遇到了一些困难
previously, whereby you wrote for the more comfortable version of problem
之前，当你为更舒适版本的题目编写代码时
set 4, edge detection, so to speak, well, you
集 4，可以这么说，边缘检测，那么你
might have then created a file that given an input like this,
可能就创建了一个文件，给定像这样的输入，
the original bridge.bmp, this new version, out.bmp, with just four
原始的 bridge.bmp，这个新版本，out.bmp，只有四
lines of code, now looks like this.
行代码，现在看起来像这样。
So, again, if this is a little frustrating
所以，再说一次，如果这有点令人沮丧
that we had to do all of this in C, that was exactly
我们不得不把所有这些都用 C 语言来实现，这正是
the point to motivate that you now understand nonetheless
想要让你理解的重点，尽管如此
what's going on underneath the hood.
了解引擎盖下的运作机制。
But with Python, you can express the solutions
但是用 Python，你可以表达解决方案
to problems all the more efficiently, all the more readily.
用更有效率的方式，更轻松地解决问题。
And just one last one, too-- it's very common nowadays
还有一个，现在很常见
in the world of photography and social media and the like to do face
在摄影、社交媒体等领域做人脸
detection, for better or for worse.
检测，无论好坏。
And it turns out that face detection, even
事实证明，人脸检测，即使
if you want to integrate it into your own application,
如果你想将它集成到你的应用程序中，
is something that lots of other people have integrated into their applications
也是许多其他人已经将其集成到他们的应用程序中的功能
as well.
。
So Python, to my point earlier of having this very rich ecosystem of libraries
所以 Python，就像我之前提到的，拥有一个非常丰富的库生态系统
that other people wrote, you can literally run a command like pip
是由其他人编写的，你实际上可以运行一个像 pip 这样的命令
install face_recognition if you want to add support to your code space,
安装 face_recognition，如果你想在你的代码空间中添加支持，
or to your programming and environment more generally,
或者更普遍地说，添加到你的编程和环境中，
for the notion of face recognition.
用于人脸识别的概念。
In fact, this is going to automatically install
事实上，这将自动安装
from some server elsewhere a library that someone else wrote
来自其他服务器上的一个由其他人编写的库
called face_recognition.
名为 face_recognition。
And with this library, you can do something like this.
使用这个库，你可以做这样的事情。
Let me go into a directory that I came with in advance.
让我进入一个我事先准备好的目录。
Let me go ahead and ls in there, and you'll see four files--
让我继续在那里 ls，你会看到四个文件——
detect.py and recognize.py, which are going to detect
detect.py 和 recognize.py，它们将分别检测
faces and then recognize specific faces, respectively, and then two files
人脸，然后识别特定人脸，以及两个文件
I brought from a popular TV show, for instance.
例如，我从一个受欢迎的电视剧中获得。
So if I open office.jpg, here is one of the early cast photos from the hit TV
所以如果我打开 office.jpg，这里就是热门电视剧《办公室》的早期演员照片之一。
series The Office.
《办公室》。
And here is a photograph of someone specific from the show, Toby.
这里是一张电视剧中某位特定人物的照片，托比。
Now, this is, of course, Toby's face.
当然，这是托比的脸。
But what is it that makes Toby's face a face?
但是什么让托比的脸成为一张脸？
More generally, if I open up office.jpg, and I asked you, the human,
更一般地说，如果我打开 office.jpg，我问你，人类，
to identify all of the faces in this picture,
识别这幅图片中所有的人脸，
it wouldn't be that hard with a marker to sort of circle all of the faces.
用标记圈出所有的人脸并不难。
But how?
但是怎样？
Why?
为什么？
How do you as humans detect faces, might you think?
你作为人类是如何检测人脸的，你可能会想？
Yeah?
是吧？
AUDIENCE: You have eyes, nose.
观众：你有眼睛，鼻子。
DAVID MALAN: Features, yeah, like eyes, nose,
大卫·马兰：特征，是的，比如眼睛，鼻子，
generally in a similar orientation, even though we all
通常以类似的方向，即使我们所有人
have different faces, ultimately.
最终都有不同的脸。
But there's a pattern to the shapes that you're seeing on the screen.
但你在屏幕上看到的形状存在一个模式。
Well, it turns out this face_recognition library
事实证明，这个 face_recognition 库
has been trained, perhaps via artificial intelligence over time,
已经过训练，也许是通过人工智能随着时间的推移，
to recognize faces, but any number of different faces,
来识别面孔，但任何数量的不同面孔，
perhaps among these folks here.
也许就在这些人中。
So if I go back into my terminal window here,
所以如果我回到我的终端窗口，
let me go ahead and run, say, python of detect.py, which I wrote
让我继续运行，比如 python detect.py，我之前写的
in advance, which uses that library.
提前准备好的，它使用了那个库。
And what that program is going to do-- it's going to think, do some thinking.
而那个程序将会做的是——它会思考，做一些思考。
It's just found some face.
它刚刚发现了一些面孔。
And let me go ahead now and open a file it just created
让我现在继续打开一个它刚刚创建的文件
called detected.jpg, which I didn't have in my folder a moment ago.
名为 detected.jpg，我之前在我的文件夹中没有它。
But when I open this here file, you'll now see all of the faces
但是当我打开这个文件时，你就会看到所有的人脸。
based on this library's detection thereof.
基于此库的检测结果。
But suppose that we're looking for a very specific face among them,
但假设我们要在其中寻找一张非常特定的脸，
maybe Toby's.
可能是托比的。
Well, maybe if we write a program that doesn't just
好吧，也许如果我们编写一个程序，它不仅仅是
take as input the office.jpg, but a second input, toby.jpg,
将 office.jpg 作为输入，而是第二个输入，toby.jpg，
maybe this library, and code more generally,
也许这个库，以及更一般的代码，
can distinguish Toby's face from Jim's, from Pam's, from everyone else
可以区分托比的脸，吉姆的脸，帕姆的脸，以及所有其他人
in the show, just based on this one piece of training data, so to speak.
在节目中，仅仅基于这一个训练数据，可以说。
Well let me instead run python of recognize.py and hit Enter.
好吧，让我运行 recognize.py 的 python 脚本并按回车键。
It's going to do some thinking, some thinking, some thinking.
它会思考，思考，思考。
And it is going to output now a file called
它现在将输出一个名为
recognized.jpg, which should show me his face, ideally, specifically.
recognized.jpg 的文件，它应该理想地、具体地显示他的脸。
And so what has it done?
那么它做了什么？
Well, with sort of a green marker, there is Toby among all of these faces.
好吧，用一种绿色的标记，在所有这些脸上，有托比。
That's maybe a dozen or so lines of code,
这可能只有十来行代码，
but it's built on top of this ecosystem of libraries.
但它是建立在这个库生态系统之上的。
And this is, again, just one of the reasons why Python is so popular.
而这，再一次，只是 Python 如此受欢迎的原因之一。
Undoubtedly, some number of years from now, Python will be out,
毫无疑问，从现在算起几年后，Python 会过时，
and something else will be back in.
而其他一些东西将重新流行起来。
But that's indeed among the goals of CS50, too, is not to teach you C,
但这确实是 CS50 的目标之一，不是教你 C 语言，
not to teach you Python, not in a couple of weeks
不是教你 Python，不是在几周内
to teach you JavaScript and other languages, too,
教你 JavaScript 和其他语言，
but to teach you how to program.
而是教你如何编程。
And indeed, all of the ideas we have explored and will now
事实上，我们已经探索过的，现在将要探索的，
explore more today, you'll see recurring for languages in the years to come.
今天将要深入探索的，你将会看到在未来的几年里，它们会在不同的语言中反复出现。
Any questions before we now dive into how it is this code is working
在我们深入研究这段代码是如何工作的之前，有什么问题吗？
and why I type the things that I did before we forge ahead?
以及为什么我之前打出这些内容，在我们继续前进之前？
Any questions along these lines?
这方面还有什么问题吗？
Anything at all?
任何问题都可以提出来吗？
No?
没有吗？
All right.
好的。
So how does Python itself work?
那么 Python 本身是如何工作的呢？
Well, let's do a quick review as we did when
好吧，让我们做一个快速回顾，就像我们在
we transitioned from Scratch to C, this time,
从 Scratch 过渡到 C 语言时所做的那样，这一次，
though, from Scratch, say, to Python.
不过，是从 Scratch 到 Python。
So in Python, as with many languages, there
所以在 Python 中，就像在许多其他语言中一样，有
are these things called functions-- the actions and verbs that
这些被称为函数的东西——实际完成动作的动词。
actually get things done.
实际上完成动作的动词。
So here on the left, recall from week 0, was the simplest of functions.
所以左边这里，回忆一下第 0 周，是最简单的函数。
We played with, first, the say block, which just literally has
我们首先玩了 say 代码块，它只是简单地让
the cat say something on the screen.
猫在屏幕上说出一些东西。
We've seen in C, for instance, the equivalent line of code is arguably
例如，我们在 C 语言中看到的等效代码行可以算是
this here, with printf(), with the parentheses, the quotation marks,
这里，使用了 printf()，带括号，引号，
the backslash n, the semicolon.
反斜杠 n，分号。
In Python now, it's going to indeed be a little simpler than that.
现在在 Python 中，它确实比那更简单一些。
But the idea is the same as it was back in week 0.
但这个想法和第 0 周时一样。
Libraries-- so we've seen already in C, and now we've
库——所以在 C 语言中我们已经看到了，现在我们已经
already seen in Python that these things exist, too.
我们已经在 Python 中看到过这些东西的存在了。
In the world of C, recall that besides the standard ones, like standard io.h,
在 C 语言的世界里，回想一下，除了像 standard io.h 这样的标准库之外，
that header file, we could very quickly introduce cs50.h,
那个头文件，我们可以很快地引入 cs50.h，
which was like your entry point, the header
它就像你的入口点，头文件
file for the CS50 library, which gave you a bunch of functions as well.
用于 CS50 库，它也为你提供了一堆函数。
Well, we're going to give you a similar library
好吧，我们将为你提供一个类似的库
for at least the next week or two, training wheels for Python
至少在接下来的一两周内，用于 Python 的辅助工具
specifically, that, again, will take off so that you can stand on your own,
具体来说，它会再次帮助你起飞，这样你就可以独立了，
even with CS50 behind you.
即使有了 CS50 的支持。
But the syntax for using a library in Python is a little different.
但是在 Python 中使用库的语法有点不同。
You don't include a .h file.
你不需要包含 .h 文件。
You just import, instead, the name of the library.
相反，你只需导入库的名称。
All right.
好的。
What does that actually mean?
这到底意味着什么呢？
Well, if there are specific functions in that library you want to use,
好吧，如果库中有一些你想要使用的特定函数，
in Python, you can be more precise.
在 Python 中，你可以更加精确。
You don't just have to say, give me the whole library.
你不需要说，给我整个库。
For efficiency purposes, you can say, let me import the get_string() function
为了效率，你可以说，让我导入 get_string() 函数
from the CS50 library.
来自 CS50 库。
So you have finer-grained control in Python, which can actually speed things
所以在 Python 中，你拥有更细粒度的控制，这实际上可以加快速度
up if you're not loading things unnecessarily
如果你没有不必要地加载东西
into memory, if all you want is, say, one feature therein.
到内存中，如果你只需要其中一个功能。
So here, for instance, in Scratch, was an example of how we might use not only
所以，例如，在 Scratch 中，就是一个例子，说明了我们如何不仅
a built-in function, like the say block, or, in C, in the printf(),
可以使用内置函数，比如 say 块，或者，在 C 语言中，使用 printf()，
but how we might similarly now do the same but achieve this in Python.
但我们现在如何以类似的方式做到这一点，并在 Python 中实现这一点。
So how might we do this?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
Well, in Python, or rather, in C, this code
好吧，在 Python 中，或者更确切地说，在 C 语言中，这段代码
looks a little something like this.
看起来像这样。
Back in week 1, we declared a variable of type string,
在第一周，我们声明了一个字符串类型的变量，
even though later we revealed that to be char*.
尽管我们后来发现它实际上是 char*。
I gave this a variable name of answer for parity with Scratch.
为了与 Scratch 保持一致，我给它起了个变量名叫做 answer。
Then we use CS50's own get_string() function and asked, for instance,
然后，我们使用 CS50 自带的 get_string() 函数，并问道，例如，
the same question as in the white oval here.
与这里白色椭圆形中的问题相同。
And then, using this placeholder syntax, these format codes,
然后，使用这种占位符语法，这些格式代码，
which was printf()-specific, we could plug in that answer to this premade
这对于 printf() 是特定的，我们可以将答案插入这个预先做好的字符串中
string where the %s is.
其中 %s 的位置。
And we saw %i and %f and a bunch of others as well.
我们也看到了 %i 和 %f 以及其他一些。
So this is sort of how, in C, you approximate
所以，这就是你在 C 语言中模拟
the idea of concatenating two things together, joining two things,
将两个东西连接在一起，组合两个东西的想法，
just as we did here in Scratch.
就像我们在这里在 Scratch 中所做的那样。
So in Python, it turns out it's not only going to be a little easier,
所以，在 Python 中，事实证明它不仅会更简单一些，
but there's going to be even more ways to do this.
而且会有更多的方法来做到这一点。
And so even what might seem today like a lot of different syntax,
因此，即使今天看起来有很多不同的语法，
it really is just different ways, stylistically,
它实际上只是风格上不同的方法，
to achieve the same goals.
来实现相同的目标。
And over time, as you get more comfortable with this,
随着时间的推移，当你对此越来越熟悉，
you too will develop your own style, or, if working for a company
你也会发展出自己的风格，或者，如果你在公司工作
or working with a team, you might collectively
或者与团队合作，你们可能会共同
decide which conventions you want to use.
决定你想使用哪些约定。
But here, for instance, is one way you could implement this same idea
但是，例如，以下是一种实现相同想法的方法
in Scratch but in Python instead.
在 Scratch 中，但用 Python 代替。
So notice I'm going to still use a variable called answer.
所以注意，我仍然要使用一个名为 answer 的变量。
I'm going to use CS50's function called get_string().
我将使用 CS50 的名为 get_string() 的函数。
I'm still going to use, quote unquote, "What's your name?"
我仍然要使用，引号中的，“What's your name？”
But down here is where we see the most difference.
但在这里，我们看到了最大的区别。
It's, again, not called printf() in Python.
它，再次强调，在 Python 中不叫 printf()。
It's now called just print().
它现在直接叫 print()。
And what might you infer the plus operator is doing here?
你能推断出加号运算符在这里的作用吗？
It's not addition, obviously, in a mathematical sense.
它不是加法，显然，在数学意义上。
But those of you who have perhaps programmed before,
但是你们中那些可能以前编程过的人，
what does the plus represent in this context?
在这个上下文中，加号代表什么？
AUDIENCE: It's joining the two strings together.
观众：它将两个字符串连接在一起。
DAVID MALAN: It's indeed joining the two strings together.
大卫·马兰：它确实将两个字符串连接在一起。
So this is indeed concatenating the thing
所以这实际上是将左边的东西
on the left with the thing on the right.
与右边的东西连接在一起。
So you don't use the placeholder in this particular scenario.
因此，你不会在这种情况下使用占位符。
You can instead, a little more simply, just use plus.
你可以改为，更简单一点，直接使用加号。
But you want your grammar to line up.
但你想要你的语法对齐。
So I still have "hello," and then close quote
所以我还保留着“hello”，然后关闭引号
because I want to form a full phrase.
因为我想构成一个完整的短语。
Notice, too, there's also one other slightly more
注意，还有另外一个稍微更
subtle difference on the first line.
细微的差异在第一行。
Besides the fact that we don't have a semicolon, what else is different?
除了我们没有分号之外，还有什么不同？
AUDIENCE: You don't declare the type of the variable.
观众：你没有声明变量的类型。
DAVID MALAN: I didn't declare the type of the variable.
大卫·马兰：我没有声明变量的类型。
So Python still has strings, as we'll see.
所以 Python 仍然有字符串，正如我们将会看到的那样。
But you don't have to tell the interpreter what type of variable
但你不需要告诉解释器变量的类型
it is.
是什么。
And this is going to save us some keystrokes,
这将为我们节省一些按键，
and it's just going to be a little more user-friendly over time.
而且随着时间的推移，它会更友好一些。
Meanwhile, you can do this also a little bit differently if you prefer.
同时，如果你愿意，也可以用稍微不同的方式来做。
You can instead trust that the print() function in Python can actually do even
你可以改为信任 Python 中的 print() 函数实际上可以做更多
more for you automatically.
更多事情，自动地为你。
The print() function in Python can take multiple arguments separated by commas
Python 中的 print() 函数可以接受多个用逗号分隔的参数
in the usual way.
以通常的方式。
And by default, Python is going to insert
默认情况下，Python 将插入
for you a single space between its first argument and its second argument.
一个空格，在它的第一个参数和第二个参数之间。
So notice what I've done here is my first argument
所以注意，我在这里做的，是我的第一个参数
is, quote unquote, "hello," with a comma but no space.
是，引号中的，“hello”，带一个逗号，但没有空格。
Then, outside of the quotes, I'm putting a comma because that just means,
然后，在引号外面，我加了一个逗号，因为这意味着，
here comes my second argument.
我的第二个参数来了。
And then I put the same variable as before.
然后，我放上了和之前一样的变量。
And I'm just going to let Python figure out
我只要让 Python 弄明白
that it should, by default, per its documentation,
它应该按照文档，默认情况下
can join these two variables, putting a single space in between them.
可以将这两个变量连接起来，并在它们之间添加一个空格。
You can do this yet another way.
你还可以用另一种方式来做到这一点。
And this way looks a little weirder, but this is actually
这种方式看起来有点奇怪，但实际上
probably the most common way nowadays in Python
现在在 Python 中，这可能是最常见的做法。
is to use what's called a format string, or f string, for short.
就是使用所谓的格式字符串，简称 f 字符串。
And this looks weird to me still.
对我来说，这仍然看起来很奇怪。
It looks weird.
看起来很奇怪。
But if you prefix a string in Python with an f,
但是，如果你在 Python 中用 f 作为字符串的前缀，
literally, you can then use curly braces inside of that string in Python.
你就可以在 Python 的字符串中使用花括号。
And Python will not print out literally a curly brace and a closed curly brace.
Python 不会直接打印出一个花括号和一个闭合的花括号。
It will instead interpolate whatever is inside of those curly braces.
相反，它会将花括号中的内容进行插值。
That is to say if answer is a variable that
也就是说，如果 answer 是一个变量，它
has some value, like "David" or something like that,
具有某个值，比如 "David" 之类的，
saying f before the first quotation mark,
在第一个引号之前加上 f，
and then using these curly braces therein,
然后使用花括号，
is going to do the exact same thing of creating a string that says "Hello,"
将生成一个包含 "Hello" 的字符串，
comma, space, "David."
逗号，空格，"David"。
So it's going to plug in the value for you.
所以它会为你插入值。
So you can think of this as %s but without that second step of having
所以你可以把它想象成 %s，但不需要第二步，也就是
to keep track of what you want to plug back in for %s.
跟踪你想插入到 %s 中的内容。
Instead of %s, you literally put in curly braces,
而不是 %s，你直接插入花括号，
what do you want to put right there?
你想在那里放什么？
You format the string yourself.
你自己格式化字符串。
So given all of those ways, how might we actually
鉴于所有这些方法，我们实际上该如何
go about implementing this or using this ourselves?
去实现它或自己使用它呢？
Well, let me propose that we do this here.
好吧，我建议我们在这里做这个。
Let me propose that I go back to VS Code.
我建议我回到 VS Code。
Let me go ahead and open up hello.py again.
让我打开 hello.py 文件。
And as before, instead of just printing out something like,
和之前一样，而不是打印类似这样的东西，
quote unquote, "hello, world," let me actually print out
"hello, world" ，让我真正打印出来
something a little more interesting.
一些更有趣的东西。
So let me go ahead and, from the CS50 library,
所以，我从 CS50 库中
import the function called get_string().
导入名为 get_string() 的函数。
Then let me go ahead and create a variable called answer.
然后我创建一个名为 answer 的变量。
Let me set that equal to the return value of get_string() with,
我将其设置为 get_string() 的返回值，
as an argument, quote unquote, "What's your name?"
作为参数，"What's your name?"
And then no semicolon at the end of that line, but on the next line, frankly
然后在那一行的末尾不要加分号，但在下一行，坦率地说
here, I can pick any one of those potential solutions.
在这里，我可以选择其中任何一个潜在的解决方案。
So let me start with the first.
所以，我从第一个开始。
So "hello, " + answer.
所以 "hello, " + answer。
And now, if I go down to my terminal window and run python of hello.py,
现在，如果我进入终端窗口并运行 hello.py 的 python，
I'm prompted for my name.
我会被提示输入我的名字。
I can type in D-A-V-I-D, and voila, that there then works.
我可以输入 D-A-V-I-D，瞧，它就运行了。
Or I can tweak this a little bit.
或者我可以稍微调整一下。
I can trust that Python will concatenate its first and second argument for me.
我可以相信 Python 会为我连接它的第一个和第二个参数。
But this isn't quite right.
但这不太对。
Let me go ahead and rerun python of hello.py, hit Enter, and type
让我重新运行 hello.py 的 python，按 Enter，然后输入
in "David."
在 "David" 中。
It's going to be ever-so-slightly buggy, sort of grammatically
它将略微有点错误，从语法上来说
or visually, if you will.
或者从视觉上来说，如果你愿意。
What did I do wrong here?
我这里做错了什么？
Yeah.
是的。
So I left the space in there, even though I'm getting one for free from
所以我留下了这个空格，即使我从
print().
print() 中免费得到了一个。
So that's an easy solution here.
所以这里有一个简单的解决方案。
But let's do it one other way after running this to be sure--
但是让我们在运行完这个后尝试另一种方法，以确保--
D-A-V-I-D.
D-A-V-I-D。
And OK, now it looks like I intended.
好了，现在看起来就像我想要的那样了。
Well, let's go ahead and use that placeholder syntax.
好吧，让我们继续使用占位符语法。
So let's just pass in one bigger string as our argument, do "hello,"
所以我们只需将一个更大的字符串作为我们的参数传递，输入 "hello,"
and then, in curly braces, [? answer ?],, like this.
然后在花括号中，[? answer ?]，像这样。
Well, let me go down to my terminal window and clear it.
好吧，让我到我的终端窗口并清除它。
Let me run python of hello.py and enter, type in D-A-V-I-D, and voila.
让我运行 python hello.py 并输入，输入 D-A-V-I-D，然后瞧！
OK, I made a mistake.
好的，我犯了一个错误。
What did I do wrong here, minor though it seems to be?
我这里做错了什么，尽管看起来很小？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: So the stupid little f that you
DAVID MALAN：所以你必须在字符串之前加的这个愚蠢的小 f
have to put before the string to tell Python
要告诉 Python
that this is a special string-- it's a format string, or f
这是一个特殊字符串--它是一个格式字符串，或者 f
string-- that it should additionally format for you.
字符串--它应该另外为你格式化。
So if I rerun this after adding that f, I can do python of hello.py.
所以如果我在添加那个 f 后重新运行它，我可以运行 python hello.py。
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
David.
David。
And now it looks the way I might intend.
现在看起来就像我想要的那样了。
But it turns out in Python, you don't actually need to use get_string().
但事实证明在 Python 中，你实际上不需要使用 get_string()。
In C, recall that we introduced that because it's actually
在 C 中，回想一下我们引入了它，因为它实际上
pretty annoying in C to get strings, in particular to get strings safely.
在 C 中获取字符串相当令人厌烦，特别是安全地获取字符串。
Recall those short examples we did with scanf not too long ago.
回想一下我们不久前使用 scanf 做的那些简短的例子。
And scanf kind of scans what the user types at the keyboard
而 scanf 扫描用户在键盘上输入的内容
and loads it into memory.
并将其加载到内存中。
But the fundamental danger with scanf when it comes to strings was what?
但是 scanf 在处理字符串时最根本的危险是什么？
Why was it dangerous to use scanf to get strings from a user?
为什么使用 scanf 从用户那里获取字符串很危险？
Why?
为什么？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: What if they give you a really long string you don't have space for?
观众：如果他们给你的字符串太长，你没有空间怎么办？
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
DAVID MALAN：正是。
What if they give you a really long string
如果他们给你的字符串太长
that you didn't allocate space for?
而你没有为它分配空间呢？
Because you're not going to know as the programmer in advance
因为作为程序员，你事先并不知道
how long of a string the human is going to type in.
用户要输入多长的字符串。
So you might under--
所以你可能会低估它，因此内存不足，或者
you might undercut it and therefore have too much memory, or too many
太多字符被放入了内存，从而导致
characters being put into that memory, thereby giving you
某种缓冲区溢出，可能会导致电脑崩溃，或者至少
some kind of buffer overflow, which might crash the computer or, minimally,
你的程序崩溃。
your program.
你的程序。
So it turns out in C, get_string() was especially useful.
所以事实证明在 C 中，get_string() 非常有用。
In Python, it's not really that useful.
在 Python 中，它并没有那么有用。
All it does is use a function that does come with Python called input().
它所做的就是使用一个 Python 自带的函数，叫做 input()。
And, in fact, the input() function in Python, for all intents and purposes,
事实上，Python 中的 input() 函数，就其目的而言，
is the same as the get_string() function that we give to you.
与我们提供的 get_string() 函数相同。
But just to ease the transition from C to Python,
但为了便于从 C 语言过渡到 Python，
we implemented a Python version of get_string() nonetheless.
我们还是实现了 Python 版本的 get_string() 函数。
But this is to say if I go to VS Code here,
但我想说的是，如果我在这里进入 VS Code，
and I just change get_string() to input(), and, in fact,
并将 get_string() 更改为 input()，事实上，
I even get rid of the CS50 library at the top, this too should work fine.
我甚至可以去掉顶部的 CS50 库，这应该也能正常工作。
If I rerun python of hello.py, type in my name, David, and voila,
如果我重新运行 hello.py 的 Python 程序，输入我的名字，David，瞧，
I have that now working as well.
现在它也能正常工作了。
All right.
好的。
Questions about this use of get_string() or input() or any of our syntax thus
关于使用 get_string() 或 input() 或我们到目前为止的任何语法，
far?
有疑问吗？
All right.
好的。
Well, what about variables?
那么，变量呢？
We've used variables already, and we already
我们已经使用过变量了，并且已经
identified the fact that you don't have to specify the type of your variables
确定了这样一个事实：你不需要主动指定变量的类型
proactively, even though, clearly, Python supports strings thus far,
尽管 Python 到目前为止支持字符串，
well, in Python, here's how you might declare
那么，在 Python 中，你可以这样声明
a variable that not necessarily is assigned like a string,
一个不一定被赋值为字符串的变量，
but maybe an integer instead.
而是可能是一个整数。
So in Scratch, here's how you could create
所以在 Scratch 中，你可以这样创建一个
a variable called counter if you want to count things and set it equal to 0.
名为 counter 的变量，如果你想统计事物并将其设置为 0。
In C, what we would have done is this--
在 C 语言中，我们会这样做：
int counter = 0; that's the exact same thing as in Scratch.
int counter = 0; 这与 Scratch 中完全相同。
But in Python, as you might imagine, we can chip away at this and type
但在 Python 中，正如你所想，我们可以简化它并输入
out this same idea little more easily.
这个相同的想法，只是更容易一点。
One, we don't need to say int anymore.
首先，我们不再需要说 int。
Two, we don't need the semicolon anymore.
其次，我们不再需要分号。
And so you just do what you intend.
所以你只需要做你想做的事情。
If you want a variable, just write it out.
如果你想要一个变量，就写出来。
If you want to assign it a value, you use the equals sign.
如果你想为它赋值，就使用等号。
If you want to specify that value, you put it on the right.
如果你想指定那个值，就将其放在右边。
And just as in C, this is not the equality operator.
就像 C 语言一样，这不是相等运算符。
It's the assignment operator from right to left.
它是从右到左的赋值运算符。
Recall that in Scratch, if you wanted to increment a variable by 1 or any value,
回想一下，在 Scratch 中，如果你想将一个变量加 1 或任何值，
you could use this puzzle piece here.
你可以使用这里的这个拼图块。
Well, in C, you could do syntax like this, which, again, is not equality.
那么，在 C 语言中，你可以使用这样的语法，它同样不是相等运算。
It's saying add 1 to counter and then assign it back to the counter variable.
它是说将 1 加到 counter 上，然后将它赋值回 counter 变量。
In Python, you can do exactly the same thing minus the semicolon.
在 Python 中，你可以做完全相同的事情，只是没有分号。
So you don't need to use the semicolon here.
所以你不需要在这里使用分号。
But you might recall that in C, there was some syntactic sugar for this idea
但你可能还记得，在 C 语言中，有一些语法糖来表达这个想法
because it was pretty popular.
因为它很流行。
And so you could shorten this in C, as you can in Python,
所以你可以在 C 语言中缩写它，就像在 Python 中一样，
to actually just this. += 1 will add to the counter variable whatever that
实际上就是这个。+= 1 会将任何值加到 counter 变量上，这个值就是
value is.
值的。
But it's not all steps forward.
但并非所有都是进步。
You might be in the habit of using ++ or --.
你可能习惯使用 ++ 或 -- 。
Sorry, those are not available in Python.
抱歉，这些在 Python 中不可用。
Why?
为什么？
It's because the designers of Python decided that you
这是因为 Python 的设计者决定你
don't need them because this is--
不需要它们，因为这...
gets the job done anyway.
无论如何都能完成工作。
But there's a question down here in front, unless it was about the same.
但这里面有一个问题，除非是关于相同的问题。
All right.
好的。
So that's one feature we're taking away.
所以，我们拿走了一个功能。
But it's not such a big deal to do += in this case.
但在这种情况下，做 += 并不算什么大问题。
Well, what about the actual types involved here
那么，这里涉及的实际类型呢？
beyond actually being able to define variables?
除了能够定义变量之外呢？
Well, recall that in the world of C, we had at least these data
回想一下，在 C 的世界里，我们至少有这些数据
types, those that came with the language in particular.
类型，那些与语言本身相关的类型。
And we played with quite a few of these over time.
随着时间的推移，我们使用了其中相当一部分。
In Python, we're going to take a bunch of those away.
在 Python 中，我们将拿走其中很多。
In Python, you're only going to have access to a bool, true or false,
在 Python 中，你将只能访问 bool、true 或 false，
a float, which is a real number with a decimal point,
float，它是一个带有小数点的实数，
typically, an int, or an integer, and a string, now known as str.
通常，int 或整数，以及字符串，现在称为 str。
So Python here sort of cuts some corners,
所以 Python 在这里某种程度上偷了一些懒，
feels like it's too long to write out strings.
感觉写出字符串太长了。
So a string in Python is called str, S-T-R, but it's the exact same idea.
所以在 Python 中，字符串被称为 str，S-T-R，但它完全是一样的概念。
Notice, though, that missing from this now, in particular,
注意，现在，尤其是，这里缺少
are double and long, which, recall, actually used more bits in order
double 和 long，回想一下，它们实际上使用了更多的位来
to store information.
存储信息。
We'll see that that might not necessarily be a bad thing.
我们会看到，这可能不一定是坏事。
In fact, Python just simplifies the world
事实上，Python 只是简化了世界
into two different types of variables but gets
分成两种不同类型的变量，但它
out of the business of you having to decide,
让你不必再决定，
do you want a small int or a large int or something along those lines?
你想要一个小的 int 还是一个大的 int，或者类似的东西？
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
好吧，让我继续做这个。
Let me switch back over to VS Code here.
让我切换回 VS Code。
And why don't we actually try to play around with some calculations using
我们为什么不尝试用一些计算来玩玩
these data types and more?
这些数据类型以及更多？
Let me go ahead and propose that we implement,
让我提议我们实现，
like we did way back in week 1, a simple calculator.
就像我们在第一周做的那样，一个简单的计算器。
So let me do this-- code of calculator.c.
所以让我这样做——calculator.c 的代码。
So I'm indeed going to do this in C first, just so
所以，我确实要先用 C 做这个，这样
that we have a similar example at hand.
我们手边就有一个类似的例子。
So I'm going to include standard io.h here at the top.
所以，我要在顶部包含 standard io.h。
I'm going to go ahead and do int main(void).
我将继续执行 int main(void)。
Inside of main(), I'm going to go ahead and declare a variable called x and set
在 main() 内部，我将继续声明一个名为 x 的变量并设置
that equal to get_int(), and I'm going to prompt the user for that value x.
它等于 get_int()，我将提示用户输入该值 x。
But if I'm using get_int(), recall that actually is from the CS50 library.
但如果我使用 get_int()，请记住，它实际上来自 CS50 库。
So in C, I'm going to need cs50.h, still, for this example.
所以在 C 中，对于这个例子，我仍然需要 cs50.h。
But back in week 1, I then did something else.
但是，回到第一周，我做了另一件事。
I then said, give me another variable called y, set that equal to get_int(),
然后我说，再给我一个名为 y 的变量，将其设置为 get_int()，
and set that equal to that-- pass in that prompt there.
并将其设置为那个 - 将提示传递进去。
And then, lastly, let's just do something super simple
最后，让我们做一些非常简单的事情
like add two numbers together.
比如将两个数字加在一起。
So in C, I'll use printf().
所以在 C 中，我会使用 printf()。
I'm going to go ahead and do %i backslash n as a placeholder.
我会用 %i 反斜杠 n 作为占位符。
And then I'm just going to plug in x + y.
然后，我只需要将 x + y 插入进去。
So all of that was in C. So it was a decent number of lines of code
所以所有这些都在 C 中。所以它有相当多的代码行
to accomplish that task, only three of which
来完成这项任务，其中只有三行
are really the logical part of my program.
才是程序的逻辑部分。
These are the three that we're really interested in.
这三行才是我们真正感兴趣的。
So let me instead now do this, code of calculator.py,
所以现在让我做这件事，calculator.py 的代码，
which is going to give me a new tab.
这将给我一个新标签。
Let me just drag it over to the right so I can view these side by side.
让我把它拖到右边，这样我就可以并排查看它们。
And in calculator.py, let's do this.
在 calculator.py 中，让我们这样做。
From the CS50 library, import the get_int() function,
从 CS50 库中导入 get_int() 函数，
which is also available.
它也是可用的。
Then let's go ahead and create a variable called x and set it equal
然后，让我们创建一个名为 x 的变量并将其设置为
to the return value of get_int(), passing in the same prompt--
get_int() 的返回值，传入相同的提示 -
no semicolon, no mention of int.
没有分号，没有提到 int。
Let's then create a second variable y, set it equal to get_int(),
然后让我们创建一个第二个变量 y，将其设置为 get_int()，
prompt the user for y, as before, no int, explicitly, no semicolon.
提示用户输入 y，如前所述，没有 int，明确地，没有分号。
And now let's just go ahead and print out x + y.
现在让我们直接打印出 x + y。
So it turns out that the print() function in Python is further flexible,
事实证明，Python 中的 print() 函数更加灵活，
that you don't need these format strings.
你不需要这些格式字符串。
If you want to print out an integer, just pass it an integer,
如果你想打印一个整数，只需传入一个整数，
even if that integer is the sum of two other integers.
即使该整数是另外两个整数的和。
So it just sort of works as you might expect.
所以它就像你预期的那样工作。
So let me go down into my terminal here.
所以让我进入我的终端。
Let me run python of calculator.py.
让我运行 calculator.py 的 python。
And when I hit Enter, I'm prompted for x.
当我按下 Enter 键时，它会提示我输入 x。
Let's do 1.
让我们输入 1。
I'm prompted for y.
它会提示我输入 y。
Let's do 2.
让我们输入 2。
And voila, I should see 3 as the result--
瞧，我应该看到结果是 3 -
so no actual surprises there.
所以没有真正的意外。
But let me go ahead and, you know what?
但是让我继续，你知道吗？
Let's take away this training wheel, right?
让我们去掉这个训练轮，对吧？
We don't want to keep introducing CS50-specific things.
我们不想一直介绍 CS50 特定的东西。
So suppose we didn't give you get_int().
假设我们没有给你 get_int()。
Well, it turns out that get_int() is still doing a bit of help for you,
好吧，事实证明 get_int() 仍然在帮助你，
even though get_string() was kind of a throwaway and we could replace
即使 get_string() 是一种一次性的，我们可以用
get_string() with input().
input() 替换 get_string()。
So let's try this same idea.
所以让我们尝试一下这个想法。
Let's go ahead and prompt the user for input for both x and y using
让我们使用
the input() function in Python instead of get_int() from CS50.
Python 中的 input() 函数而不是 CS50 中的 get_int()，来提示用户输入 x 和 y。
Let me go ahead and rerun Python of calculator.py and hit Enter.
让我继续重新运行 calculator.py 的 Python 并按下 Enter。
So far, so good.
到目前为止，一切顺利。
Let me type in 1.
让我输入 1。
Let me type in 2.
让我输入 2。
And what answer should we see?
我们应该看到什么答案？
Hopefully still 3, but nope.
希望仍然是 3，但不是。
Now the answer is 12, or is it?
现在答案是 12，还是？
Why am I seeing 12 and not 3?
为什么我看到的是 12 而不是 3？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] two strings.
观众：[听不清] 两个字符串。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
So it's actually concatenating what seem to be two strings.
所以它实际上是连接了两个看似是字符串的东西。
So if we actually read the documentation for the input() function,
所以如果我们实际阅读 input() 函数的文档，
it's behaving exactly as it's supposed to.
它的行为完全符合预期。
It is getting input from the user from their keyboard.
它正在从用户的键盘获取输入。
But anything you type at the keyboard is effectively a string.
但是你在键盘上输入的任何东西实际上都是一个字符串。
Even if some of the symbols happen to look like or actually
即使某些符号碰巧看起来像或实际上
be decimal numbers, they're still going to come to you as strings.
是十进制数，它们仍然会作为字符串传递给你。
And so x is a string, a.k.a., str, y is a str,
所以 x 是一个字符串，也就是 str，y 也是一个 str，
and we've already seen that if you use plus in between two strings, or strs,
我们已经看到，如果你在两个字符串或 strs 之间使用加号，
you're going to get concatenation, not addition.
你将得到连接，而不是加法。
So you're not seeing 12 as much as you're seeing 1 2, not 12.
所以你看到的不是 12，而是 1 2，而不是 12。
So how can we fix this?
那么我们该如何解决这个问题？
Well, in C, we had this technique where we could cast one thing to another
好吧，在 C 中，我们有这种技术，我们可以将一个东西转换为另一个东西
by just putting int in parentheses, for instance.
例如，只需将 int 放入括号中。
In Python, things are a little higher-level such
在 Python 中，事物级别更高一些
that you can't quite get away with just casting
以至于你不能仅仅通过强制转换就解决问题
one thing to another because a string, recall, is not
一个东西到另一个东西，因为一个字符串，回忆一下，不是
the same thing as a char.
与 char 相同。
A string has zero or more characters.
一个字符串有零个或多个字符。
A char always has one.
一个 char 始终只有一个。
And in C, there was a perfect mapping between single characters
而在 C 中，单个字符之间存在完美的映射
and single numbers in decimal, like 65 for capital A.
以及十进制的单个数字，例如 65 代表大写字母 A。
But in Python, we can do something somewhat similar and not so much cast
但在 Python 中，我们可以做一些类似的事情，而不是强制转换
but convert this input() to an int and convert this input() to an int.
而是将这个 input() 转换为 int，并将这个 input() 转换为 int。
So just like in C, you can nest functions.
所以就像在 C 中一样，你可以嵌套函数。
You can call one function and pass its output
你可以调用一个函数，并将它的输出
as the input to another function.
作为另一个函数的输入。
And this now will convert x and y to integers.
现在这将把 x 和 y 转换为整数。
And so now plus is going to behave as you should-- as you would expect.
所以现在加号将按照你应该的方式，也就是你期望的方式工作。
Let me rerun python of calculator.py, type in 1, type in 2, and now
让我重新运行 calculator.py 的 python，输入 1，输入 2，现在
we're back to seeing 3 as the result. If this is a little unclear,
我们又看到结果是 3 了。如果这一点不太清楚，
this nesting, let me do this one other way.
这种嵌套，让我用另一种方式来做。
Instead of just passing input() output into int,
而不是简单地将 input() 的输出传递给 int，
I could also more pedantically do this.
我也可以更严格地这样做。
x should actually equal int(x), y should actually equal int(y).
x 实际上应该等于 int(x)，y 实际上应该等于 int(y)。
This would be the exact same effect.
这将产生完全相同的效果。
It's just two extra lines where it's not really necessary.
它只是两行额外的代码，实际上并不必要。
But that would work fine.
但这样也能正常工作。
If you don't like that approach, we could even do it inline.
如果你不喜欢这种方法，我们甚至可以在一行代码中完成。
We could actually convert x to an int and y to an int.
我们实际上可以将 x 转换为 int，并将 y 转换为 int。
Why?
为什么？
Well, int, I-N-T, in the context of Python itself, is a function.
嗯，int，I-N-T，在 Python 本身中，是一个函数。
And it takes as input here a string, or str,
它将字符串（或str）作为输入，
and returns to you the numeric, the integral equivalent-- so similar idea,
并返回给您数值，即整数等价物——所以概念类似，
but it's actually a function.
但它实际上是一个函数。
So all of the syntax that I've been tinkering with here
所以，我一直在这里调试的语法
is sort of fundamentally the same as it would be in C. But in this case,
从根本上来说与C语言中的语法相同。但在这种情况下，
we're not casting but converting more specifically.
我们不是类型转换，而是更确切地说是转换。
Well, let me go back to these data types.
好吧，让我回到这些数据类型。
These are some of the data types that are available to us in Python.
这些是Python中可用的数据类型。
It turns out there's a bunch of others as well
事实证明还有很多其他的类型
that we'll start to dabble with today.
我们今天会开始尝试。
You can get a range of values, a list of values,
您可以获得一系列值、一组值，
which is going to be like an array, but better, tuples, which
这就像数组，但更好；元组，它
are kind of like x, comma, y, often, combinations of values that
就像x、逗号、y一样，通常是值的组合，
don't change.
不会改变。
dict for dictionary-- it turns out that in Python, you get dictionaries.
dict代表字典——事实证明，在Python中，您可以获得字典。
You get hash tables for free.
您免费获得哈希表。
They're built into the language.
它们是语言的一部分。
And we already saw that Python also gives you
我们已经看到，Python也为您提供了
a data type known as a set, which is just
一种称为集合的数据类型，它只是一个
a collection of values that gives you--
值的集合，它为您提供——
gets rid of any duplicates for you.
为您清除所有重复项。
And as we saw briefly in speller-- and we'll play more with these ideas soon--
我们在拼写器中简单地看到了这一点——我们很快就会更多地尝试这些概念——
it's going to actually be pretty darn easy to get values or check
实际上，获取或检查这些数据类型中的值会非常容易。
for values in those there data types.
在这些数据类型中检查值。
So that in C, we were able to get input easily, we had all of these functions.
所以在C语言中，我们可以轻松地获取输入，我们拥有所有这些函数。
In the CS50 library for Python, we're only going to give you these instead.
在Python的CS50库中，我们将只提供这些函数。
They're going to be the same name.
它们将具有相同的名称。
So it's still get_string(), not get_str, because we wanted the functions
所以仍然是get_string()，而不是get_str，因为我们希望函数
to remain named the same.
保持相同的名称。
But get_float(), get_int(), get_string() all exist.
但get_float()、get_int()、get_string()都存在。
But, again, get_string() is not all that useful.
但是，再次强调，get_string()并不是那么有用。
But get_int() and get_float() actually are.
但get_int()和get_float()实际上很有用。
Why?
为什么？
Well, let me go back to VS Code here.
好吧，让我回到VS Code这里。
And let me go back to the second version of this program,
让我回到这个程序的第二个版本，
whereby I proactively converted each of these return values to integers.
在这个版本中，我主动地将这些返回值都转换为整数。
So recall that this is the solution to the 1 2 problem.
所以，回想一下，这是1 2问题的解决方案。
And to be clear, if I run python of calculator.py and input 1 and 2,
明确地说，如果我运行calculator.py并输入1和2，
I get back now 3 as expected.
现在我会得到3，如预期。
But what I'm not showing you is that there's still potentially a bug here.
但我没有告诉您的是，这里仍然存在潜在的错误。
Let me run python of calculator.py, and let me just not cooperate.
让我运行calculator.py，并且不配合。
Instead of typing what looks like a number,
而不是输入看起来像数字的东西，
let me actually type something that's clearly a string, like cat.
让我输入明显是字符串的东西，比如“cat”。
And unfortunately, we're going to see the first of our errors,
不幸的是，我们将看到我们的第一个错误，
the first of our runtime errors.
第一个运行时错误。
And this, like in C, is going to look cryptic at first.
就像C语言一样，一开始看起来很神秘。
But this is generally known as a traceback, where
但它通常被称为回溯，它
it's going to trace back for you everything your program just did,
它将为你跟踪回溯程序刚刚执行的所有操作，
even though this one's relatively short.
即使这段代码相对较短。
And you'll see that calculator.py, line 1--
你会看到 calculator.py 文件，第一行——
I didn't even get very far before there's an error.
我还没有执行多远就出现了错误。
And then, with all of these carrot symbols here, this is a problem.
然后，这里所有这些尖括号符号都表示存在问题。
Why?
为什么？
invalid literal for int() function with base 10, quote unquote, 'cat.'
“使用基数 10 为 int() 函数提供的无效文字，引号内的文字是 'cat'。”
Again, just like in C, It's very arcane.
同样，就像在 C 语言中一样，这很深奥。
It's hard to understand this the first time you read it.
第一次读到它时很难理解。
But what it's trying to tell me is that cat is not an integer.
但它试图告诉我的是，“cat”不是一个整数。
And therefore, the int() function cannot convert it to an integer for you.
因此，int() 函数无法将其转换为整数。
We're going to leave this problem alone for now.
我们现在先放着这个问题。
But this is why, again, get_int()'s looking kind of good,
但这就是为什么，get_int() 看起来还不错，
and get_float()'s looking kind of good because those functions from
get_float() 也看起来还不错，因为来自
CS50's library will deal with these kinds of problems for you.
CS50 库的这些函数将为你处理这些问题。
Now, just so you've seen it, there's another way
现在，为了让你了解，还有另一种方法
to import functions from these things.
从这些文件中导入函数。
If you were to use, for instance, in a program, get_float(), get_int(),
例如，如果你要在程序中使用 get_float()，get_int()，
and get_string(), you don't need to do three separate lines like this.
和 get_string()，你不需要像这样写三行单独的代码。
You can actually separate them a little more cleanly with commas.
实际上，你可以用逗号更简洁地将它们分开。
And, in fact, if I go back to a version of this program here in VS Code whereby
事实上，如果我回到这个程序在 VS Code 中的一个版本，在这里
I actually do use the get_int() function--
我确实使用了 get_int() 函数——
so let me actually get rid of all this and use get_int() as before.
所以让我实际上去掉所有这些代码，就像以前一样使用 get_int()。
Let me get rid of all this and use get_int() as before.
让我去掉所有这些代码，就像以前一样使用 get_int()。
Previously, the way I did this was by saying from cs50 import get_int()
以前，我使用的方式是说 from cs50 import get_int()
if you know in advance what function you want to use.
如果你事先知道要使用哪个函数。
But suppose, for whatever reason, you already have your own function named
但假设，由于某种原因，你已经有了自己的名为
get_int(), and therefore, it would collide with CS50's own,
get_int() 的函数，因此，它将与 CS50 的函数冲突，
you can avoid that issue, too, by just using that first statement we saw
你也可以通过使用我们之前看到的第一个语句来避免这个问题
earlier.
更早。
Just import the library itself.
只需导入库本身。
Don't specify explicitly which functions you're going to use.
不要明确指定要使用的函数。
But thereafter-- and you could not do this in C--
但是之后——你不能在 C 语言中这样做——
you could specify cs50.get_int(), cs50.get_int(),
你可以指定 cs50.get_int()，cs50.get_int()，
in order to go into the library, access its get_int() function, and therefore,
以便进入库，访问它的 get_int() 函数，因此，
it doesn't matter if you or any number of other people wrote
无论你或其他任何人是否写了
an identically-named function called get_int().
一个名为 get_int() 的同名函数。
You're using here, clearly, CS50's own.
你在这里使用的是 CS50 自己的函数。
So this is, again, just more ways to achieve the same solution
所以，这又是另一种实现相同解决方案的方法
but with different syntax.
但使用了不同的语法。
All right.
好的。
Any questions about any of this syntax or features thus far?
到目前为止，对任何语法或功能有任何疑问吗？
No?
没有吗？
All right.
好的。
Well, how about maybe another example here,
那么，这里再举个例子，
whereby we revisit conditionals, which was the way of implementing
我们重新回顾一下条件语句，这是实现的一种方式。
do this thing or this thing, sort of proverbial forks in the road.
做这件事或那件事，就像谚语中说的岔路口。
In Scratch, recall, we might use building blocks like these
还记得 Scratch 中，我们可以使用这样的积木
to just check, is x less than y, and if so, say so.
来检查，x 是否小于 y，如果是，就说出来。
In C, this code looked like this.
在 C 中，这段代码看起来是这样的。
And notice that we had parentheses around the x and the y.
请注意，我们在 x 和 y 周围加了括号。
We had curly braces, even though I did disclaim that for single lines of code,
我们有花括号，即使我确实声明了，对于单行代码，
you can actually omit the curly braces.
实际上可以省略花括号。
But stylistically, we always include them in CS50's code.
但从风格上来说，我们始终在 CS50 的代码中包含它们。
But you have the backslash n and the semicolon.
但你有反斜杠 n 和分号。
In a moment, you're about to see the Python equivalent of this,
一会儿，你将看到这段代码的 Python 等价物，
which is almost the same.
它几乎一样。
It's just a little nicer.
只是它稍微好一点。
This, then, is the Python equivalent thereof.
然后，这就是它的 Python 等价物。
So what's different at a glance here, just to be clear?
那么，一目了然，这里有什么不同，为了更清楚起见？
What's different?
有什么不同？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: So the conditional is not in parentheses.
所以条件语句不在括号里。
You can use parentheses, especially if, logically, you need to group things.
你可以使用括号，尤其是在逻辑上，你需要将某些东西分组的时候。
But if you don't need them, don't use them is Python's mindset.
但如果你不需要它们，就不要用它们，这是 Python 的理念。
What else has changed here?
这里还有什么变化？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: No curly brackets.
观众：没有花括号。
DAVID MALAN: No curly braces, yeah, so no curly braces around this.
没有花括号，是的，所以这里没有花括号。
And even though it's one line of code, you just don't use curly braces at all.
即使它只有一行代码，你也根本不用花括号。
Why?
为什么？
Because in Python, indentation is actually really, really important.
因为在 Python 中，缩进实际上非常非常重要。
And we know from office hours and problem sets
我们从办公室时间和作业集中知道
occasionally that if you forgot to run style50
有时，如果你忘记运行 style50
or you didn't manually format your code beautifully,
或者你没有手动格式化你的代码使其美观，
C is not actually going to care if everything is aligned on the left.
C 实际上并不关心所有内容是否都左对齐。
If you never once hit the Tab character or the space bar,
如果你从未按下过 Tab 键或空格键，
C, or specifically, clang, isn't really going to care.
C，或者更确切地说，clang，实际上并不关心。
But your teaching fellow, your TA, is going
但你的助教，你的助教，将要
to care, or your colleague in the real world, because your code's just a mess
关心，或者你现实世界中的同事，因为你的代码只是一团糟
and hard to read.
而且难以阅读。
Python, though-- because you are not the only ones in the world that might have
不过，Python-- 因为你并不是世界上唯一一个可能会有
bad habits when it comes to style--
关于风格的坏习惯的人--
Python as a language decided, that's it.
Python 作为一门语言决定了，就这样。
Everyone has to indent in order for their code to even work.
每个人都必须缩进才能让他们的代码正常工作。
So the convention as Python is to use for spaces--
所以 Python 的惯例是使用 4 个空格--
so 1, 2, 3, 4, or hit Tab and let it automatically convert to the same,
所以 1、2、3、4，或者按下 Tab 键，让它自动转换为相同的值，
and use a colon instead of the curly braces,
并使用冒号代替花括号，
for instance, to make clear what is associated
例如，为了清楚地表明什么与
with this particular conditional.
这个特定的条件语句相关。
We can omit, though, the backslash n per before.
不过，我们可以像之前一样省略反斜杠 n。
We can omit the semicolon.
我们可以省略分号。
But this is essentially the Python version thereof.
但这本质上是它的 Python 版本。
Here in C-- in Scratch, if you wanted to do an if-else,
在 C 中-- 在 Scratch 中，如果你想做一个 if-else 语句，
like we did back in week 0, in C, It's very similar to the if, except you add
就像我们在第 0 周做的那样，在 C 中，它与 if 非常相似，除了你需要添加
the else clause and write out an additional printf() like this.
else 子句并像这样写出另一个 printf()。
In Python, we can tighten this up.
在 Python 中，我们可以简化它。
if x less than y, colon, that's exactly the same.
如果 x 小于 y，冒号，这完全一样。
First line's the same.
第一行相同。
All we're doing now is adding an else and the second print line here.
我们现在所做的只是在这里添加一个 else 和第二行打印语句。
How about in Scratch?
在 Scratch 中呢？
If we had a three-way fork in the road-- if, else, if, else.
如果我们有一条三岔路口 - if、else、if、else。
In C, it looked pretty much like that-- if, else, if, else.
在 C 中，它看起来很像这样 - if、else、if、else。
In Python, we can tighten this up.
在 Python 中，我们可以简化它。
And this is not a typo.
这不是打字错误。
What jumps out at you as weird but you got to just get used to it?
有什么让你觉得奇怪但你必须习惯的东西吗？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: elif.
观众：elif。
DAVID MALAN: elif.
大卫·马兰：elif。
And honestly, years later, I still can't remember if it's elif or elsif
说实话，几年过去了，我仍然记不住是 elif 还是 elsif
because other languages actually do E-L-S-I-F.
因为其他语言实际上使用的是 E-L-S-I-F。
and now I probably now biased all of you to now questioning this.
现在我可能让你们所有人都开始质疑这个问题了。
But it's elif in Python.
但在 Python 中是 elif。
E-L-I-F is not a typo.
E-L-I-F 不是打字错误。
It's in the spirit of let's just save ourselves some keystrokes.
这是为了节省按键次数。
So elif is identical to elsif, but it's a little tighter to type it this way.
所以 elif 与 elsif 相同，但这样打起来更紧凑。
All right.
好的。
So if we now have this ability to express conditionals,
所以，如果我们现在有了表达条件语句的能力，
what can we actually do with them?
我们实际上可以用它们做什么？
Well, let me go over to VS Code here.
好吧，让我到 VS Code 中去看看。
And let me propose that we revisit maybe another program from before,
我建议我们再看一个之前的程序，
where we just compare two integers in particular.
我们只是比较两个特定的整数。
So I'm in VS Code.
所以我在 VS Code 中。
Let me open up a file called, say, compare.py.
让我打开一个文件，例如，compare.py。
And in compare.py, we'll use the CS50 library just
在 compare.py 中，我们将使用 CS50 库，
so we don't risk any errors, like if the human doesn't type an integer.
这样我们就不会冒任何错误的风险，例如，如果用户没有输入一个整数。
So we're going to go ahead and say from cs50 import get_int().
所以，我们将使用 from cs50 import get_int()。
And in compare.py, let's get two variables-- x = get_int(),
在 compare.py 中，让我们获取两个变量 - x = get_int()，
and prompt the user for x.
并提示用户输入 x。
So "What's x?"
所以，“x 是多少？”
To be a bit more verbose, y = get+int("What's y? ")
为了更详细一些，y = get+int("y 是多少？")
And then let's go ahead and just compare these two values.
然后，让我们比较一下这两个值。
So if x is less than y, then go ahead and print out with print("x is less
所以，如果 x 小于 y，那么使用 print("x 小于
than y"), close quote, elif x is greater than y,
y")，关闭引号，如果 x 大于 y，
go ahead and print out "x is greater than y," close quote, else,
那么使用 "x 大于 y"，关闭引号，否则，
go ahead and print out "x is equal to y"-- so the exact same program,
使用 "x 等于 y" - 所以是完全相同的程序，
but I've added to the mix getting a value of x and y.
但我添加了获取 x 和 y 值的功能。
Let me run python of compare.py.
让我运行 compare.py 的 Python 脚本。
Enter.
输入。
Let's type in 1 for x, 2 for y. x is less than y.
让我们输入 1 作为 x，2 作为 y。x 小于 y。
Let's run it once more.
让我们再运行一次。
x is 2. y is 1.
x 是 2，y 是 1。
x is greater than y.
x 大于 y。
And just for good measure, let's run it a third time. x is 1.
为了确保，让我们再运行一次。x 是 1。
y is 1.
y 等于 1。
x is equal to y.
x 等于 y。
So the code, daresay, works exactly as you would expect, as you would hope.
所以这段代码，我可以肯定地说，它完全按照你预期的那样工作，就像你希望的那样。
But it turns out that in the world of Python,
但事实证明，在 Python 的世界里，
we're actually going to get some other behavior that might actually
我们实际上会得到一些其他的行为，这些行为可能实际上
have been what you expected weeks ago, even though C did not behave this way.
是你几周前所期待的，即使 C 的行为并非如此。
In the world of Python and in the world of strings, a.k.a.
在 Python 的世界里，以及在字符串的世界里，也就是
strs, strings actually behave more like you would expect.
strs，字符串实际上更符合你的预期。
So by that I mean this.
我的意思是这个。
Let me actually go back to this code.
让我回到这段代码。
And instead of using integers, let me go ahead and get rid of--
而不是使用整数，让我继续去掉 -
I could do get_string(), but we said that that's not really necessary.
我可以使用 get_string()，但我们说过那不是真的必要。
So let's just go ahead and change this to input().
所以让我们直接把这个改成 input()。
And actually, you know what?
实际上，你知道吗？
Let's just start fresh.
让我们从头开始。
Let's give myself a string called s and use the input() function and ask
让我们给自己一个叫做 s 的字符串，并使用 input() 函数，然后询问
the user for s.
用户输入 s。
Let's use another variable called t just because it comes after s and use
让我们使用另一个叫做 t 的变量，因为它在 s 之后，并使用
the input() function to get t.
input() 函数来获取 t。
Then let's compare if s and t are the same.
然后让我们比较 s 和 t 是否相同。
Now, a couple of weeks ago, this backfired.
现在，几周前，这反倒起了作用。
And if I tried to compare two strings for equality, it did not work.
如果我尝试比较两个字符串是否相等，它没有奏效。
But if I do if s == t, print("Same"), else,
但如果我执行 if s == t，print("Same")，否则，
let's go ahead and print("Different").
让我们继续打印 "Different"。
I daresay, in Python, I think this is going to work as you would expect.
我可以肯定地说，在 Python 中，我认为这将按照你预期的那样工作。
So python of compare.py, let's type in cat and cat.
所以 python 的 compare.py，让我们输入 cat 和 cat。
And indeed those are the same.
确实它们是相同的。
Let me run it again and type in cat and dog, respectively.
让我再次运行它，并分别输入 cat 和 dog。
And those are now different.
现在它们不同了。
But in C, we always got "Different," "Different," "Different,"
但在 C 中，我们总是得到 "Different"，"Different"，"Different"，
even if I typed the exact same word, be it cat or dog or high or anything else.
即使我输入完全相同的词，无论是 cat 还是 dog 还是 high，或者其他任何东西。
Why, in C, were s and t always different a couple of weeks ago?
为什么，在 C 中，几周前 s 和 t 总是不同的？
Yeah?
对吧？
AUDIENCE: Because it was comparing the value of the char* with the memory
观众：因为它是比较 char* 的值和内存
address.
地址。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
DAVID MALAN：没错。
In C, string is the same thing as char*, which is a memory address.
在 C 中，字符串与 char* 是同一个东西，它是一个内存地址。
And because we had called get_string() twice,
因为我们两次调用了 get_string()，
even if the human typed the same things, that was two different chunks of memory
即使人输入了相同的东西，那也是两块不同的内存
at two different addresses.
在两个不同的地址。
So those two char*s were just naturally always different,
所以这两个 char* 自然总是不同的，
even if the characters at those addresses were the same.
即使这些地址上的字符是相同的。
Python is meant to be higher-level.
Python 旨在成为更高级别的语言。
It's meant to be a little more intuitive.
它旨在更直观一些。
It's meant to be more accessible to folks who might not necessarily
它旨在更容易被那些可能不一定
know or want to understand those lower-level details.
了解或想要了解这些低级细节的人所使用。
So in Python, ==, even for strings just works the way that you might expect.
所以在 Python 中，==，即使对于字符串，也按照你预期的那样工作。
But in Python, we can do some other things,
但在 Python 中，我们可以做一些其他的事情，
too, even more easily than we could in C. Let me go back to VS Code here.
而且比我们在 C 中更容易。让我回到 VS Code 这里。
Let me close compare.py.
让我关闭 compare.py。
And let's reimplement a program from C called agree,
让我们重新实现一个来自 C 的名为 agree 的程序，
which allowed us to prompt the user for a yes/no question, like,
它允许我们提示用户一个是/否问题，例如，
do you agree to these terms and conditions or something like that.
你是否同意这些条款和条件或类似的东西。
So let's do code of agree.py.
所以让我们编写 agree.py 的代码。
And with agree.py, let me go ahead and--
在 agree.py 中，让我继续，
actually, let's go ahead and do this.
实际上，让我们继续这样做。
Let me also open up a file that I came with in advance.
让我打开一个我事先准备好的文件。
And this is called agree.c.
它叫做 agree.c。
And this is what we did some weeks ago when
几周前我们就是这样做的，
we wanted to check whether or not the user had agreed to something or not.
我们想要检查用户是否同意某件事。
So we used the CS50 library, the standard I/O library,
所以我们使用了 CS50 库，标准 I/O 库，
we had a main() function, we used get_char().
我们有一个 main() 函数，我们使用了 get_char()。
And then we used == a lot, and we used the two vertical bars,
然后我们使用了 == 很多次，也使用了两个竖线，
which meant logical or.
这意味着逻辑或。
Is this thing true or is this thing true?
这东西是真的还是这东西是真的？
And if so, printf() "Agreed" or "Not agreed."
如果是，则打印 "Agreed" 或 "Not agreed."
So this worked.
所以这有效。
And this is relatively simple.
这相对简单。
That's the right way to do it in C. But notice
这是在 C 中做这件事的正确方法。但请注意
it was a little verbose because we wanted
它有点冗长，因为我们想要
to handle uppercase and lowercase, uppercase and lowercase.
处理大小写，大小写。
So that did start to bloat the code, admittedly.
所以不可否认，这确实让代码膨胀了。
So let's try to do the same thing in Python
所以让我们尝试在 Python 中做同样的事情
and see what we can do the same or different-- no pun intended.
看看我们可以做哪些相同或不同的事情——没有双关语。
So let me do this.
所以让我这样做。
In agree.py, why don't we try to get input from the user as before?
在 agree.py 中，我们为什么不尝试像以前一样从用户获取输入？
And I will use--
我会使用——
I could use get_string(), but I'll go ahead and use input().
我可以使用 get_string()，但我将继续使用 input()。
So s = input("Do you agree? ") in double quotes.
所以 s = input("Do you agree? ") 用双引号。
And then let's go ahead and check if s == "Y"--
然后让我们继续检查 s 是否等于 "Y"——
and it's not vertical bar now, it's actually more readable,
现在不是竖线了，实际上更易读了，
more English-like-- or s == "y," then go ahead and print out "Agreed" as before,
更像英语——或者 s == "y"，然后继续打印 "Agreed" 就像以前一样，
elsif--
否则——
see, I did it there-- elif s == "N" or s == "n,"
看，我在那里做了——elif s == "N" 或者 s == "n"，
go ahead and print out "Not agreed."
继续打印 "Not agreed."
So it's almost the same as the C version, except that I'm using,
所以它几乎与 C 版本相同，除了我正在使用，
literally, O-R instead of two vertical bars.
实际上，O-R 而不是两个竖线。
So let's run this-- so python of agree.py.
所以让我们运行这个——所以 python agree.py。
Enter.
输入。
Do I agree?
我同意吗？
Yes, for little y.
是的，是小写 y。
Let's do it again. python of agree.py, capital Y. Yes.
让我们再做一次。python agree.py，大写 Y。是的。
That works there.
在那里有效。
And if I do it again with lowercase n, and if I do it
如果我再用小写 n 做一遍，如果我做
with capital N, this program, too, seems to work.
用大写 N，这个程序也似乎有效。
But what if I do this?
但如果我这样做呢？
Let me rerun python of agree.py.
让我重新运行 python agree.py。
Let me type in Yes.
让我输入“Yes”。
OK, it just ignores me.
好的，它直接忽略了我。
Let me run it again.
让我重新运行它。
Let me type in no.
让我输入“no”。
It just ignores me.
它直接忽略了我。
Let me try it very emphatically, YES in all caps.
让我尝试一下，非常肯定地，用全大写字母输入“YES”。
It just ignores me.
它直接忽略了我。
So there's some explosion of possibilities
所以存在着大量的可能性
that ideally we should handle, right?
理想情况下，我们应该处理这些可能性，对吧？
This is bad user interface design if I have-- the user has to type Y or N,
如果我必须让用户输入“Y”或“N”，这将是糟糕的用户界面设计，
even if yes and no in English are perfectly reasonable and logical, too.
即使英语中的“yes”和“no”也很合理，也很逻辑。
So how could we handle that?
我们该如何处理这种情况呢？
Well, it turns out in Python, we can use something like an array,
事实证明，在 Python 中，我们可以使用类似数组的东西，
technically called a list, to maybe check a bunch of things at once.
在技术上称为列表，用来同时检查很多东西。
So let me do this.
让我来做这个。
Let me instead say not equality, but let me use the in keyword in Python
与其说是不等，不如让我在 Python 中使用“in”关键字
and check if it's in a collection of possible values.
并检查它是否在一个可能的取值集合中。
Let me say if s is in--
让我说如果 s 在...
and here comes, in square brackets, just like--
这里出现了，在方括号中，就像...
in square brackets, quote unquote, "y", quote unquote, "yes,"
在方括号中，引号引起来，"y"，引号引起来，"yes"，
then we can go ahead and print out "Agreed,"
那么我们可以继续打印出“Agreed”，
elif s in this list of values, lowercase "n" or lowercase "no,"
或者如果 s 在这个取值列表中，小写字母 "n" 或小写字母 "no"，
then we can print out, for instance, "Not agreed."
那么我们可以打印出，例如，“Not agreed”。
But this is a bit of a step backwards because now
但这有点倒退，因为现在
I'm only handling lowercase.
我只处理小写字母。
So let me go into the mix and maybe add capital "Y"--
所以让我来混合一下，可能还要添加大写字母“Y”...
wait a minute, then maybe capital "YES," then maybe "YeS," also--
等等，然后是大写字母“YES”，然后是“YeS”，还有...
I mean, weird, but we should probably support this and "YEs."
我的意思是，很奇怪，但我们应该支持这个和“YEs”。
I mean, there's a lot of combinations.
我的意思是，有很多组合。
So this is not going to end well.
所以结局不会很好。
Or it's just going to bloat my code unnecessarily.
或者它会不必要地膨胀我的代码。
And eventually, for longer words, I'm surely going to miss capitalization.
最终，对于更长的单词，我肯定会忽略大小写。
So logically, whether it's in Python or C or any language,
所以从逻辑上讲，无论是在 Python、C 还是任何语言中，
what might be a better design for this problem of handling Y and Yes,
对于处理“Y”和“Yes”这个问题，一个更好的设计是什么？
but who cares about the capitalization?
但谁在乎大小写呢？
AUDIENCE: Don't use capitals or [INAUDIBLE]
观众：不要使用大写字母或...（听不清）
DAVID MALAN: So OK, so don't use capitals.
大卫·马兰：好的，所以不要使用大写字母。
You could only support lowercase.
你只能支持小写字母。
That's fine.
这样可以。
That's kind of a copout, right?
这有点像逃避责任，对吧？
Because now the program's usability is worse.
因为现在程序的可使用性变差了。
AUDIENCE: Convert it.
观众：转换它。
DAVID MALAN: Oh, we could convert it to lowercase, yeah.
大卫·马兰：哦，我们可以把它转换成小写字母，是的。
Though I did hear you say we could just check the first letter,
虽然我听到你说我们可以只检查第一个字母，
I bet that's going to get us into trouble.
我打赌那会让我们陷入麻烦。
And we probably don't want to allow any word starting
我们可能不想允许任何以...开头的单词
with Y, any word starting with N, just because it logically-- especially you
以 Y 开头的单词，任何以 N 开头的单词，仅仅是因为它在逻辑上...尤其是你
want the lawyers happy, presumably.
希望律师开心，可以理解。
You should probably get an explicit semantically correct word like Y or N
你应该获得一个语义上正确的明确单词，比如 Y 或 N
or yes or no.
或者 yes 或者 no。
But, yeah, we can actually go about converting this to something
但是，是的，我们实际上可以将它转换成一些东西
maybe smaller.
可能更小。
But how do we go about converting this?
但是我们如何进行转换呢？
In C, that alone was going to be pretty darn annoying because we'd have to use
在 C 语言中，仅此一项就相当令人厌烦，因为我们必须使用
the tolower() function on every character and compare it for equality.
tolower() 函数对每个字符进行比较，以检查是否相等。
It just feels like that's a bit of work.
感觉这有点工作量。
But in Python, you're going to get more functionality for free.
但在 Python 中，你会免费获得更多功能。
So there might very well be a function, like in C,
所以，可能会有一个函数，就像在 C 语言中一样，
called tolower() or toupper().
叫做 tolower() 或 toupper()。
But the weird thing about C, perhaps in retrospect,
但是 C 语言的奇怪之处，也许是事后看来，
is that those functions just kind of worked on the honor system.
就是这些函数只是在荣誉制度下运行。
tolower() and toupper() just trusted that you would pass them an input,
tolower() 和 toupper() 只相信你会传递给他们一个输入，
an argument, that is, in fact, a char.
一个参数，即一个 char。
In Python, and in a lot of other higher-level languages,
在 Python 以及许多其他高级语言中，
they introduced this notion of Object-Oriented Programming,
他们引入了面向对象编程的概念，
which is commonly described as OOP.
通常被描述为 OOP。
And in the world of Object-Oriented Programming,
在面向对象编程的世界中，
your values can not only-- your variables,
你的值不仅可以，你的变量，
for instance, and your data types can not only have values.
例如，你的数据类型不仅可以拥有值。
They can also have functionality built into them.
它们还可以具有内置的功能。
So if you have a data type like a string,
所以，如果你有一个像字符串这样的数据类型，
frankly, it just makes good sense that strings
坦白地说，字符串应该可以转换为大写、小写、首字母大写，
should be uppercaseable, lowercaseable, capitalizable,
这是合理的。
and any number of other operations on strings.
以及字符串上的许多其他操作。
So in the world of object-oriented programming functions,
所以在面向对象编程的世界中，函数
like toupper() and tolower() and isupper() and islower() are not just
比如 toupper() 和 tolower() 以及 isupper() 和 islower()，不仅仅是
in some random library that you can use.
你在某个随机库中可以使用。
They're built into the strings themselves.
它们内置在字符串本身。
And what this means is that in the world of strings in Python,
这意味着在 Python 中的字符串世界中，
here, for instance, is the URL of the documentation for all of the functions,
例如，这里就是所有函数的文档的 URL，
otherwise known as methods, that come with strings.
也称为方法，它们与字符串一起出现。
So you don't go check for a C-type library
所以，你不用去检查 C 语言库
like we did in C. You check the actual data
就像我们在 C 语言中那样。你检查实际数据
type, the documentation, therefore, and you
类型，因此，文档，然后你
will see in Python's own documentation what functions, a.k.a.
会看到 Python 自己的文档中有哪些函数，又称
methods, come with strings.
方法，与字符串一起出现。
So a method is just a function.
所以，方法只是一个函数。
But it's a function that comes with some data type, like a string.
但它是一个与某种数据类型（比如字符串）一起出现的函数。
So let me propose that we do this.
所以，我建议我们这样做。
In the world of object-oriented programming,
在面向对象编程的世界中，
we can come back to agree.py.
我们可以回到 agree.py 文件。
And we can actually improve the program by getting
我们实际上可以通过消除
rid of this crazy long list, which I wasn't even done with,
这个疯狂的长列表（我甚至还没写完），
and just canonicalize everything as lowercase.
来改进程序，并将所有内容规范化为小写。
So let's just check for lowercase y and lowercase yes, lowercase
所以，我们只需要检查小写 y 和小写 yes，小写
n, lowercase no, and that's it.
n，小写 no，就这些。
But to your suggestion, let's force everything
但是根据你的建议，我们来强制所有内容
that the user types into lowercase, not because we want
用户输入的内容变成小写，不是因为我们想要
to permanently change their input--
永久地改变他们的输入 -
we can throw the value away thereafter-- but
我们可以在之后丢弃这个值 - 但是
because we want to more easily logically compare it
因为我们想更轻松地逻辑比较它
for membership in this list of values.
在这些值的列表中是否包含它。
So one way to do this would be to literally do s = s.lower().
所以一种方法是直接执行 s = s.lower()。
So here's the difference.
所以这就是区别。
In the world of C, we would have done this--
在 C 语言的世界里，我们会这样做 -
tolower and pass in the value s.
tolower 并传入值 s。
But in the world of Python, and, in general, object-oriented programming--
但是在 Python 的世界里，总的来说，在面向对象编程中 -
Java is another language that does this--
Java 也是另一门这样做的语言 -
if s is a string, a.k.a. str, therefore, s is actually
如果 s 是一个字符串，也称为 str，因此，s 实际上
what's known in Python as an object.
在 Python 中被称为一个对象。
An object can not only have values or attributes inside of them,
一个对象不仅可以在内部包含值或属性，
but also functionality built in.
还包含内置的功能。
And just like in C, with a struct, if you want to go inside of something,
就像在 C 中，使用结构体，如果你想进入某个东西的内部，
you use the dot operator.
你需要使用点运算符。
And inside of this string, I claim, is a function, a.k.a., method,
我声称在这个字符串内部，存在一个函数，也称为方法，
called lower().
叫做 lower()。
Long story short, the only takeaway, if this is a bit abstract,
长话短说，唯一需要记住的是，如果这有点抽象，
is that instead of doing lower and then, in parentheses,
就是，与其执行 lower 然后在括号里
s, in the world of object-oriented programming, you kind of flip that
是 s，在面向对象编程的世界里，你需要反过来
and you do s dot name of the method, and then open paren and close paren if you
并且你执行 s 点 方法名称，然后打开括号并关闭括号，如果你
don't need to pass in any arguments.
不需要传入任何参数。
So this actually achieves the same.
所以这实际上实现了相同的功能。
So let me go ahead and rerun agree.py, and let me type in lowercase y.
所以让我继续重新运行 agree.py，并且让我输入小写 y。
That works.
这可以。
Let me run it again, type in lowercase yes.
让我再次运行，输入小写 yes。
That works let me run it again, type in capital Y. That works.
这可以，让我再次运行，输入大写 Y，这可以。
Let me type in capital YES, all capital--
让我输入大写 YES，全部大写 -
all uppercase YES.
所有大写的 YES。
That too works.
这也行。
Let me try no.
让我尝试 no。
Let me try no in lowercase.
让我尝试小写 no。
And all of these permutations now actually work
现在这些排列组合都行
because I'm forcing it to lowercase.
因为我把它强制转换为小写。
But even more interestingly, in Python, if you're sort of becoming a languages
但更有趣的是，在 Python 中，如果你正在成为一个语言
person, if you have a variable s that is being set the return value of input()
人员，如果你有一个变量 s，它被设置为 input() 函数的返回值
function, and then you're immediately going about changing it to lowercase,
函数，然后你立即将其更改为小写，
you can also chain method calls together in something like Python by doing this.
你也可以在像 Python 这样的东西中将方法调用链接在一起，通过这样做。
We can get rid of this line altogether, and then I can just do this, .lower.
我们可以完全去掉这一行，然后我就可以这样做，.lower。
And so whatever the return value of input() is, it's going to be a str.
所以，无论 input() 的返回值是什么，它都会是一个 str。
Whatever the human types in, you can then immediately
无论人类输入什么，你都可以立即
force it to lowercase and then assign the whole value to this variable
将其强制转换为小写，然后将整个值分配给这个变量
called s.
叫做 s。
You don't actually have to wait around and do it on a separate line
你实际上不必等待并在单独的一行上执行它。
altogether.
总而言之。
Questions, then, on any of this?
那么，对此有任何问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right.
好的。
Let me do one other that's reminiscent of something we did in the past.
让我做另一个，它让人想起我们过去做过的事情。
Let me go into VS Code here, clear my terminal.
让我进入 VS Code，清除我的终端。
Let's close both the C and the Python version of agree.
让我们关闭 C 和 Python 版本的 agree。
And let's create a program called uppercase.py, whose purpose in life
让我们创建一个名为 uppercase.py 的程序，它的目的是
is to actually uppercase a whole string.
将整个字符串转换成大写。
In the world of C, we had to do this character by character by character.
在 C 的世界里，我们必须逐个字符地执行此操作。
And that's fine.
这很好。
I'm going to go ahead and do it similarly here
我将继续在这里以类似的方式进行操作
in Python, whereby I want to convert it character by character.
在 Python 中，我想要逐个字符地转换它。
But unfortunately, before I can do that, I actually
但不幸的是，在我能够做到之前，我实际上
need some way of looping in Python, which we actually haven't seen yet.
需要一些在 Python 中循环的方法，而我们实际上还没有见过。
So we need one more set of building blocks.
所以我们需要另一组构建块。
And, in fact, if we were to consult the Python documentation,
事实上，如果我们要查阅 Python 文档，
we'd see this and much more.
我们会看到这些以及更多内容。
So, in fact, here's a list of all of the functions that come with Python.
所以，实际上，这里列出了 Python 附带的所有函数。
And it's actually not that long of a list,
而且实际上这并不是一个很长的列表，
because so much of the functionality of Python is built into data types,
因为 Python 的很多功能都内置在数据类型中，
like strings and integers and floats and more.
比如字符串、整数、浮点数等等。
Here is the canonical source of truth for Python documentation.
这里是对 Python 文档的权威来源。
So as opposed to using the CS50 manual for C,
所以与使用 C 的 CS50 手册相反，
which is meant to be a simplified version of publicly
它旨在成为公开的简化版本
available documentation, we'll generally, for Python,
提供的文档，对于 Python，我们通常会
point you to the official docs.
把你指向官方文档。
I will disclaim they're not really written for introductory students.
我得说，它们并不是专门为入门学生编写的。
And they'll generally leave some detail off and use arcane language.
而且它们通常会省略一些细节，并使用晦涩难懂的语言。
But at this point in the term, even if it
但在本学期这个阶段，即使它
might be a little frustrating at first, it's
可能一开始会有点令人沮丧，但是
good to see documentation in the real world
看到现实世界中的文档是件好事
because that's what you're going to have after the course.
因为这是你在课程结束后会接触到的东西。
And so you'll get used to it through practice over time.
所以，随着时间的推移，你会通过实践逐渐习惯它。
But with loops, let's introduce one other feature
但对于循环，让我们介绍另一个特性
that we can compare to Scratch.
我们可以把它与 Scratch 相比较。
Here, for instance, in Scratch, is how we might have repeated something three
例如，在 Scratch 中，我们可以像这样重复某件事三次
times, like meowing on the screen.
比如在屏幕上喵喵叫。
In C, there were a bunch of ways to do this.
在 C 中，有很多方法可以做到这一点。
And the clunkiest was maybe to do it with a while loop
也许最笨拙的方法是用 while 循环
where we declare a variable called i, set it equal to 0,
我们声明一个名为 i 的变量，并将其设置为 0，
and then, iteratively, increment i again and again until it exceeds--
然后，反复增加 i 直到它超过--
until it equals 3, each time printing out "meow."
直到它等于 3，每次都打印 "meow"。
In Python, we can do this in a few different ways as well.
在 Python 中，我们也可以通过几种不同的方式来实现这一点。
The nearest translation of C into Python is perhaps this.
C 语言翻译成 Python 语言最接近的可能是这样。
It's almost the same, and logically, it really is the same,
它几乎相同，从逻辑上讲，它确实相同，
but you don't specify int, and you don't have a semicolon.
但你不需要指定 int，也不需要分号。
You don't have curly braces.
你没有大括号。
But you do have a colon.
但你有一个冒号。
You don't use printf().
你不使用 printf()。
You use print().
你使用 print()。
And you can't use i++, but you still can use i += 1.
你不能使用 i++，但你仍然可以使用 i += 1。
So logically, exactly the same idea as in C--
所以逻辑上，这和 C 语言中完全相同——
It's just a little tighter.
它只是更简洁一点。
I mean, it's a little easier to read, even though it's very mechanical,
我的意思是，它更容易阅读，即使它非常机械化，
if you will.
如果你愿意的话。
You're defining all of these.
你定义了所有这些。
You're defining this variable and changing it incrementally.
你正在定义这个变量并对其进行增量更改。
Well, recall that in C, we could also use a for loop, which at first glance
好吧，回想一下，在 C 语言中，我们也可以使用 for 循环，乍一看
was probably more cryptic than a while loop.
可能比 while 循环更难以理解。
But odds are by now, you're more comfortable or more
但到目前为止，你可能对使用循环更熟悉或更有
in the habit of using loops-- same exact idea.
使用循环的习惯——完全相同的概念。
In Python, though, we might do it like this.
但在 Python 中，我们可能会这样做。
We've seen how, in square brackets, you can have lists of values, like y, yes,
我们已经看到了，在方括号中，你可以有值的列表，例如 y，yes，
and so forth.
等等。
Well, let's just do the same thing with numbers.
好吧，我们用数字做同样的事情。
So if you want Python to do something three times, give it
所以，如果你想让 Python 做某事三次，就给它
a list of three values, like 0, 1, 2, and then print out "hello, world"
一个包含三个值的列表，例如 0、1、2，然后打印出 “hello, world”
that many times.
那么多次。
Now, this is correct, but it's bad design.
现在，这是正确的，但设计不好。
Even if you've never seen Python before, extrapolate mentally from this.
即使你以前从未见过 Python，也可以从这里进行心理推断。
Why is this probably not the right way or the best way to do this looping?
为什么这可能不是正确的方法或最好的方法来进行循环？
AUDIENCE: Because if you wanted to do it more than,
观众：因为如果你想做超过，
like, three times, you have to [INAUDIBLE]..
比如，三次，你必须 [听不清]。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
If you want to do it four times, five times, 50 times, 100 times,
如果你想做四次、五次、五十次、一百次，
I mean, surely, there's a better way than enumerating all of these values.
我的意思是，肯定有比枚举所有这些值更好的方法。
And there is.
并且确实有。
In fact, in Python, there's a function called range() that actually returns
事实上，在 Python 中，有一个名为 range() 的函数，它实际上返回
to you very efficiently a range of values.
给你一个值的范围，非常高效。
And by default, it hands you the number 0 and then 1 and then 2.
默认情况下，它会给你数字 0，然后是 1，然后是 2。
And if you want more than that, you just change the argument to range() to be
如果你想要更多，你只需要更改 range() 的参数为
how many values do you want.
你想要多少个值。
So if you passed in range of 50, you would get back 0
所以，如果你传入范围为 50，你将得到 0
through 49, which effectively allows you to do something 50 times in total.
到 49，这实际上允许你总共做某事 50 次。
So this is perhaps the most Pythonic way, so to speak.
所以这也许是最 Pythonic 的方式，这么说吧。
And this is actually a term of art.
这实际上是一个艺术术语。
Pythonic isn't necessarily the only way to do something.
Pythonic 不一定只是做某事的唯一方法。
But it's the way to do something based on consensus in the Python community.
但它是根据 Python 社区的共识来做某事的方式。
So it's pretty common to do this.
所以这样做很常见。
But there's some curiosity here.
但这里有一些好奇的地方。
Notice I'm declaring a variable i, but I'm never actually using it.
请注意，我声明了一个变量 i，但我实际上从未使用过它。
In fact, I don't even increment it because that's
事实上，我甚至没有对其进行增量操作，因为那是
sort of happening automatically.
自动发生的。
Well, what's really happening here is automatically in Python,
好吧，这里真正发生的事情是，在 Python 中，它会自动
on every iteration of this loop, Python is assigning i to the next value.
在循环的每次迭代中，Python 将 i 赋值为下一个值。
So initially, i is 0.
因此，最初，i 为 0。
Then it goes through an iteration.
然后它经历一次迭代。
Then i is 1.
然后 i 为 1。
Then i is 2.
然后 i 为 2。
And then that's it if you only asked for three values.
如果你只要求三个值，那就到此为止。
But there's this other technique in Python, just so you know,
但是，您需要了解 Python 中的另一种技巧，
whereby if you're the programmer, and you know you don't actually
如果您是程序员，并且知道您实际上
care about the name of this variable, you
不关心这个变量的名称，那么您
can actually change it to an underscore, which has no functional effect per se.
可以将它更改为下划线，它本身没有功能上的影响。
It just signals to the reader, your colleague, your teaching fellow,
它只是向读者、您的同事、您的助教传达信号，
that it's a variable, and you need it in order to achieve a for loop.
这是一个变量，您需要它才能实现 for 循环。
But you don't care about the name of the variable
但是您不关心变量的名称
because you're not going to use it explicitly anywhere.
因为您不会在任何地方显式地使用它。
So that might be an even more Pythonic way of doing things.
所以这可能是一种更 Pythonic 的做事方式。
But if you're more comfortable seeing the i
但如果您更习惯看到 i
and using the variable more explicitly, that's fine.
并且更习惯显式地使用变量，那就没问题。
Underscore does not mean anything special.
下划线没有特殊含义。
It's just a valid character for a variable name.
它只是一个有效的变量名字符。
So this is convention, nothing more technical than that.
所以这只是一个约定，没有比这更技术性的内容。
What about a forever loop in Scratch, like literally meow forever.
Scratch 中的无限循环呢，就像真的永远喵喵叫。
Well, over here, we can just use in C, while(true) printf() "meow,"
好吧，在这里，我们可以在 C 中使用 while(true) printf() "meow,"
again and again and again.
一遍又一遍。
In Python, it's almost the same.
在 Python 中，几乎是一样的。
You still get rid of the curly braces.
您仍然需要去掉花括号。
You add the colon.
您需要添加冒号。
You get rid of the semicolon.
您需要去掉分号。
But there's a subtlety.
但是有一个细微之处。
What else is different here?
这里还有什么不同？
Yeah?
是吧？
So True is uppercase.
所以 True 是大写的。
Why?
为什么？
Who knows?
谁知道呢？
The world decided that in Python, True is capitalized
全世界决定在 Python 中，True 是大写的
and False is capitalized.
而 False 也是大写的。
In many other languages, daresay most, they are not.
在许多其他语言中，敢说大多数语言，它们都不是大写的。
It's just a difference that you have to keep in mind or remember.
这只是一个你需要记住的差异。
All right.
好的。
So now that we have looping constructs, let me go back to my code here.
现在我们有了循环结构，让我回到我的代码。
And recall that I proposed that we re-implement a program like uppercase,
还记得我建议我们重新实现一个像 uppercase 这样的程序，
force an entire string to uppercase.
强制整个字符串变为大写。
And in C, we would have done this with a for loop, iterating from left to right.
在 C 中，我们会用 for 循环来做，从左到右迭代。
But what's nice in Python frankly, is that it's a lot easier
但坦率地说，Python 中的好处是，它比 C 中更容易
to loop in Python than it is in C because you can loop over
在 Python 中循环，因为您可以在
anything that is iterable.
任何可迭代的东西上循环。
A string is iterable in the sense that you can iterate over it
字符串是可迭代的，因为您可以从左到右迭代它
from left to right.
从左到右。
So what do I mean by this?
我的意思是什么呢？
Well, let me go ahead and, in uppercase.py,
好吧，让我在 uppercase.py 中继续，
let's first prompt the user for a variable called before and set that
让我们首先提示用户输入一个名为 before 的变量，并设置它。
equal to the return value of input(), giving them a prompt of "Before,"
等于输入函数input()的返回值，并提示他们输入“Before”，
colon.
冒号。
Then let's go ahead, as we did weeks ago, and print out just the word
然后让我们继续，就像几周前一样，打印出这个词
"After," just to make clear to the user what is actually going to be printed.
“After”，以便让用户清楚地知道实际要打印的内容。
Then let me go ahead and specify the following loop--
然后让我继续指定下面的循环——
for-- and previously you saw me use i, but because I'm dealing with
for——之前你看到我使用了i，但因为我现在正在处理
characters, I'm actually going to do this instead--
字符，所以我实际上会这样做——
for c in before, colon, print out c.upper.
对于before中的每个字符c，打印c.upper。
And that's it.
就这样。
Now, this is a little flawed, I will concede.
现在，我承认，这有点缺陷。
But let me run this-- python of uppercase.py.
但是让我运行一下——python uppercase.py。
Let's type in something like cat, C-A-T in all lowercase.
让我们输入一些东西，比如cat，C-A-T，全部小写。
Enter.
回车。
All right.
好的。
Well, you see "After," and I did get it right in the sense
好吧，你看到了“After”，而且就结果而言，我确实做对了
that it is capital C, capital A, capital T, but it looks a little stupid.
它确实是C，A，T大写，但是看起来有点愚蠢。
And in order to fix this, we actually need
为了解决这个问题，我们需要
to introduce something that's called named parameters.
引入一个叫做命名参数的东西。
So let me actually go ahead and propose that we can fix this problem
所以让我提议，我们可以解决这个问题
by actually passing in another argument to the print() function.
通过向print()函数传递另一个参数。
And this is a little different syntactically from C.
这在语法上与C语言有点不同。
But if I go back to VS Code here, it turns out
但如果我回到VS Code这里，结果证明
that there's two aesthetic problems here.
这里有两个美学问题。
One, I did not want the new line automatically inserted after "After."
第一，我不希望在“After”后面自动插入换行符。
Why?
为什么？
Because, just like in week 1, I want them to line up nicely--
因为，就像第一周一样，我希望它们整齐地对齐——
or in week 2.
或者第二周。
And I don't want a new line after C-A-T. So even
而且我不希望在C-A-T后面出现换行符。所以即使
though at first glance a moment-- a bit ago,
虽然乍一看，前不久，
it might have seemed nice that Python just does the backslash n for you,
Python自动为你添加反斜杠n，看起来可能挺好，
it can backfire if you don't actually want a new line every time.
但如果你并不想每次都出现换行符，它就会适得其反。
So the syntax is going to look a little weird.
所以语法看起来会有点奇怪。
But in Python, with the print() function,
但是在Python中，使用print()函数，
if you want to change the character that's automatically used at the end
如果你想改变自动用在每行末尾的字符
of every line, you can literally pass in a second argument called end and set it
你可以直接传入一个名为end的第二个参数，并将其设置为
equal to something else.
其他东西。
So if you want to set it equal to something else,
所以如果你想将其设置为其他东西，
and that something else is nothing, "", then that's fine.
而这个其他东西是空字符串，""，那就没问题。
You can actually specify end="".
你可以指定end=""。
Down here, too, if you want to specify that at the end of every one of these
这里也是，如果你想指定每个字符末尾
characters should be nothing, I can specify end="".
都是空字符串，我可以指定end=""。
What this implies is that by default in Python,
这意味着在Python中，默认情况下，
the default value of this end parameter is actually always backslash n.
这个end参数的默认值实际上始终是反斜杠n。
So if you want to override it and take that away,
所以如果你想覆盖它并将其移除，
you just literally change it to "" instead.
你只需将其更改为空字符串""。
And now if I clear my-- if I rerun this program, uppercase.py,
现在，如果我清空我的——如果我重新运行这个程序，uppercase.py，
type in cat in all lowercase, now you'll see--
输入cat，全部小写，现在你将看到——
oh, two minor bugs here.
哦，这里有两个小错误。
One was just stupid.
其中一个很愚蠢。
I had one too many spaces here.
我在这里多打了一个空格。
But you'll notice that I didn't move the cursor to the next line
但是你会注意到我没有将光标移动到下一行
after CAT was printed in all uppercase.
在 CAT 全部大写打印之后。
And that we can fix by just printing nothing.
而我们可以通过什么都不打印来解决这个问题。
It turns out when you don't pass print() an argument at all,
事实证明，当你没有给 print() 传递任何参数时，
it automatically gives you just the line ending, nothing else.
它会自动给你一个行结束符，除此之外什么都没有。
So I think this will move the cursor as expected.
所以我认为这将按预期移动光标。
So let me clear it now, run python of uppercase.py
所以现在让我清除它，运行 uppercase.py 的 python
and hit Enter, type in cat in all lowercase, cross my fingers this time,
然后按回车键，输入 cat 的小写字母，这次我祈祷一切顺利，
and now I have indeed capitalized this, character by character
现在我确实已经逐个字符地将它大写了
by character, just like we did in C.
逐个字符，就像我们在 C 中做的那样。
But honestly, this, too, not really necessary--
但老实说，这也不太必要——
it turns out I don't need to loop over a whole string,
事实证明我不需要遍历整个字符串，
because strings themselves come with methods.
因为字符串本身就带有方法。
And if you were to visit the documentation for strings,
如果你要查看字符串的文档，
you would see that indeed, upper is a method that comes with every string,
你会发现，确实，upper 是每个字符串都带有的一个方法，
and you don't need to call it on every character individually.
你不需要对每个字符单独调用它。
I could instead get rid of all of this and just print out--
我可以用另一种方法，去掉所有这些，然后只打印出来——
for instance, I can just print out before.upper.
例如，我可以只打印出 before.upper。
And the upper() function that comes with strings will automatically apply it
字符串自带的 upper() 函数会自动将其应用
to every character they're in and, I think, achieve the same result.
到它们包含的每个字符中，我认为，将达到相同的结果。
So let me go ahead and try this again-- python of uppercase.py, type in cat,
所以让我再次尝试一下——运行 uppercase.py 的 python，输入 cat，
enter, and indeed, it works exactly the same way.
回车，确实，它以完全相同的方式工作。
Let me take this one step further.
让我更进一步。
Let me go ahead and combine a couple of ideas now here.
现在让我在这里将几个想法结合起来。
Let me go ahead and, for instance, let me get rid of this last print() line.
让我继续，例如，让我去掉最后一行 print()。
Let me change my logic to be after equals the return value of this.
让我将我的逻辑更改为 after 等于此的返回值。
And now I can use one of those f strings and plug this in maybe here, After.
现在我可以使用其中一个 f 字符串，并将它插入到这里，After。
And I can get rid of the new line ending.
我可以去掉换行符。
I can specify this is an f string.
我可以指定这是一个 f 字符串。
So I'm just changing this around a little bit
所以我只是稍微改变一下这个
logically so that now I have a variable called after that
从逻辑上来说，现在我有一个名为 after 的变量
is the uppercase version of before.
是 before 的大写版本。
And now, if I do python of uppercase.py, type in cat, that too now works.
现在，如果我运行 uppercase.py 的 python，输入 cat，它也工作了。
And if I-- actually let me add a space there,
如果我——实际上让我在那里加一个空格，
if I run python of uppercase.py, type in cat, that too now works.
如果我运行 uppercase.py 的 python，输入 cat，它也工作了。
And lastly here, if you don't want to bother
最后在这里，如果你不想麻烦
creating another variable like this, you can even
创建另一个这样的变量，你甚至可以
put short bits of code inside of these format strings.
在这些格式字符串中放入一小段代码。
So I, for instance, could go in here into these curly braces
例如，我可以进入这里，进入这些大括号
and not just put a variable name.
并且不仅仅放一个变量名。
I can actually put Python code inside of the curly braces, inside of my string.
我实际上可以将 Python 代码放入大括号中，放入我的字符串中。
And so now if I run Python of uppercase.py, type in cat,
所以现在如果我运行 uppercase.py 的 Python，输入 cat，
even that too now works.
现在，甚至那个也起作用了。
Now, which one is the best?
现在，哪个最好？
This is kind of reasonable to put the bit of code inside of the string.
把代码片段放在字符串里似乎是合理的。
I would not start writing long lines of code inside of curly braces
我不会在花括号里写长长的代码行
that start to wrap, no less, because then it's
而且还要开始换行，因为这样
just going to be a matter of bad style.
就只是糟糕的风格问题了。
But this, again, is to say that there's a bunch of different ways
但是，再说一次，这只是说有很多不同的方法
to solve each of these problems.
来解决这些问题。
And so up until now, we've generally seen not named parameters.
到目前为止，我们一般没有看到命名参数。
end is the first parameter we've ever seen that has a name, literally, end.
end 是我们见到的第一个有名字的参数，准确地说，是 end。
Up until now in C and up until a moment ago in Python,
到目前为止，在 C 语言中，以及在刚才的 Python 中，
we've always been assuming that our parameters are positional.
我们一直假设我们的参数是位置参数。
What matters is the order in which you specify them, not necessarily something
重要的是你指定它们的顺序，而不是其他的什么东西。
else.
其他东西。
Whew.
哇。
OK, that was a lot.
好吧，内容很多。
Any questions about any of this here?
关于这里的内容有任何问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right.
好吧。
It feels like a lot.
感觉很多。
Let's take our 10-minute break here.
我们在这里休息 10 分钟。
Fruit roll-ups are now served.
现在供应水果卷。
We'll be back in 10.
我们 10 分钟后回来。
All right.
好的。
We are back.
我们回来了。
And recall that as we left off, we had just introduced loops.
回想一下，在我们离开的时候，我们刚刚介绍了循环。
And we'd seen a bunch of different ways by which
我们已经看到了很多不同的方法，通过这些方法
we could get, say, a cat to meow.
我们可以让一只猫发出喵喵的声音。
Let's actually translate that to some code
让我们实际把它翻译成一些代码
and start to make sense of some of the programs with which we began,
并开始理解我们一开始的一些程序，
like creating our own functions, as we did for the speller example
比如创建我们自己的函数，就像我们在拼写程序示例中所做的那样
at the very beginning, and actually do this a little more methodically.
在一开始，而且实际上更加有条理地做这件事。
So let me go over to VS Code here.
所以让我转到这里的 VS Code。
Let me go ahead and create a program called meow.py, instead of meow.c
让我创建一个名为 meow.py 的程序，而不是 meow.c
as in the past.
像以前一样。
And suffice it to say if you want to implement the idea of a cat,
如果要实现猫的想法，就足够了，
we can do better than just saying print("meow"), print("meow"),
我们可以做得比仅仅说 print("meow")、print("meow") 更好，
print("meow").
print("meow")。
This, of course, would work.
当然，这可以工作。
This is correct if the goal is to get the thing to meow three times.
如果目标是让这个东西喵喵叫三次，那这是正确的。
But when I run python of meow.py, it's going to work as expected,
但是当我运行 meow.py 的 python 时，它将按预期工作，
but this is just not good design, right?
但这只是一个不好的设计，对吧？
We should minimally be using a loop.
我们应该至少使用一个循环。
So let me propose that we improve this per the building blocks we've seen.
所以让我提议我们根据我们看到的构建块来改进它。
And I could say something like, for i in range(3),
我可以说类似这样的东西，对于 i in range(3)，
go ahead and print out now, quote unquote, "meow."
继续打印出来，现在，引号中的 "meow"。
So this is better in the sense that it still prints meow, meow, meow.
所以，从这个意义上说，这更好，因为它仍然打印 meow、meow、meow。
But if I want to change this to a dog and change the meow to a woof
但是如果我想把它改成一条狗，把 meow 改成 woof
or something like that, I can change it in one place and not three
或类似的东西，我可以在一个地方更改它，而不是三个
different places-- so just, in general, better design.
不同的位置——所以总体来说，更好的设计。
or something like that, I can change it in one place and not three
或者类似的东西，我可以改变一个地方，而不是三个地方。
different places-- so just, in general, better design.
不同的位置——所以总体来说，设计更好。
But what if now, much like in Scratch and in C,
但是如果现在，就像在 Scratch 和 C 中一样，
I wanted to create my own meow() function which did not come with either
我想创建自己的 meow() 函数，它不包含在两种语言中的任何一种。
of those languages as well.
在这两种语言中。
Well, as a teaser at the start of class, we
好吧，作为课堂开始时的预告，我们
saw that you can define your own functions
看到了你可以定义自己的函数
with this keyword def, which is a little bit different from how C does it.
使用这个关键字 def，这与 C 的做法略有不同。
But let me go ahead and do this indeed in Python and define my own function
但是让我在 Python 中继续这样做，并定义我自己的函数
meow().
meow()。
So let me go ahead and do def meow(), and then, inside of that function,
所以让我继续做 def meow()，然后，在这个函数里面，
I'm just going to literally do for now, quote unquote, "meow" with print().
我现在就用 print() 来做，引号引起来的“meow”。
And now down here, notice, I can actually go ahead and just call meow().
现在，请注意，我可以直接调用 meow()。
And I can go ahead and call meow(), and I can call meow().
我可以调用 meow()，我还可以调用 meow()。
And this is not the best design at the moment.
目前，这不是最好的设计。
But Python does not constrain me to have to implement a main() function,
但是 Python 没有限制我必须实现一个 main() 函数，
as we've seen thus far.
正如我们迄今所见。
But I can define my own helper functions, if you will,
但如果愿意，我可以定义自己的辅助函数，
like a helper function called meow().
比如一个叫做 meow() 的辅助函数。
So let me go ahead and just run this for demonstration's sake
所以，让我继续执行它，为了演示的缘故，
and run python of meow.py.
运行 python of meow.py。
That does seem to work.
这似乎可以工作。
But this is not good design.
但这并不是好的设计。
And let me go ahead and actually do this-- for i in range(3),
让我继续执行它——for i in range(3)，
now let me call the meow() function.
现在让我调用 meow() 函数。
And this, too, should work.
这也应该可以工作。
If I do python of meow.py, there we have meow, meow, meow.
如果我执行 python of meow.py，我们有 meow、meow、meow。
But I very deliberately did something clever here.
但我很故意在这里做了一些聪明的事情。
I defined meow at the top of my file.
我在文件的顶部定义了 meow。
But that's not the best practice because as in C,
但这并不是最佳实践，因为就像在 C 中一样，
when someone opens the file for the first time, whether you,
当有人第一次打开文件时，无论是你，
a TF, a TA, a colleague, you'd like to see the main part of the program
一个 TF，一个 TA，一个同事，你都想看到程序的主要部分
at the top of the file, just because it's easier mentally to dive right in
在文件顶部，仅仅是因为在心理上更容易直接进入
and know what this file is doing.
并知道这个文件正在做什么。
So let me go ahead and practice what I'm preaching and put the main part
所以，让我继续实践我所宣扬的，并将主要部分
of my code, even if there's no main() function per se,
我的代码，即使没有一个真正的 main() 函数，
at the top of this file.
放在这个文件的顶部。
So now I have the loop at the top.
所以，现在我在顶部有了循环。
I'm calling meow() on line 2, and I'm defining meow() on lines 5 and 6.
我在第二行调用 meow()，我在第五行和第六行定义 meow()。
Well, instinctively, you can perhaps see where this is going.
嗯，凭直觉，你或许能看出这将走向何方。
If I run Python of meow.py and hit Enter,
如果我运行 Python of meow.py 并按回车键，
there's one of those tracebacks that's tracing my error.
就会出现一个回溯，它正在追踪我的错误。
And here, my error is apparently on line 2 in meow.py.
在这里，我的错误显然出现在 meow.py 的第二行。
And you'll notice that, huh, the name 'meow' is not defined.
你会注意到，嗯，名字'meow'没有定义。
And so previously, we saw a different type of error, a value error.
因此，之前我们看到了不同类型的错误，一个值错误。
Here we're seeing a name error in the sense
这里我们看到的是一个名字错误，从某种意义上说
that Python does not recognize the name of this function.
这意味着 Python 无法识别这个函数的名称。
And intuitively, why might that be, even if the error is a little cryptic?
直觉上，为什么会出现这种情况，即使错误信息有点难以理解？
Yeah?
是吧？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] top to bottom.
观众：[听不清] 从上到下。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, Python, too-- as fancier as it seems to be than C,
David Malan：是的，Python 也是这样，虽然它看起来比 C 更高级，
it still takes things pretty literally, top to bottom, left to right.
但它仍然非常直白地按顺序执行代码，从上到下，从左到右。
So if you define meow() on line 5, you can't use it on line 2.
因此，如果你在第 5 行定义了 meow()，就不能在第 2 行使用它。
OK, so I could undo this, and I could flip the order.
好的，我可以撤销这个操作，然后改变顺序。
But let me just stipulate that as soon as we have a bunch of functions,
但是我要说明的是，一旦我们拥有大量函数，
it's probably naive to assume I can just keep putting my functions above, above,
假设我可以一直把我的函数放在上面，上面，就太天真了，
above, above.
上面，上面。
And honestly, that's going to move all of my main code, so to speak,
老实说，这样一来，我的主代码（可以这样说）
to the bottom of the file, which is sort of counterproductive or less obvious.
就会移到文件的底部，这有点事与愿违，或者说不太直观。
So it turns out in Python, even though you don't need a main() function,
所以，在 Python 中，虽然你并不需要一个 main() 函数，
it's actually quite common to define one nonetheless.
但实际上，定义一个 main() 函数很常见。
So what I could do to solve this problem is this.
所以，解决这个问题的方法是：
Let me go ahead and define a function called main() that takes no arguments,
我可以定义一个名为 main() 的函数，它不接受任何参数，
in this case.
在这个例子中。
Let me indent that same code beneath it.
我将这段代码缩进，放在 main() 函数下面。
And now let me keep meow() defined at the bottom of my file.
现在，我把 meow() 函数定义放在文件的底部。
So if we read this literally, on line 1, I'm defining a function called main().
如果我们从字面上理解，在第 1 行，我定义了一个名为 main() 的函数。
And it will do what is prescribed on lines 2 and 3.
它将执行第 2 和第 3 行的代码。
On line 6, I'm defining a function called meow(),
在第 6 行，我定义了一个名为 meow() 的函数，
and it will do what's prescribed on line 7-- so fairly straightforward,
它将执行第 7 行的代码——非常简单，
even though the keyword def is, of course, new today.
即使关键词 def 是今天才出现的新东西。
If I run, though, python of meow.py, you'd
如果我运行 python meow.py，你会
like to think I'll see three meows.
希望看到三个 "喵"。
But I see nothing.
但我什么也看不到。
I don't see an error, but I see nothing.
我没看到错误，但我什么也看不到。
Why?
为什么？
Intuitively, what explains the lack of behavior?
直觉上，什么解释了这种行为的缺失？
I didn't call main().
我没有调用 main() 函数。
So this is the thing even though it's not required in Python to have a main()
所以，虽然 Python 不要求必须有一个 main()
function, but it is conventional in Python to have a main() function,
函数，但在 Python 中，使用 main() 函数是惯例，
you have to call the function yourself.
你必须自己调用这个函数。
It doesn't get magically called as it does in C.
它不像在 C 语言中那样被自动调用。
So this might seem a little stupid--
所以，这可能看起来有点愚蠢——
and that's fine-- but it is the convention in Python.
没关系——但这是 Python 中的惯例。
Generally, the very last line of your file might just be to literally this,
通常，你文件中的最后一行代码可能是这样：
call main(), because this satisfies the constraint that main() is defined
调用 main()，因为这满足了 main() 函数在
on line 1 meow() is defined on line 6, but we don't call anything until line
第 1 行定义，meow() 函数在第 6 行定义，但我们直到第
10.
10 行才调用函数。
So line 10 says call main().
所以，第 10 行的意思是调用 main() 函数。
So that means execute this code.
这意味着执行这段代码。
Line 3 says call meow(), which means execute this code.
第 3 行的意思是调用 meow() 函数，这意味着执行这段代码。
So now it all works because the last thing I'm doing is call main().
现在，所有代码都可以正常工作了，因为我最后做的就是调用 main() 函数。
You can think of C as just kind of secretly having
你可以将C语言视为在你不知情的情况下偷偷地拥有
this line there for you the whole time.
一直默默地存在那里的代码。
But now that we have our own functions, notice that we can enhance this
但现在我们有了自己的函数，请注意，我们可以增强
implementation of meow() to maybe be parameterized and take actually
meow() 的实现，使其参数化，并实际接收
an argument itself.
一个参数。
So let me make a tweak here.
所以让我在这里做一个小修改。
Just like in C, and just like in Scratch,
就像在 C 语言中一样，也像在 Scratch 中一样，
I can actually let meow() meow a specific number of times.
我实际上可以让 meow() 叫出特定的次数。
So let me do this.
所以让我来试试这个。
Wouldn't it be nice, instead of having my loop in main(),
如果我们不用在 main() 函数里写循环，而是
to instead just distill main() into a single line of code and just pass
将 main() 函数简化成一行代码，并且直接传入
in the number of times you want the thing to meow?
你想让它叫多少次呢？
What I could do in meow() here is I have to give it a parameter.
我可以在 meow() 函数里做的是，我必须给它一个参数。
And I could call it anything I want.
我可以随便给它取名字。
I'm going to call it n for number, which seems fine.
我打算把它叫做 n，代表数字，这样看起来还不错。
And then, in the meow() function, I could do this--
然后，在 meow() 函数里，我可以这样做--
for i in range of, not 3, but n now, I can tell range() to give me a range
for i in range of，不是 3，而是 n，现在我可以告诉 range() 函数给我一个
that is of variable length based on what n is.
根据 n 的值来决定长度的范围。
And then I indent the print() below the loop now.
然后现在我把 print() 函数缩进到循环的下面。
And this should now do what I expect, too.
这样应该就能得到我想要的结果了。
Let me run python of meow.py.
让我运行一下 meow.py 的 python 程序。
Enter.
回车。
And there's 3.
结果是 3 次。
But if I change the 3 to a 5 and rerun this, python of meow.py,
但如果我把 3 改成 5，然后重新运行这个程序，python of meow.py，
now I'm getting five meows.
现在我得到了 5 次猫叫声。
So we've just seen a third way how, in Python, now we
所以我们刚刚看到了第三种方法，在 Python 中，现在我们可以
can implement the idea of meowing as its own abstracted function.
将猫叫声的概念实现为一个独立的抽象函数。
And I can assume now that meow() exists.
现在我可以假设 meow() 函数已经存在了。
I can now treat it as out of sight, out of mind.
现在我可以把它当作眼不见心不烦的东西。
It's an abstraction.
这就是抽象。
And frankly, I could even put it into a library, import it from a file,
坦白地说，我甚至可以把它放到一个库里，从一个文件中导入它，
like we've done with CS50, and make it usable by other people as well.
就像我们对 CS50 做的那样，让其他人也能使用它。
So the takeaway here, really, though, is that in Python, you
所以，这里真正的重点是，在 Python 中，你可以
can, similarly to C, define your own functions.
像在 C 语言中一样，定义你自己的函数。
But you should understand the slight differences
但你应该理解一些细微的差异
as to what gets called automatically for you.
关于哪些东西会被自动调用。
All right.
好的。
Other differences or similarities with C?
与 C 语言相比，还有哪些其他差异或相似之处？
Well, recall that in C, truncation was an issue.
好吧，回想一下，在 C 语言中，截断是一个问题。
Truncation is whereby if you, for instance, divide an int by an int,
截断是指，如果你，例如，将一个 int 除以一个 int，
and it's a fractional answer, everything after the decimal point
而结果是一个小数，小数点后的所有内容
gets truncated by default because an int divided by an int in C
默认会被截断，因为在 C 语言中，一个 int 除以一个 int
gives you an int.
结果是一个 int。
And if you can't fit the remainder in that integer, everything at the decimal
如果你无法将余数放入那个整数中，小数点后的所有内容
gets cut off.
会被截断。
So what does this mean?
那这意味着什么呢？
Well, let me actually go back to VS Code here.
好吧，我实际上要回到 VS Code 里。
Let me go ahead and open, say, calculator.py again,
让我继续打开，比如，calculator.py 文件，
and let's change up what the calculator now does.
让我们改变一下这个计算器现在执行的操作。
Let me do this.
我来做这个。
Let me define a variable called x, set it equal to the input() function,
让我定义一个名为 x 的变量，并将其设置为等于 input() 函数，
prompting the user for x.
提示用户输入 x。
Let me ask the user for y, let me not repeat past mistakes,
让我询问用户 y，不要重蹈覆辙，
and let me proactively convert both of these to ints.
并让我主动将这两个值转换为整数。
And I'll do it in one pretty one-liner here so that I definitely get x and y.
我会在这里使用一行代码来完成，这样我就能确保获得 x 和 y。
And on the honor system, I just won't type cat.
而且我承诺，我不会输入“cat”。
I won't type dog, even though this program is not
我不会输入“dog”，即使这个程序没有
really complete without error checking.
没有错误检查就没有真正的完成。
Now, let me go ahead and declare a third variable,
现在，让我继续声明第三个变量，
z = x / y, and now let's just go ahead and print out z.
z = x / y，现在让我们直接打印出 z。
I don't need a format code.
我不需要格式代码。
I don't need an f string.
我不需要 f 字符串。
If all you want to do is print a variable, print() is very flexible.
如果你只想打印一个变量，print() 非常灵活。
You can just say print(z), in parentheses.
你只需在括号内写 print(z) 即可。
Let me run python of calculator.py, hit Enter.
让我运行 calculator.py 的 Python 代码，按 Enter 键。
Let's type in 1 for x, 3 for y.
让我们输入 1 作为 x，3 作为 y。
I left out a space there.
我漏掉了空格。
And oh, interesting.
哦，有趣。
What seems to have happened here?
这里发生了什么？
Let me fix my spacing and rerun this again-- python of calculator.py-- so 1,
让我修正一下空格，重新运行它——calculator.py 的 Python 代码——所以是 1，
3.
3。
What did not happen?
发生了什么？
AUDIENCE: It doesn't truncate.
观众：它没有截断。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
So it didn't truncate.
所以它没有截断。
So Python is a little smarter when it comes
所以 Python 在这方面更智能一些
to converting one value to another.
将一个值转换为另一个值。
So an integer divided by an integer, if it ends up
所以一个整数除以另一个整数，如果结果
giving you this fractional component, not to worry now,
出现了小数部分，现在不用担心，
you'll get back what is effectively a float in Python here.
你将在这里获得一个 Python 中的浮点数。
Well, what else do we want to be mindful of in, say, Python?
那么，在 Python 中，我们还需要注意什么？
Well, recall that in C, we had this issue of floating point and precision
在 C 语言中，我们有浮点数精度问题
whereby if you want to represent a number, like 1/3, and on a piece
比如，如果你想表示一个数字，比如 1/3，在一张纸上，它会是
of paper, it's, like, 0.3 with a line over it
0.3 上面有一条线
because the 3 infinitely repeats--
因为 3 无限循环——
but we saw a problem in C last time when we actually
但上一次，我们在 C 语言中看到了一个问题，当时我们实际上
played around with some value.
对一些值进行了操作。
So, for instance, let me go back to VS Code here.
例如，让我回到 VS Code 这里。
And this is going to be the ugliest syntax I do think we see today.
我认为这是我们今天见过的最难看的语法。
But there was a way in C, using %f, to show more than the default number
但在 C 语言中，我们可以使用 %f，显示比默认值更多的
of digits after the decimal point, to see more significant digits.
小数点后的数字，以查看更多有效数字。
In Python, there's something similar.
在 Python 中，也有类似的方法。
It just looks very weird.
它看起来很奇怪。
And the way you do it in Python is this.
你在 Python 中使用的方法是：
You specify that you want an f string, a format string.
你指定要使用 f 字符串，也就是格式化字符串。
And I'm just going to start and finish my thought first--
我首先要说明一下——
f before "".
f 放在 "" 之前。
If you want to print out z, you could literally just do this.
如果你想打印 z，你可以直接这样操作。
And so this is just an f string, but you're interpolating z.
所以这只是一个 f 字符串，但你正在插入 z。
So it doesn't do anything more than it did a moment ago when I literally just
所以它与我刚才直接输入z时的效果相同
passed in z.
输入z。
But as soon as you have an f string, you can
但只要你使用f字符串，你就可以
configure the variable to print out to a specific number of digits.
将变量配置为以指定位数打印出来。
So if you actually want to print out z to, say, 50 decimal points,
所以如果你真的想将z打印成，比如，50位小数，
just to see a lot, you can use crazy syntax like this.
为了看到很多位数，你可以使用这样的疯狂语法。
So it's just using the curly braces, as I introduced before.
所以它只是使用了花括号，就像我之前介绍的那样。
But you then use a dot after a colon, and then
但是你随后在冒号之后使用点，然后
you specify the number of digits that you want and then an f to make clear
你指定你想要的位数，然后添加一个f来明确
it's a float.
它是一个浮点数。
Honestly, I google this all the time when I don't remember the syntax.
老实说，当我记不住语法时，我总是去谷歌搜索。
But the point is the functionality exists.
但关键是这个功能是存在的。
All right.
好的。
Let me go down here and rerun python of calculator.py.
让我到下面重新运行calculator.py的Python程序。
And unfortunately, if I divide 1 by 3, not all of my problems are solved.
不幸的是，如果我将1除以3，并非所有的问题都解决了。
Floating point precision is still a thing.
浮点精度仍然存在。
So be mindful of the fact that there are these limitations
所以要注意，在Python世界中存在这些限制
in the world of Python.
。
Floating point precision remains.
浮点精度仍然存在。
If you want to do even better than that, though, there
如果你想做得比这更好，那么就存在
exist a lot more libraries, third-party libraries,
许多其他的库，第三方库，
that can give you much greater precision for scientific purposes,
它们可以为你提供更高的精度，以用于科学目的，
financial purposes, or the like.
财务目的，或类似的用途。
But what about another problem from C, integer overflow?
但C语言中的另一个问题，整数溢出呢？
If you just count to high, recall that you might accidentally
如果你只是计数到一个很大的数字，请记住，你可能会意外地
overflow the capacity of an integer and end up going back to 0,
超出整数的容量，最终回到0，
or worse, going negative altogether.
或者更糟糕的是，完全变为负数。
In Python, this problem does not exist.
在Python中，这个问题不存在。
In Python, when you have an integer, a.k.a.
在Python中，当你有一个整数，也称为
int, even though we haven't needed to use the keyword int,
int，即使我们不需要使用int关键字，
it will grow and grow and grow.
它会不断增长。
And Python will reserve more and more memory for that integer to fit it.
Python会为这个整数保留越来越多的内存来容纳它。
So it is not a fixed number of bits.
所以它不是一个固定数量的比特。
So floating point imprecision is still a problem.
所以浮点精度仍然是一个问题。
Integer overflow-- not a problem in the latest versions of Python,
整数溢出——在最新版本的Python中不是问题，
so a difference worth knowing.
这是一个值得注意的区别。
But what about other features of Python that we didn't have in C?
但Python中我们没有在C语言中拥有的其他功能呢？
Well, let's actually revisit one of those tracebacks, one of those errors
那么，让我们重新看看那些回溯，那些错误
I ran into earlier, to see how we might actually solve it.
我之前遇到过，看看我们如何实际解决它。
So let me go back to VS Code here.
所以让我回到这里的VS Code。
And just for fun, let me go ahead and do this.
为了好玩，让我继续做这个。
Let me clear my terminal.
让我清空我的终端。
And let me change my calculator to actually have a get_int() function.
让我修改我的计算器，使其拥有一个get_int()函数。
We've seen how to define our own functions.
我们已经了解了如何定义自己的函数。
Let me not bother with the CS50 library.
让我不要使用CS50库。
Let me just invent my own get_int() function as follows.
让我像下面这样发明自己的get_int()函数。
So def get_int(), and just like the CS50 function,
所以def get_int()，就像CS50函数一样，
I'm going to have get int take a prompt, a string to show the user to ask them
我要让 get_int 函数接收一个提示，一个字符串，用于向用户提问
for an integer.
以获取一个整数。
And now I'm going to go ahead and return the return value of input(),
现在，我将返回 input() 函数的返回值，
passing that same prompt to input()-- because input(),
并将相同的提示传递给 input() 函数——因为 input() 函数，
just like get_string(), shows the user a string of text.
就像 get_string() 函数一样，会向用户显示一个文本字符串。
But I do want to convert this thing here to an int.
但我想要将这里的内容转换为一个整数。
So this is just a one-liner, really, of an implementation of get_int().
所以这实际上只是一行代码，实现了 get_int() 函数。
So this is kind of like what CS50 did in its Python library, but not quite.
这有点类似于 CS50 在其 Python 库中所做的，但并不完全相同。
Why?
为什么？
Because there's a problem with it.
因为它存在一个问题。
So let me do this.
所以让我这样做。
Let me define a main() function just by convention.
让我按照惯例定义一个 main() 函数。
Let me use this implementation of get_int() to ask the user for x.
让我使用这个 get_int() 函数的实现来向用户询问 x 的值。
Let me use this get_int() function to prompt the user for y.
让我使用这个 get_int() 函数来提示用户输入 y 的值。
And then let me do something simple like print out x + y.
然后，让我做一些简单的操作，比如打印出 x + y 的结果。
And then, very last thing, I have to call main().
最后，我必须调用 main() 函数。
And this is a minor point, but I'm deliberately
这只是一个细微的点，但我故意
putting multiple blank lines between my functions.
在函数之间添加多行空白。
This too is Pythonic.
这也是 Python 风格的。
It's a matter of style. style50 will help you with this.
这是一个风格问题，style50 会帮助你解决这个问题。
It's just meant for larger files to really make your functions stand out
这只是为了让较大的文件中的函数更加突出，
and be a little more separated visually from others.
并在视觉上与其他函数保持一定的距离。
All right.
好的。
Let me go ahead and run Python of calculator.py.
让我运行 calculator.py 的 Python 代码。
Enter.
回车。
Let me type in 1.
让我输入 1。
Let me type in 3.
让我输入 3。
And that actually works.
这实际上是有效的。
1 plus 3 is 4.
1 加 3 等于 4。
Let me do the more obvious.
让我做更明显的事情。
1 plus 2 gives me 3.
1 加 2 等于 3。
So the calculator is in fact working until such time as I, the human,
所以，这个计算器确实有效，直到我，这个人类，
don't cooperate and type in something like cat for x.
不配合，输入像 cat 这样的东西作为 x 的值。
Then we get that same traceback as before,
然后，我们会得到与之前相同的跟踪信息，
but I'm seeing it now in this file.
但我现在在文件中看到了。
And let me zoom in on my terminal just to make clear.
让我放大终端，以便看得更清楚。
We don't need to see the old history there.
我们不需要看到那里的历史记录。
Let me type in cat, Enter, and you'll see the same traceback.
让我输入 cat，回车，你就会看到相同的跟踪信息。
And you'll see that, OK, here's where now there's
你会看到，好吧，现在这里有
multiple functions involved.
多个函数参与其中。
So what's going on?
所以发生了什么？
The first problem is at line 12 in main().
第一个问题出现在 main() 函数中的第 12 行。
But that's not actually the problem because main() calls my get_int()
但这并不是真正的問題，因為 main() 函數调用了我的 get_int()
function.
函数。
So on line 6 of calculator.py, this is really the issue--
所以，在 calculator.py 文件中的第 6 行，这才是真正的问题——
so, again, it's tracing everything that just happened from top to bottom here--
所以，再次说明，它正在从上到下跟踪这里刚刚发生的所有事情——
and value error-- invalid literal for int() with base 10,
以及值错误——对于 int() 函数来说，'cat' 是一个无效的文字，基数为 10，
'cat,' which is to say, like before, cat is not an integer in base 10 or any
'cat'，也就是说，就像之前一样，cat 在 10 进制或任何
other base.
其他进制中都不是一个整数。
It just cannot be converted to an integer.
它不能被转换为一个整数。
So how do you fix this, or, really, how does the CS50 library fix this?
那么，你该如何解决这个问题呢？或者说，CS50 库是如何解决这个问题的？
You won't have to write much code like this.
你将不必编写太多这样的代码。
But it turns out that Python supports what are called exceptions.
但事实证明，Python 支持所谓的异常。
And generally, an exception is a better way
通常，异常是处理某些类型的错误的更好方法
of handling certain types of errors because in C, recall
因为在 C 语言中，请回忆一下
that the only way we could really handle errors
我们真正处理错误的唯一方法
is by having functions return special values.
是让函数返回特殊值。
malloc() could return null, which means it ran out of memory.
malloc() 可以返回 null，这意味着它内存不足。
Something went wrong.
出问题了。
Some functions we wrote in C could return 1, could return 2,
我们在 C 语言中编写的一些函数可以返回 1，可以返回 2，
could return negative 1.
可以返回 -1。
Recall that we could write our own functions that return values
请回忆一下，我们可以编写返回值的自定义函数
to indicate something went wrong.
以指示出错。
But the problem in C is that if you're stealing certain values,
但在 C 语言中，问题在于如果你正在窃取某些值，
be it null or 1 or 2 or 3, your function can never return null or 1 or 2 or 3
无论是 null 还是 1 还是 2 还是 3，你的函数永远不能返回 null 还是 1 还是 2 还是 3
as actual values.
作为实际值。
Why?
为什么？
Because other people are going to interpret them as errors.
因为其他人会将它们解释为错误。
So you kind of have to use up some of your possible return values
因此，你必须使用一些可能的返回值
in a language like C and treat them specially as errors.
在像 C 这样的语言中，并将它们特殊地视为错误。
In Python and other languages--
在 Python 和其他语言中——
Java and others-- you don't have to do that.
Java 和其他语言——你无需这样做。
You can instead have more out of band error handling, known as exceptions.
你可以改为使用带外错误处理，称为异常。
And that's what's happening here.
这就是这里发生的事情。
When I run calculator.py and I type in cat, what I'm seeing here
当我运行 calculator.py 并输入 cat 时，我在这里看到的是
is actually an exception.
实际上是一个异常。
It's something exceptional, but not in a good way.
这是一件例外的事情，但不是好的方面。
This exception means this was not supposed to happen.
这个异常意味着这本不应该发生。
The type of exception happens to be called a value error.
这种异常恰好被称为 ValueError。
And within the world of Python, there's this whole taxonomy, that is to say,
在 Python 的世界里，存在着整个分类法，也就是说，
a whole list of possible exceptions.
存在着整个可能的异常列表。
ValueError is one of the most common.
ValueError 是最常见的异常之一。
We saw another one before, name error, when I said
我们之前见过另一个异常，NameError，当我说了
meow when Python didn't know what meow meant.
meow 时，Python 不知道 meow 的意思。
So this is just an example of an exception.
所以这只是一个异常的例子。
But what this means is that there is a way for me to try to handle this
但这意味着，我有一种方法可以尝试处理这种情况
myself.
我自己。
So I'm actually going to go ahead and do this.
所以，我实际上将继续执行此操作。
Instead of get_int() simply blindly returning the integer conversion
而不是让 get_int() 简单地盲目地返回用户提供给我的任何输入的整数转换
of whatever input the user gives me, I'm going to instead literally try to do
而是尝试做
this instead.
这个。
So it's kind of a aptly named phrase.
所以它是一个恰如其分的短语。
It literally means that.
它的意思就是那样。
Please try to do this, except if something goes wrong,
请尝试执行此操作，除非出现错误，
except if there is a ValueError, in which case
除非出现 ValueError，在这种情况下
I want Python to do something else, for instance,
我希望 Python 执行其他操作，例如
quote unquote, "Not an integer."
说白了，就是“不是整数”。
So what does this mean?
那么这意味着什么？
It's a little weird, the syntax.
语法有点奇怪。
But in the get_int() function, Python will first try to do the following.
但在 get_int() 函数中，Python 将首先尝试执行以下操作。
It will try to get an input from the user.
它将尝试从用户那里获取输入。
It will try to convert it to an integer.
它将尝试将其转换为整数。
And it will try to return it.
它将尝试将其返回。
But if one of those operations fails, namely the integer step in this case,
但如果其中一个操作失败，在这种情况下，特别是整数步骤，
then an exception could happen.
就会发生异常。
And you might get what's called a ValueError.
你可能会得到一个叫做 ValueError 的错误。
Why?
为什么？
Because the documentation tells you that might happen.
因为文档告诉过你可能会发生这种情况。
Or, in my case, I experienced it firsthand,
或者，在我的例子中，我亲身经历过，
and now I want to catch this kind of exception in my own code.
现在我想在我的代码中捕获这种异常。
So if there is a ValueError, I'm not going
所以，如果有 ValueError，我不会
to see that crazy traceback anymore.
再看到那个疯狂的跟踪信息。
I'm instead going to see, quote unquote, "Not an integer."
我反而会看到“不是整数”的提示。
But what the CS50 library does for you technically is it
但从技术上讲，CS50 库为你做的就是
lets you try again and again and again.
让你反复尝试。
Recall in the past, if I type in cat and dog and bird,
还记得之前，如果我输入 cat、dog 和 bird，
it's just going to keep asking me again and again
它会反复询问我
until I actually give it an int.
直到我真正输入一个整数。
So that kind of implies that we really need a loop inside of this function.
所以，这意味着我们真的需要在这个函数中使用循环。
And the easiest way to do something forever
最简单的方法是让程序永远运行
is to loop while true, just like in C, but a capital T in Python.
就是使用 while true 循环，就像在 C 语言中一样，但在 Python 中，T 要大写。
And what I'm going to do now is implement a better version of get_int()
我现在要实现一个更完善的 get_int() 版本
here because what's it going to do?
因为它的作用是什么？
It is going to try-- it's going to do this forever.
它会尝试——它会永远这样做。
It's going to try to get an input, convert it to an int, and return it.
它会尝试获取输入、将其转换为整数并返回。
And just like break breaks you out of a loop,
就像 break 可以让你跳出循环一样，
return also breaks you out of a loop as well, right?
return 也可以让你跳出循环，对吧？
Because once you've returned, there's no more need for this function to execute.
因为一旦你返回，这个函数就不再需要执行。
So long story short, you won't have to write much code like this yourself.
总之，你不需要自己写很多这样的代码。
But this is essentially what the CS50 library is doing when it implements
但这本质上是 CS50 库在实现时所做的
the Python version of get_int().
Python 版本的 get_int() 函数。
So what happens now?
现在会发生什么？
If I run python of calculator.py, and I type in cat, I get yelled at,
如果我运行 calculator.py 的 Python 代码，然后输入 cat，我会收到提示，
but I'm prompted again because of the loop.
但由于循环，我会再次被提示。
I type in dog.
我输入 dog。
I'm yelled at, but I'm prompted again.
我收到提示，但我会再次被提示。
I type in bird, yelled at, but I'm prompted again.
我输入 bird，收到提示，但我会再次被提示。
If I type in 1, then I type in 2, now it proceeds
如果我输入 1，然后输入 2，现在它会继续执行
because it tried and succeeded this time as opposed to trying and failing
因为它这次尝试并成功了，而上次尝试却失败了
last time.
上次。
And technically, the CS50 library doesn't actually
从技术上讲，CS50 库实际上不会
yell at you with "Not an integer."
用“不是整数”的提示来提醒你。
So technically, if you want to handle the error, that is to say,
所以从技术上讲，如果你想处理这个错误，也就是说，
catch the exception, you can actually just say, oh, pass,
捕获异常，你实际上只需说，哦，pass，
and it will just silently try again and again.
它会默默地反复尝试。
So let me go ahead and run this. python of calculator.py works almost the same.
所以让我运行它，calculator.py 的 Python 代码与之前的代码几乎相同。
But notice now it works just like the C version.
但是请注意，它现在的工作方式与 C 版本相同。
It doesn't yell at you, but it does prompt you again and again and again.
它不会对你大喊大叫，但它会一次又一次地提示你。
But I'll do 1 and 2, and that now is satisfied.
但是我会输入 1 和 2，现在就满足了。
So that then is exceptions which you'll encounter,
所以这些就是你会遇到的异常，
but you yourself won't have to write much code along those lines.
但你自身不需要写很多这方面的代码。
Well, what else can we now do?
那么，我们现在还能做什么？
Well, let's revisit something like this for Mario,
让我们重新审视一下像这样的马里奥代码，
recall, whereby we had this two-dimensional world with things
回想一下，我们之前有一个二维世界，其中有各种东西
in the way for Mario, like this column of three bricks.
挡住马里奥的路，比如这一列三块砖。
Let me actually play around now for a moment with some loops
让我现在花点时间来玩玩循环
just to see how there's different ways that might actually
看看是否有不同的方式，实际上
resonate with you just in terms of the simplicity of some of these things.
会让你产生共鸣，仅仅因为这些东西的简单性。
Let me go ahead and create a program called mario.py.
让我创建一个叫做 mario.py 的程序。
And suppose that I want to print a column of three bricks.
假设我想打印一列三块砖。
It kind of doesn't get any easier than this in Python.
在 Python 中，这几乎是最简单的做法了。
So for i in range(3), just go ahead and print out a single hash--
所以对于 i 在 range(3) 中，就打印一个井号——
done.
完成。
That then is what we took us more lines of code in the past.
这正是我们之前用更多代码行才能实现的功能。
But if I run mario.py, that there gets the job done.
但是如果我运行 mario.py，它就能完成任务。
I could change the i to an underscore, but it's not
我可以把 i 变成下划线，但这
bad to remind myself that i is what's really doing my counting.
并不好，它提醒我 i 才是真正进行计数的变量。
Well, what else could we do beyond this?
那么，除了这个，我们还能做什么？
Well, recall that in the world of Mario, we prompted the user, actually,
回想一下，在马里奥的世界里，我们实际上提示了用户
for a specific height.
输入一个特定的高度。
We didn't just always hardcode 3.
我们并不总是硬编码 3。
So I could actually do something like this.
所以我实际上可以这样做。
Let me actually open up from today's code that I came with in advance
让我从今天提前准备好的代码中打开
and pull up this C version of Mario.
并调出这个马里奥的 C 版本。
So this was from some time ago, in week 1.
这是几周前，第一周的代码。
And this is how we implemented a loop that
这就是我们实现的循环，它
ensures that we get a positive integer from the user by just doing while
通过使用 while 循环来确保我们从用户那里得到一个正整数。
and is not positive, and then we use this for loop
它不是正数，然后我们使用这个 for 循环
to actually print out that many hashes.
来打印出那么多井号。
Now, in Python, it's actually going to be pretty similar,
现在，在 Python 中，它实际上会非常类似，
except for the fact that in Python, there is no do while loop.
除了在 Python 中没有 do while 循环。
But recall that a do while loop was useful
但回想一下，do while 循环是有用的，因为它
because it means you can get the user to try something and then maybe try again,
意味着你可以让用户尝试一些东西，然后可能再尝试一次，
maybe try again, maybe try again.
可能再尝试一次，可能再尝试一次。
So it's really good for user input.
所以它非常适合用户输入。
So let's actually do this.
所以让我们实际操作一下。
Let me borrow the CS50's library get_int() function,
让我借用 CS50 库的 get_int() 函数，
just so we don't have to re-implement that ourselves again and again.
这样我们就不用一次又一次地自己重新实现它了。
Let me, in Python, do this the Pythonic way.
让我在 Python 中以 Pythonic 的方式来做这件事。
In Python, if you want to prompt the user to do something again and again
在 Python 中，如果你想反复提示用户做某事，
and again, potentially, you deliberately, by convention,
再一次，可能，你故意，通过惯例，
induce an infinite loop.
诱导一个无限循环。
You just get yourself into an infinite loop.
你只是把自己陷入无限循环。
But the goal is going to be try something, try something, try
但目标是要尝试一些东西，尝试一些东西，尝试
something, and as soon as you have what you want, break out of the loop
一些东西，一旦你得到了想要的东西，就退出循环
instead.
反而。
So we're implementing the idea of a do while loop ourselves.
所以我们自己实现了 do while 循环的思想。
So I'm going to do this. n, for number, equals get_int(),
所以我会这样做。n，表示数字，等于 get_int()，
and let's ask the user for a height.
让我们向用户询问高度。
Then let's just check.
然后让我们检查一下。
If n is greater than 0, you know what?
如果 n 大于 0，你知道吗？
Break.
退出。
We've got the value we need.
我们得到了我们需要的价值。
And if not, it's just going to implicitly keep looping again and again
如果没有，它就会隐式地不断循环下去
and again.
再循环一次。
So in Python, this is to say-- super common--
所以在 Python 中，这表示——非常常见——
to deliberately induce an infinite loop and break out of it when you have
故意诱发一个无限循环，并在你拥有想要的东西时退出循环。
what you want.
你想要的东西。
All right?
好吗？
Now I can just do the same kind of code as before. for i in range not of--
现在我可以像以前一样编写相同的代码。for i in range 不用——
rage sometimes-- for i in range, not 3, but n,
range 有时候——for i in range，不是 3，而是 n，
now I can go ahead and print out--
现在我可以继续打印出——
oops-- a hash like this.
糟糕——一个这样的哈希。
If I open my terminal window, it's going to work almost the same,
如果我打开终端窗口，它几乎会以相同的方式工作，
but now mario is going to prompt me for the height.
但现在马里奥会提示我输入高度。
So I could type in 3, or I could type in 4,
所以我可以输入 3，或者我可以输入 4，
or I could be uncooperative and type in 0 or negative 1 or even cat.
或者我可以不合作地输入 0 或负 1，甚至输入 cat。
And because I'm using the CS50 library, cat is ignored.
因为我使用的是 CS50 库，所以 cat 被忽略了。
Because I'm using my while loop and breaking out
因为我使用了 while 循环，并且只在 n 为正时才退出循环
of it only when n is positive, I'm also ignoring the 0 and the negative 1.
所以我也忽略了 0 和负 1。
So, again, this would be a Pythonic way of implementing this particular idea.
所以，再次强调，这将是实现这个特定想法的 Pythonic 方式。
If I want to maybe enhance this a bit further, let me propose that,
如果我想进一步增强它，我建议，
for instance, we consider something like the two-dimensional version--
例如，我们考虑像二维版本这样的东西——
or the horizontal version of this instead.
或者考虑它的水平版本。
So recall that some time ago, we printed out,
所以回忆一下，之前我们打印过，
like, four question marks in the sky that might have
比如，天空中四个问号，它们可能
looked a little something like this.
看起来有点像这样。
Now, the very mechanical way to do this would be as follows.
现在，非常机械的做法如下。
Let me close my C code.
让我关闭我的 C 代码。
Let me clear my terminal.
让我清空我的终端。
And let me just delete my old mario version here.
让我删除我在这里的旧版马里奥。
And let's just do this-- for i in range(4), let's go ahead
让我们就这样做——for i in range(4)，让我们继续
and print out a question mark, all right?
并打印一个问号，好吗？
I'm going to run python of mario.py, enter,
我将运行 mario.py 的 python，输入，
and, ugh, it's still a column instead of a row.
而且，呃，它仍然是一列而不是一行。
But what's the fix here, perhaps?
但是这里有什么解决方法吗？
What's the fix?
有什么解决方法吗？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: The end equals [INAUDIBLE]
观众：结尾等于 [听不见]
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
We can use that named parameter and say end=""
我们可以使用这个命名参数，并说 end=""
to just suppress the default backslash n.
只是为了抑制默认的反斜杠 n。
But let's give ourselves one at the very end of the loop
但让我们在循环的最后给自己一个
just to move the cursor correctly.
只是为了正确移动光标。
So now if I run python of mario.py, now it
所以现在，如果我运行 mario.py 的 python，现在它
looks like what it might have in the sky here.
看起来像它可能在天空中的样子。
But it turns out Python has some neat features, too, more syntactic sugar,
但事实证明，Python 也有一些很酷的功能，更多的语法糖，
if you will, for doing things a little more easily.
如果你愿意，可以更容易地完成一些事情。
It turns out in Python, you could also do this.
事实证明，在 Python 中，你也可以这样做。
You could just say print("?" * 4).
你可以直接说 print("?" * 4)。
And just like + means concatenation, * here means,
就像 + 代表连接一样，* 在这里代表，
really, multiply the string by itself that many times, so sort
实际上，将字符串自身乘以这么多次，所以排序
of automatically concatenate it with itself.
自动地将它自身连接起来。
So if I run python of mario.py, this too works-- so,
所以如果我运行 mario.py 的 python，这也是可以的——所以，
again, just some features of Python that make it a little more
再次，只是一些 Python 的特性，使它更
pleasant to use so you don't always have to slog through implementing
使用起来更愉快，所以你不必总是费力地实现
a loop or something along those lines.
一个循环或类似的东西。
Well, what about something more two-dimensional,
那么，关于更二维的东西，
like in the world of this brick here?
就像在这块砖的世界里？
Well, in the context of this sort of grid of bricks,
那么，在这种砖块网格的背景下，
we might do something like this in VS Code.
我们可能会在 VS Code 中做这样的事情。
Let me go back to mario.py, and let me do a 3-by-3 grid for that block,
让我回到 mario.py，让我为那个块创建一个 3x3 的网格，
like we did in week 1.
就像我们在第一周做的那样。
So for i in range(3)--
所以，对于 i 在 range(3) 中——
I can nest loops, just like in C-- for j in range(3),
我可以嵌套循环，就像在 C 中一样——对于 j 在 range(3) 中，
I can then print out a hash here.
然后我可以在此处打印一个井号。
And then let's leave this alone even though it's not quite right yet.
然后让我们先不管它，尽管它还不完全正确。
Let's do python of mario.py.
让我们运行 mario.py 的 python。
OK, it's, like, nine bricks all in a column, which so your mind might
好的，它就像九块砖，都在一列，所以你的想法可能会
wander to the end parameter again.
再次想到 end 参数。
So, yeah, let's fix this-- end="", but at the end of that loop,
所以，是的，让我们修复它——end=""，但在那个循环的末尾，
let's just print out a new line.
让我们打印一个新行。
So this logically is the same as it was in C But in this case,
所以，这在逻辑上与它在 C 中一样，但在这种情况下，
I'm now doing it in Python, just a little more easily, without i++,
我现在在 Python 中做，只是更容易一些，不需要 i++，
without a conditional, I'm just relying on this for i in syntax using range().
不需要条件语句，我只依靠这个 for i in 语法使用 range()。
I can tighten this up further, frankly.
坦率地说，我可以进一步压缩它。
If I already have the outer loop, I could do something like this.
如果我已经有了外循环，我可以做这样的事情。
I could print out a single hash times 3.
我可以打印出三个井号。
And now if I run python of mario.py, that works, too.
现在，如果我运行 mario.py 的 python，它也起作用了。
So I can combine these ideas in interesting ways as well.
因此，我也可以以有趣的方式将这些想法结合起来。
The goal is simply to seed you with some of these building blocks.
目标只是用这些积木为你播种。
All right.
好的。
How about code that was maybe a little more logical in nature?
怎么样，也许更符合逻辑的代码？
Well, in Python, we indeed have some other features as well, namely lists.
那么，在 Python 中，我们确实还有一些其他特性，即列表。
And lists are denoted by those square brackets,
而列表由这些方括号表示，
reminiscent of the world of arrays.
让人想起数组的世界。
But in Python, what's really nice about lists
但在 Python 中，关于列表真正好的地方是，
is that their memory is automatically handled for you.
这意味着它们的内存会自动为你处理。
An array is about having values contiguously in memory.
数组指的是在内存中连续存储值。
In Python, a list is more like a linked list.
在 Python 中，列表更像一个链表。
It will allocate memory for you and grow and shrink these things.
它会为你分配内存，并可以扩展和缩减这些东西。
And you do not have to know about pointers.
你不需要了解指针。
You do not have to know about nodes.
你不需要了解节点。
You do not have to implement linked lists yourself.
你不需要自己实现链表。
You just get list as a data type in Python itself.
你直接在 Python 中获得列表作为数据类型。
Here, for instance, is some of the documentation for lists specifically.
例如，这里有一些关于列表的特定文档。
And in particular, lists also, like strings, or strs,
特别是，列表也像字符串或 strs 一样，
have methods, functions that come with them,
具有方法，即附带的函数，
that just make it easy to do certain things.
这使得做某些事情变得很容易。
So, for instance, if I wanted to maybe do something like taking averages
例如，如果我想做一些事情，比如计算平均值，
of scores, like we did some time ago, we can do that using a combination
比如我们之前做过的那样，我们可以使用列表和 len() 函数的组合
of lists and the function called len(), which I alluded to earlier,
我之前提到的 len() 函数，
which will tell you the length of a list.
它可以告诉你列表的长度。
Now, how might we do this?
我们现在该如何做呢？
Well, if we read the documentation for len(),
好吧，如果我们阅读 len() 函数的文档，
it turns out there's other functions there too that might be helpful.
我们会发现，那里还有其他一些可能有用的函数。
So let me go back to VS Code here.
所以，让我回到这里的 VS Code。
Let me close mario.py.
让我关闭 mario.py。
And let me open a file called scores.py, reminiscent of something
让我打开一个名为 scores.py 的文件，它让人想起我们之前做过的事情。
we did weeks ago, too.
我们几周前也做过。
Let me go ahead and, just for demonstration's sake,
让我继续，为了演示，
give myself a variable called scores that has my three test scores
给自己一个名为 scores 的变量，其中包含我的三次考试成绩
or whatnot from weeks ago.
或者几周前的那些成绩。
So I'm using square brackets, not curly braces, as in C. This is a linked list,
因此我使用方括号，而不是像在 C 中那样使用花括号。这是一个链表，
or a list in Python.
或者在 Python 中是列表。
And let me get the average of these values.
让我获取这些值的平均值。
Well, I could do this-- average =, and it turns out in Python,
好吧，我可以这样做 - average = ，事实证明，在 Python 中，
you just get a lot of functionality for free.
你得到了很多免费的功能。
And those functions sometimes take not single arguments,
这些函数有时不接受单个参数，
but lists as their arguments.
而是将列表作为参数。
So, for instance, I can use Python's built-in sum() function and pass
例如，我可以使用 Python 内置的 sum() 函数并传递
in those scores.
这些分数。
I can then divide that sum by the length of the scores list as well.
然后我也可以用这个和除以分数列表的长度。
So length of a list just tells you how many things are in it.
所以列表的长度就是告诉你它里面有多少个东西。
So this is like doing magically 72 plus 73 plus 33, all divided by 3 in total.
所以这就像神奇地将 72 加 73 加 33，然后除以总共 3 一样。
If I want to now do the math out, I can print the result.
如果我现在想进行计算，我可以打印出结果。
So I can print out, using an f string and maybe some prefix text here.
所以我可以使用 f 字符串和一些前缀文本打印出来。
Let's print out that average here.
让我们在这里打印出平均值。
So let me do python of scores.py, enter, and there
所以让我执行 scores.py 的 Python 脚本，回车，然后
is the average, slightly imprecisely.
就是平均值，稍微有点不精确。
But at that point, I'm not doing so well anyway.
但无论如何，我在那一点上的表现并不太好。
So that's fine.
所以没关系。
So at this point, we've seen that we have sort of more functionality than C.
所以，在这一点上，我们看到我们拥有的功能比 C 更多。
In C, how would we have computed the average weeks ago?
在 C 语言中，我们之前是如何计算平均值的？
I mean, we literally created a variable.
我的意思是，我们实际上创建了一个变量。
We then had a loop.
然后我们使用了一个循环。
We iterated over the array.
我们遍历了数组。
We added things together.
我们把东西加在一起。
It was just so much more work.
这只是多做了很多工作。
It's nice when you have a language that comes with functions, among them len(),
当你拥有一个包含函数的语言时，这很好，其中包括 len()，
among them sum(), that just does more of this for you.
其中包括 sum()，它可以为你做更多这样的事情。
But suppose you actually want to get the scores from the user.
但是假设你实际上想从用户那里获得分数。
In C, we used an array, and in C, we used get_int().
在 C 语言中，我们使用了一个数组，并且在 C 语言中，我们使用了 get_int()。
We can do something a little similar here.
我们在这里可以做一些类似的事情。
Let me propose that instead of hardcoding those three values,
让我建议，与其硬编码这三个值，
let me do this. from cs50 import get_int().
让我这样做。从 cs50 导入 get_int()。
Now let me give myself an empty list by just saying scores
现在让我通过说 scores 来给自己一个空列表
equals open bracket, closed bracket.
等于开括号，闭括号。
And unlike C, where you just can't do this-- you can't say give me an array
与 C 语言不同，你不能这样做——你不能说给我一个数组
and I'll figure out the length later, unless you resort
然后我稍后会确定长度，除非你诉诸
to pointers and memory management or the like, in Python
指针和内存管理等等，在 Python 中
you can absolutely give yourself an initially empty list.
你可以绝对给自己一个最初为空的列表。
Now let's do this. for i in range(3), let's
现在让我们这样做。对于 i in range(3)，让我们
prompt the human for three test scores.
提示用户输入三个考试分数。
So the first score will be the return value of get_int(),
所以第一个分数将是 get_int() 的返回值，
prompting the user for their score.
提示用户输入他们的分数。
And now, if I want to add this score to that otherwise empty list,
现在，如果我想将这个分数添加到那个原本为空的列表中，
here's where methods come into play, functions
这就是方法发挥作用的地方，函数
that come with objects, like lists.
与对象一起提供的，例如列表。
I can do scores, plural--
我可以做 scores，复数——
because that's the name of my variable from line 3-- .append,
因为这是我来自第 3 行的变量的名称——.append，
and I can append that score.
我可以追加那个分数。
So if we read the documentation for lists in Python,
所以，如果我们阅读 Python 中列表的文档，
you will see that lists come with a function, a method called append(),
你会看到列表带有一个函数，一个叫做 append() 的方法，
which literally just tacks a value onto the end, tacks a value onto the end,
它实际上只是将一个值追加到末尾，将一个值追加到末尾，
like all of that annoying code we would have written in C to iterate with
就像我们在 C 语言中编写的用来迭代的所有烦人的代码一样
pointer and pointer and pointer to the end of the list, append it,
指针和指针和指针到列表的末尾，追加它，
malloc() a new node.
malloc() 一个新的节点。
Python does all of that for us.
Python 为我们做了所有这些。
And so once you've done that, now I can do something similar to before.
所以一旦你做完了，我现在可以做一些类似之前的事情。
The average equals the sum of those scores divided
平均值等于这些分数的总和除以
by the length of that list of scores.
那个分数列表的长度。
And I can again print out, with an f string, the average value
我再次使用 f 字符串打印出平均值
in that variable like this.
在这个变量中，像这样。
So, again, you just have more building blocks at your disposal
所以，再次，你只是有更多的构建块供你使用
when it comes to something like this.
当涉及到像这样的事情时。
You can also do this, just so you've seen other syntax.
你也可以这样做，只是让你看到其他的语法。
It turns out that instead of doing scores.append, you could also do this.
事实证明，除了使用 scores.append，你还可以这样做。
You could concatenate scores with itself by adding two lists together like this.
你可以通过将两个列表加在一起的方式将 scores 与自身连接起来。
This looks a little weird.
这看起来有点奇怪。
But on the left is my variable scores.
但在左边是我的变量分数。
On the right here, I am taking whatever is in that list,
在右边这里，我正在获取该列表中的任何内容，
and I'm adding the current score by adding it to its own list.
并将当前得分添加到其自身列表中。
And this will update the value as we go.
这将随着我们的进行更新值。
But it does, in fact, change the value of score
但实际上，它确实改变了分数的值
as opposed to appending to the initial list.
而不是追加到初始列表。
All right.
好的。
How about some other building blocks here?
这里的一些其他构建块怎么样？
Let me propose this.
让我提出这个。
Let me close out scores.py.
让我关闭 scores.py。
Let me open up a file called phonebook.py,
让我打开一个名为 phonebook.py 的文件，
reminiscent of what we did weeks ago in C.
让人想起几周前我们在 C 语言中所做的。
And let me give myself a list of names.
让我给自己一个名字列表。
We won't bother with numbers just yet.
我们现在还不会考虑数字。
Let's just play with lists for another moment.
让我们再玩一下列表。
So here is a variable called names.
所以这里有一个名为 names 的变量。
It has maybe three names in it-- maybe Carter and David
它可能包含三个名字——可能是卡特和戴维
and John Harvard, as in past weeks.
还有约翰·哈佛，就像过去几周一样。
And now let me go ahead and ask the user to input a name--
现在让我继续要求用户输入一个名字——
because this is going to be like a phone book.
因为这将就像一本电话簿。
I want to ask the user for a name and then look up
我想询问用户姓名，然后查找
that person's name and the phone book, even though I'm not bothering
那个人的名字和电话簿，即使我没有费心
by having any phone numbers just yet.
暂时没有电话号码。
How could I search for, a la linear search, someone's name?
我怎样才能像线性搜索一样搜索某人的姓名呢？
Well, in Python I could do this. for name--
好吧，在 Python 中我可以这样做。 对于姓名——
rather, for n in names, if the current name equals what the human typed in,
更确切地说，对于 names 中的 n，如果当前姓名等于人类输入的姓名，
then go ahead and print out "Found," then break out of this loop.
然后继续打印“已找到”，然后退出此循环。
Otherwise, we'll print out "Not found" at the bottom.
否则，我们将在底部打印“未找到”。
All right.
好的。
So let's try this-- python of phonebook.py.
所以让我们尝试一下——phonebook.py 的 Python。
Let's search for maybe Carter.
让我们搜索一下可能存在的卡特。
That's easy.
这很容易。
He's at the beginning.
他在开头。
Oh, hmm.
哦，嗯。
Well, he was found, but then I printed "Not found."
好吧，他被找到了，但我却打印了“未找到”。
So that's not quite what I want.
所以这并不完全是我想要的。
How about David?
戴维呢？
D-A-V-I-D. "Found," "Not found"--
D-A-V-I-D。“已找到”，“未找到”——
all right, not very correct.
好吧，不太正确。
How about this?
这个怎么样？
Let's search for Eli, not in the list.
让我们搜索一下不在列表中的伊莱。
OK.
好的。
So at least someone not being in the list is working.
所以至少不在列表中的人是有效的。
But logically, for Carter, for David, and even John,
但从逻辑上讲，对于卡特、戴维甚至约翰，
why are we seeing "Found" and then "Not found?"
为什么我们会看到“已找到”，然后是“未找到”？
Why is it not found?
为什么找不到？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: You need to intend the print().
观众：你需要缩进 print()。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
大卫·马兰：好的。
I don't have seem to have indented the print(), but let me try this.
我似乎没有缩进 print()，但我试试这个。
If I just go with the else here--
如果我直接在 else 这里使用它，
let me go up here and indent this and say else--
让我到这里，缩进它，然后写 else
I'm not sure logically this is what we want,
从逻辑上讲，我不确定这就是我们想要的，
because what I think this is going to do if I search for maybe Carter--
因为我认为，如果我要搜索 Carter，这将是...
OK, that worked.
好吧，成功了。
So it's partially fixed the problem.
所以它部分解决了问题。
But let me try searching for maybe David.
但让我试着搜索 David。
Oh, now we're sort of the opposite problem--
哦，现在我们遇到的是相反的问题，
"Not found," "Found."
“未找到”，“找到”。
Why?
为什么？
Well, I don't think we want to immediately conclude
好吧，我认为我们不想立刻得出结论，
that someone's not found just because they don't
某人没有找到，仅仅是因为他们没有
equal the current name in the list.
等于列表中当前的名称。
So it turns out we could fix this in a couple of different ways.
所以事实证明，我们可以通过几种不同的方式来修复它。
But there's kind of a neat features of Python.
但 Python 有一个很酷的功能。
In Python, even for loops can have an else clause.
在 Python 中，即使是 for 循环也可以有 else 语句。
And this is weird.
这很奇怪。
But the way this works is as follows.
但它的工作原理如下。
In Python, if you break out of a loop, that's it for the for loop.
在 Python 中，如果你从循环中跳出，就结束了 for 循环。
If, though, you get all the way through the list that you're looping over,
但是，如果你遍历了整个列表，
and you never once call line 8-- you never break out of the loop--
而且你从来没有调用过第 8 行，你从来没有跳出循环，
Python is smart enough to realize, OK, you just
Python 足够聪明，它意识到，好吧，你只是
went through lines 5 through 8.
遍历了第 5 行到第 8 行。
You never actually logically called break.
实际上你并没有逻辑地调用 break。
Here's an else clause to be associated with it.
这里有一个 else 语句与它关联。
Semantically, this is weird.
从语义上讲，这很奇怪。
We've only ever seen if and else associated with each other.
我们只见过 if 和 else 彼此关联。
But for loops in Python actually can have else as well.
但 Python 中的 for 循环实际上也可以有 else。
And in this case now, if I do python of phonebook.py, type in Carter,
在这种情况下，现在，如果我运行 phonebook.py，输入 Carter，
now we get only one answer.
现在我们只得到一个答案。
If I do it again and type in David, now we get only one answer.
如果我再次运行并输入 David，现在我们只得到一个答案。
Do it again with John.
再试一次，输入 John。
Now we get only one answer.
现在我们只得到一个答案。
Do it with Eli.
输入 Eli。
Now we get only one answer.
现在我们只得到一个答案。
So, again, you just get a few more tools in your toolkit
所以，再次，你只是在你的工具箱里获得了一些额外的工具，
when it comes to a language like Python that might very well make solving
对于像 Python 这样的语言，这可能会让解决问题变得更轻松。
problems a little more pleasant.
让解决问题变得更加愉快。
But this is kind of stupid in Python.
但在 Python 中这有点蠢。
This is correct, but it's not well designed,
这是正确的，但它设计得不好，
because I don't need to iterate over lists like this so pedantically
因为我不需要像这样那么迂腐地遍历列表，
like we've been doing for weeks in C.
就像我们在 C 语言中几个星期以来一直在做的那样。
I can actually tighten this up, and I can just do this.
我实际上可以简化它，我可以直接做这个。
I can get rid of the loop, and I can say if name in names, then print out,
我可以去掉循环，然后可以写 if name in names，然后打印出，
quote unquote, "Found."
引号，"找到”。
That's it in Python.
这就是 Python 中的做法。
If you want Python to search a whole list of values for you,
如果你想让 Python 为你搜索整个值的列表，
just let Python do the work.
就让 Python 做这项工作。
And you can literally just say if the name that the human inputted is
你可以直接说，如果人类输入的名称是
in names, which is this list here, Python will use linear search for you,
在名称中，也就是这里列表中，Python 会为你使用线性搜索，
search automatically from left to right, presumably, looking for the value.
它会自动地从左到右进行搜索，大概是在寻找这个值。
And if it doesn't find it then and only then will
如果它没有找到，也只有在这种情况下才会
this else clause execute instead.
执行这个 else 子句。
So, again, Python's just starting to save us
所以，同样，Python 刚刚开始为我们省时间
some time because this, too, will find Carter, but it will not find,
因为这个也会找到 Carter，但它不会找到
for instance, Eli.
例如，Eli。
All right?
好的吧？
So we get that functionality for free.
所以我们免费获得了这个功能。
But what more can we perhaps do here?
但是我们还可以在这里做些什么呢？
Well, it turns out that Python has yet other features
事实证明，Python 还有其他特性
we might want to explore, namely dictionaries, shortened as dict.
我们可能想要探索，也就是字典，缩写为 dict。
And a dictionary in Python is just like it was in C and, really,
Python 中的字典和 C 中一样，实际上，
in computer science in general.
在计算机科学中，通常都是这样。
A dictionary was an abstract data type.
字典是一种抽象数据类型。
And it's a collection of key value pairs it looks a little something like this.
它是一组键值对，它看起来有点像这样。
If in C, if in Python, if, in any language,
如果在 C 中，如果在 Python 中，如果，在任何语言中，
you want to associate something with something, like a name with a number,
你想将某个东西与另一个东西关联起来，比如将姓名与数字关联起来，
you had to, in problem set 5, implement the darn thing yourself
在问题集 5 中，你不得不自己实现这个东西
by implementing an entire spell checker with an array and linked list
通过使用数组和链表来实现一个完整的拼写检查器
to store all of those words in your dictionary.
来存储字典中的所有单词。
In Python, as we saw earlier, you can use a set, or you can use,
在 Python 中，正如我们之前看到的，你可以使用一个集合，或者你可以使用
more simply, a dictionary that implements for you all of problem
更简单地说，是一个为你实现所有问题的字典
set 5's ideas.
问题集 5 的想法。
But Python does the heavy lifting for you.
但是 Python 为你做了繁重的工作。
A dict in Python is essentially a hash table, a collection of key value pairs.
Python 中的 dict 本质上是一个哈希表，是一组键值对。
So what does this mean for me in Python?
那么这对我在 Python 中意味着什么？
It means that I can do some pretty handy things pretty easily.
这意味着我可以很容易地做一些非常方便的事情。
So, for instance, let me go back here to VS Code,
所以，例如，让我回到 VS Code，
and let me change my phone book altogether to be this.
让我将我的电话簿完全改为这样。
Let me give myself a list of dictionaries.
让我给自己一个字典列表。
So people is now going to be a global list.
所以 people 现在将是一个全局列表。
And I'm going to demarcate it here with open square bracket
我将用左方括号来标记它
and closed square bracket.
和右方括号。
And just to be nice and neat and tidy, I'm
为了整洁美观，我
going to have these people no longer just be Carter and David and John,
不再让这些人只是 Carter、David 和 John，
as in the previous example.
就像上一个例子一样。
But I want each of the elements of this list to be a key value
但我希望这个列表的每个元素都是一个键值
pair, like a name and a number.
对，比如姓名和数字。
So how can I do this?
我该如何做到呢？
In Python, you can use this syntax.
在 Python 中，你可以使用这种语法。
And this is, I think, the last of the weird looking syntax today.
我认为这是今天最后一种看起来很奇怪的语法。
You can define a dictionary that is something like this
你可以定义一个类似于这样的字典
by using two curly braces like this.
使用两个花括号，就像这样。
And inside of your curly braces, you get to invent
在你的花括号中，你可以创造
the name, the keys, and the values.
名称、键和值。
So if you want one key to be the person's name, you can do,
所以如果你想让一个键是人的姓名，你可以这样做，
quote unquote, "name" and then, quote unquote, "Carter."
引号引起来，"name" 然后，引号引起来，"Carter"。
If you want another key to be "number," you can do, quote unquote, "number,"
如果你想要另一个键是 "number"，你可以做，引号引起来，"number"，
and then, quote unquote, something like last time, "1-617-495-1000,"
然后，引号引起来，就像上次一样，"1-617-495-1000"，
for instance, for Carter's number there.
例如，这是 Carter 的电话号码。
And collectively, everything here on line 2 represents a dictionary.
总体而言，这里第 2 行的所有内容都代表一个字典。
It's as though, on a chalkboard, I wrote down "name, Carter, number,
就好像我在黑板上写下 "name, Carter, number,
+1-617-495-1000," row by row by row in this table.
+1-617-495-1000"，一行一行地在表格里写。
This is simply the code equivalent thereof.
这只是代码等价物。
If you want to be really nitpicky or tidy,
如果你真的想要挑剔或者整洁，
you could style your code to look like this,
你可以将代码样式设置为这样，
which makes it a little more clear, perhaps, as to what's going on.
这可能让代码更加清晰地展示正在发生的事情。
It's just starting to add a lot of whitespace to the screen.
只是开始在屏幕上添加很多空白。
But it's just a collection of key value pairs,
但它只是一个键值对集合，
again, akin to a two-column table like this.
再次强调，它类似于这样一个两列表格。
I'm going to undo the whitespace just to kind of tighten things up because I
我要撤销空白，让代码更加紧凑，因为我要
want to cram two other people in here.
在这里塞进另外两个人。
So I'm going to go ahead and do another set of curly braces with,
所以我要继续添加另一组花括号，里面包含，
quote unquote, "name" and "David," quote unquote, "number"--
引号引起来，"name" 和 "David"，引号引起来，"number" --
and we'll have the same number, so "+1-617-495-1000."
他们的电话号码相同，都是 "+1-617-495-1000"。
And then, lastly, let's do another set of curly braces for a name of say
最后，我们再添加一组花括号，里面包含一个叫做
"John," and John Harvard's number, quote unquote, "number" will be "+1"--
"John" 的人，John Harvard 的电话号码，引号引起来，"number" 将是 "+1" --
let's see-- "949-468-2750" is always John Harvard's number.
让我们看看 -- "949-468-2750" 永远是 John Harvard 的电话号码。
And then, by convention, you typically end even this element with a comma.
然后，按照惯例，你通常会用逗号结束这个元素。
But it's not strictly necessary syntactically.
但在语法上它并非严格必须。
But stylistically, that's often added for you.
但在风格上，它通常会被添加进去。
So what is people?
那么 people 是什么呢？
people is now a list of dictionaries, a list of dictionaries.
people 现在是一个字典列表，一个字典列表。
So what does that mean?
所以这意味着什么？
It means I can now do code like this.
这意味着我现在可以编写这样的代码。
I can prompt the user with the input() function for someone's name if the goal
我可以使用 input() 函数提示用户输入某人的姓名，如果目标
now is to look up that person's number.
是查找该人的电话号码。
How can I look up that number?
我如何查找那个号码？
Well, for each person in the list of people, let's go ahead and do this.
好了，对于 people 列表中的每个人，让我们继续执行以下操作。
If the current person's name equals equals whatever name the human
如果当前人的姓名等于用户输入的姓名，那么通过进入该人的信息并执行以下操作，获取该人的电话号码。
typed in, then get that person's number by going into that person and doing,
引号引起来，"number"，然后继续
quote unquote, "number," and then go ahead
并打印出类似于以下格式的字符串 "Found" 该人的电话号码。
and print out something like this f string "Found" that person's number.
然后，既然我们找到了他们，我们就一起退出。
And then, since we found them, let's just break out all together.
如果我们遍历了整个列表，那么就在最后打印
And if we get through that whole thing, let's just, at the very end, print
出 "Not found"。
out "Not found."
这里有什么奇怪的地方？
So what's weird here?
如果我关注这段代码，很明显，这种语法是新的。
If I focus on this code here, this syntax obviously is new.
方括号，意思是，嘿，Python，这里有一个列表。
The square brackets, though, just means, hey, Python, here comes a list.
嘿，Python，列表到此为止。
Hey, Python, that's it for the list.
Inside of this list are three dictionaries.
这个列表里面有三个字典。
The curly braces mean, hey, Python, here comes a dictionary.
花括号的意思是，嘿，Python，这里有一个字典。
Hey, Python, that's it for the dictionary.
嘿，Python，字典到此为止了。
Each of these dictionaries has two key value pairs--
每个字典都有两个键值对——
"name" and its value, "number" and its value.
“name”和它的值，“number”和它的值。
So you can think of each of these lines as being like a C struct,
所以你可以把这些行想象成一个 C 结构体，
like with typedef and struct.
就像使用 typedef 和 struct 一样。
But I don't have to decide in advance what the keys and the values
但我不用提前决定键和值
are going to be.
是什么。
I can just, on the fly, create a dictionary like this,
我可以直接，在运行时，像这样创建一个字典，
again, reminiscent of this kind of chalkboard design.
再次，让人想起这种黑板设计。
All right.
好的。
So what am I actually doing in code?
那么我在代码中到底做了什么？
A dictionary in Python lets you index into it,
Python 中的字典允许你索引它，
similar to an array with numbers in C. So in C, this
类似于 C 中带数字的数组。所以在 C 中，这
is a little bit different.
有点不同。
In C, you might have been in the habit of doing person.name.
在 C 中，你可能习惯于做 person.name。
But because it's a dictionary, the syntax in Python
但因为它是一个字典，Python 中的语法
is you actually use square brackets with strings
是你实际上使用方括号，里面是字符串
as being inside the square brackets rather than numbers.
而不是数字。
But all this is now doing is it's creating a variable on line 11,
但现在它所做的一切只是在第 11 行创建一个变量，
setting that number equal to that same person's number.
将该数字设置为与该人的数字相同。
Why?
为什么？
Because we're inside of this loop, I'm iterating
因为我们在循环中，我正在迭代
over each person one at a time.
每个人的时间。
And that's what for--
那就是 for——
that's what n does.
那就是 n 所做的。
It assigns the person variable to this dictionary, then this dictionary,
它将 person 变量分配给这个字典，然后分配给这个字典，
then this dictionary automatically for me--
然后自动分配给这个字典——
no need for i and i++ and all of that.
不需要 i 和 i++ 以及所有这些。
So this is just saying, if the current person's name
所以这只是说，如果当前人的名字
equals the name we're looking for, get a variable called number and assign it
等于我们正在寻找的名字，得到一个名为 number 的变量并分配它
that person's number, and then print out that person's number.
该人的号码，然后打印出该人的号码。
So whereas last time we were just printing "Found" and "Not found,"
所以，上次我们只是打印“Found”和“Not found”，
now I'm going to print an actual number.
现在我要打印一个实际的数字。
So if I run python of phonebook.py and I search for Carter,
所以，如果我运行 phonebook.py 的 python 并搜索 Carter，
there then is his number.
那里就是他的号码。
If I run python of phonebook.py, type in John, there then is John's number.
如果我运行 phonebook.py 的 python，输入 John，那里就是 John 的号码。
And if I search for someone who's not there, I instead just get "Not found."
如果我搜索一个不在那里的人，我只会得到“Not found”。
So what's interesting and compelling about dictionaries
所以，字典有趣且引人入胜的地方在于
is they're kind of known as the Swiss Army knives of data structures
它们被称为数据结构的瑞士军刀
in programming because you can just use them
在编程中，因为你可以随意使用它们
in so many interesting, clever ways.
以很多有趣、巧妙的方式。
If you ever want to associate something with something else,
如果你想将某些东西与其他东西关联起来，
a dictionary is your friend.
字典就是你的朋友。
And you no longer have to write dozens of lines of code as in P set 5.
你不再需要像 P set 5 那样编写数十行代码。
You can write single lines of code to achieve this same idea.
你可以编写单行代码来实现同样的想法。
So, for instance, if I, too, want to tighten this up,
例如，如果我也想把这个收紧，
I actually don't need this loop altogether.
实际上，我根本不需要这个循环。
An even better version of this code would be this.
这段代码有一个更好的版本。
I don't need this variable, technically, even
从技术上讲，我甚至不需要这个变量，
though this will look a little uglier.
尽管这看起来有点丑。
Notice that I'm only creating a variable called number
请注意，我只创建了一个名为 number 的变量，
because I want to set it equal to this person's number.
因为我想把它设置为这个人的电话号码。
But strictly speaking, any time you've declared a variable
但严格地说，任何时候你声明一个变量，
and then used it in the next line, eh, you don't really need it.
然后在下一行使用它，嗯，你真的不需要它。
So I could do this.
所以我可以这样做。
I could get rid of that line.
我可以去掉那行。
And instead of printing "number" in my curly braces,
而不用在我的花括号中打印 "number"，
I could actually do person, square brackets,
我可以实际做 person，方括号，
and you might be inclined to do this.
你可能倾向于这样做。
But this is going to confuse Python because you're mixing double quotes
但这会让 Python 困惑，因为你在内部和外部混合了双引号
on the inside and the outside.
在内部和外部。
But you can use single quotes here, compellingly.
但你可以在这里使用单引号，很有说服力。
So you don't have to do it this way.
所以你不必这样去做。
But this is just to show you, syntactically,
但这只是为了从语法上向你展示，
you can put most anything you want in these curly braces
你可以在这些花括号中放入你想要的任何东西
so long as you don't confuse Python by using the same syntax.
只要你不通过使用相同的语法来混淆 Python。
But let me do one other thing here.
但让我在这里做另外一件事。
This is even more powerful.
这更强大。
Let me propose that if all you're storing
让我假设，如果你所存储的全部是
is names and numbers, names and numbers, I can actually
姓名和电话号码，姓名和电话号码，我实际上可以
simplify this dictionary significantly.
显著简化这个字典。
Let me actually redeclare this people data structure
让我重新声明这个 people 数据结构
to be not a list of dictionaries, but how about just one big dictionary?
不要是一个字典列表，而是只有一个大字典怎么样？
Because if I'm only associating names with numbers,
因为如果我只将姓名与电话号码关联起来，
I don't technically need to create special keys
我从技术上讲不需要创建名为 "name" 和 "number" 的特殊键
called "name" and "number."
名为 "name" 和 "number"。
Why don't I just associate Carter with his number, +1-617-495-1000?
为什么我不直接将 Carter 与他的电话号码 +1-617-495-1000 关联起来？
Why don't I just associate, quote unquote, "David" with his number,
为什么我不直接将 "David" 与他的电话号码
+1-617-495-1000?
+1-617-495-1000 关联起来？
And then, lastly, let's just associate John with his number, +1-949-468-2750?
然后，最后，让我们只将 John 与他的电话号码 +1-949-468-2750 关联起来？
And that too would work.
这样也可以。
But notice that I'm going to get rid of my list of people
但请注意，我要去掉我的 people 列表
and instead just have one dictionary of people, the downside of which
而只保留一个 people 字典，缺点是
is that you can only have one key, one value, one key, one value.
你只能有一个键，一个值，一个键，一个值。
You can't have a name key and a number key and an email key and an address key
你不能有一个 name 键，一个 number 键，一个 email 键和一个 address 键
and any number of other pieces of data that might be compelling.
以及其他任何可能引人注目的数据。
But if you've only got key value pairs like this,
但如果你只有像这样的键值对，
we can tighten up this code significantly so that now, down here,
我们可以显著压缩这段代码，这样现在，在这里，
I can actually do this.
我实际上可以这样做。
If the name I'm looking for is somewhere in that people dictionary,
如果我在 people 字典中找到了我要找的姓名，
then go ahead and get the person's number
那就继续获取这个人的电话号码
by going into the people dictionary, indexing into it at that person's name,
通过进入 people 字典，在该人的姓名处索引到它，
and then printing out "Found," for instance, that here number,
然后打印出 "Found"，例如，这里的号码，
making this an f string, else you can go ahead
将它改为一个 f 字符串，否则你可以继续
and print out "Not found" in this case here.
并在这种情况下打印出 "未找到"。
So, again, the difference is that the previous version created
所以，再次强调，不同之处在于之前的版本创建了
a list of dictionaries, and I very manually,
一个字典列表，我手动地
methodically, iterated over it, looking for the person.
有条理地遍历了它，寻找这个人。
But what's nice again about dictionaries is
但字典的好处在于
that Python gives you a lot of support for just looking into them easily.
Python 为你提供了很多便利的查找方式。
And this syntax, just like you can use it for lists,
这种语法，就像你在列表中使用它一样，
you can use it for dictionaries as well.
你也可以在字典中使用它。
And Python will look for that name among the keys in the dictionary.
Python 会在字典的键中寻找那个名字。
And if it finds it, you use this syntax to get at that person's number.
如果它找到了，你可以使用这种语法来获取那个人的号码。
Whew, OK.
哇，好吧。
A lot all at once, but are there any questions on this here syntax?
一下子讲了很多，但关于这种语法，大家有什么问题吗？
We'll then introduce a couple of final features with a final flourish.
然后我们将以最后的点睛之笔介绍几个最后的特性。
Yes?
有吗？
AUDIENCE: This way [INAUDIBLE] break [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：这样 [听不清]  break  [听不清]..
DAVID MALAN: In this case, I do not need to use break
大卫·马兰：在这种情况下，我不需要使用 break
because I don't have any loop involved.
因为我没有使用任何循环。
So break is only used, as we've seen it, in the context of looping
所以，正如我们所见，break 仅在循环的上下文中使用
over something when you want to terminate the loop early.
当你想提前终止循环时，在循环某个东西时使用它。
But here Python is doing the searching for you.
但这里 Python 帮你进行搜索。
So Python is taking care of that automatically.
所以 Python 自动处理了这件事。
All right.
好的。
Just a couple of final features so that you have a couple of more building
最后再介绍几个特性，这样你就能拥有更多构建
blocks-- here is the documentation for dictionaries themselves
模块 - 这里是字典本身的文档
in case you want to poke around as to what more you can do with them.
如果你想知道你能用它们做更多的事情，你可以查阅文档。
But it turns out that there are other libraries that
但事实证明，还有其他库
come with Python, not even third-party, and one of them
与 Python 一起提供，甚至不是第三方库，其中一个
is the sys library, whereby you have system-related functionality.
是 sys 库，它提供了与系统相关的功能。
And here's its official documentation, for instance.
例如，这是它的官方文档。
But what this means is that certain functionality that was just
但这意味着某些在 C 语言中可以直接使用的功能
immediately available in C is sometimes tucked away now into libraries
现在有时会被隐藏在 Python 的库中
in Python.
中。
So, for instance, let me go over to VS Code
例如，让我打开 VS Code
here, and let me just create a program called greet.py, which
这里，让我创建一个名为 greet.py 的程序，它
is reminiscent of an old C program that just greets
让人想起一个旧的 C 程序，它只是用
the user using command-line arguments.
命令行参数来问候用户。
But in C, recall that we got access to command-line arguments with main()
但请记住，在 C 语言中，我们使用 main() 获取命令行参数
and argc and argv.
以及 argc 和 argv。
But none of those have we seen at all today.
但我们今天还没有看到过这些。
And, in fact, main() itself is no longer required.
事实上，main() 本身不再是必需的。
So if you want to do command-line arguments in Python,
所以如果你想在 Python 中使用命令行参数，
you actually do this.
你需要这样做。
From the sys library, you can import something called argv.
从 sys 库中，你可以导入一个名为 argv 的东西。
So argv still exists.
所以 argv 仍然存在。
It's just tucked away inside of this library, otherwise known as a module.
它只是被隐藏在这个库中，也被称为模块。
And I can then do this.
然后我就可以这样做。
If the length of argv, for instance, does not equal 2,
如果 argv 的长度不等于 2，
well, then, we're going to go ahead and do what we did--
那么，我们将继续做我们之前做过的事情——
or rather, let's do this.
或者，我们这样做。
If the length of argv does equal 2, we're
如果 argv 的长度等于 2，我们
going to go ahead and do what we did a couple of weeks
将继续做我们几周前做过的事情
ago, whereby I'm going to print out "hello,"
之前，我将打印出“hello”，
comma, and then argv bracket 1, for instance,
逗号，然后是 argv 中括号 1，例如，
so whatever is in location 1 of that list.
也就是说列表中位置 1 的内容。
Else, if the length of argv is not equal to 2-- that is,
否则，如果 argv 的长度不等于 2——也就是说，
the human did not type two words at the prompt--
用户没有在提示符处输入两个单词——
let's go ahead and print out "hello, world" by default.
让我们默认打印出“hello, world”。
So we did the exact same thing in C. The only difference here is that this now
所以我们在 C 中做了完全相同的事情。这里唯一的区别是，现在
is how you get access to argv.
就是你如何访问 argv。
So let me run this-- python of greet.py and hit Enter. "hello, world" is all I
所以让我运行一下——python of greet.py 然后按回车。“hello, world” 就是我
get.
得到的。
And actually, I got an extra line break because out of habit,
事实上，我得到了一个额外的换行，因为习惯使然，
I included backslash n, but I don't need that in Python.
我包含了反斜杠 n，但在 Python 中我不需要它。
So let me fix that. python of greet.py-- "hello, world."
所以让我修正一下。python of greet.py——“hello, world”。
But if I do python of greet.py, D-A-V-I-D,
但如果我输入 python of greet.py，D-A-V-I-D，
now notice that argv equals 2.
现在请注意 argv 等于 2。
If I instead do something like Carter, argv now equals 2.
如果我改为输入类似 Carter 的内容，argv 现在等于 2。
But there is a difference.
但存在一个区别。
Technically, I'm typing three words at the prompt, three words at the prompt,
从技术上讲，我在提示符处输入了三个单词，在提示符处输入了三个单词，
but argv still only equals 2 because the command python is ignored from argv.
但 argv 仍然只等于 2，因为命令 python 被 argv 忽略了。
It's only the name of your file and the thing you type after it.
它只是你的文件名和你在它之后输入的内容。
So that's then how we might print out arguments in Python using argv.
所以这就是我们如何使用 argv 在 Python 中打印出参数。
Well, what else might we do using some of these here features?
好吧，我们还可以使用这里的一些功能做些什么？
Well, it turns out that you can exit from programs using this same sys
事实证明，你可以使用相同的 sys 从程序中退出
library.
库。
So let me close greet.py.
所以让我关闭 greet.py。
Let me open up exit.py just for demonstration's sake.
让我打开 exit.py，只是为了演示。
And let's do something like this.
让我们做一些类似这样的事情。
Let's import sys.
让我们导入 sys。
And if the length of sys.argv--
如果 sys.argv 的长度——
so here's just another way of doing this.
所以这只是另一种方法。
And actually, I'll do it the same first-- from sys import argv.
事实上，我将先用相同的方式做——从 sys 导入 argv。
If the length of argv does not equal 2--
如果 argv 的长度不等于 2——
well, let's actually yell at the user with something
那么，让我们实际上用一些东西吼一下用户
like "Missing command-line argument."
比如“缺少命令行参数”。
And then what we can do is exit out of the program entirely using sys.exit(),
然后我们可以使用 sys.exit() 完全退出程序，
which is a function therein.
这是一个其中的函数。
But notice that exit() is a function in sys.
但请注意 exit() 是 sys 中的一个函数。
So you know what?
所以你知道吗？
It's actually more convenient in this case.
在这种情况下，它实际上更方便。
Let's just import all of sys.
让我们只导入 sys 的所有内容。
But because that has not given me direct access to argv,
但因为这没有给我直接访问 argv 的权限，
let me do sys.argv here and sys.exit() here.
让我在这里做 sys.argv 以及在这里做 sys.exit()。
Otherwise, if all is well, let's just go ahead and print out something
否则，如果一切顺利，让我们继续打印出一些东西
like "hello, sys.argv," bracket 1, close quote, and that will print out "hello,
像“hello，sys.argv”，方括号1，引号结束，这将打印出“hello，
so-and-so."
某某”。
And when I'm ready to exit with a non-0--
当我准备以非0退出时--
with a 0 exit status, I can actually start to specify these things here.
以0退出状态，我可以真正开始在此指定这些东西。
So just like in C, if you want to exit from a program with 1 or 2
所以就像在C语言中一样，如果你想用1或2退出程序
or anything else, you can use sys.exit.
或者其他任何东西，你可以使用sys.exit。
And if you want to exit with a 0, you can do this here instead.
如果你想以0退出，你可以在此处这样做。
So we have the same capabilities as in C,
所以我们有与C语言相同的性能，
just accessed a little bit differently.
只是访问方式略有不同。
Let me propose that--
让我提议一下--
let's see.
让我们看看。
Let me propose that--
让我提议一下--
how about this?
这个怎么样？
How about this?
If we want to go ahead and create something a little more interactive,
如果我们想继续创建一些更交互的东西，
recall that there was that command a while back, namely
回想一下之前有一个命令，即
pip, whereby I ran pip install face_recognition.
pip，我用它运行了pip install face_recognition。
That's one of the examples with which we began.
这是我们开始使用的示例之一。
And that allows me to install more functionality from a third party
它允许我从第三方安装更多功能
into my own code space or my programming environment more generally.
到我自己的代码空间或更一般地我的编程环境中。
Well, we can have a little fun with this, in fact.
事实上，我们可以用它来玩点乐子。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我回到VS Code这里。
And just like there's a command in Linux called cowsay,
就像Linux中有一个叫做cowsay的命令一样，
whereby you can get the cow to say something,
你可以让牛说点什么，
you can also use this kind of thing in Python.
你也可以在Python中使用这种东西。
So if I do pip install cowsay, this, if it's not installed already,
所以如果我执行pip install cowsay，如果它还没有安装，
will install a library called cowsay.
将安装一个叫做cowsay的库。
And what this means is that if I actually want to code up a program
这意味着，如果我真的想编写一个程序
called, like, moo.py, I can import the cowsay library,
叫做 moo.py，我可以导入cowsay库，
and I can do something simple like cowsay.cow,
我可以做一些简单的事情，比如cowsay.cow，
because there's a function in this library called cow(),
因为这个库中有一个叫做cow()的函数，
and I can say something like "This is CS50," quote unquote.
我可以说一些类似“这是CS50”之类的话，引号结束。
How do I run this program?
我该如何运行这个程序？
I can run python of moo.py, and-- oh, underwhelming.
我可以运行python moo.py，然后--哦，太不令人满意了。
If I increase the size of my terminal window, run python of moo.py,
如果我增加终端窗口的大小，运行python moo.py，
we have that same adorable cow as before,
我们有之前那只可爱的牛，
but I now have programmatic capabilities with which to manipulate it.
但我现在有了可以用来操控它的编程能力。
And so, in fact, I could make this program a little more interesting.
所以事实上，我可以让这个程序更有趣一点。
I could do something like name = quote--
我可以做一些类似 name = 引号--
or rather, name = input("What's your name?") and combine some
或者更确切地说，name = input("你的名字是？")并结合一些
of today's ideas.
今天的想法。
And now I can say not "This is CS50," but something like,
现在我可以不说什么“这是CS50”，而是说一些类似，
quote unquote, "Hello," comma, person's name.
引号结束，"Hello"，逗号，人的名字。
And now, if I increase the size of my terminal, rerun python of moo.py,
现在，如果我增加终端的大小，重新运行python moo.py，
it's not going to actually moo or say "This is CS50."
它不会真的哞哞叫或说“这是CS50”。
It's going to say something like "hello, David," and so forth.
它会说一些类似“hello，David”之类的话，等等。
And suffice it to say through other functions,
而且可以这么说，通过其他函数，
you can do not only cows but dragons and other fancy things, too.
你可以不只画奶牛，还可以画龙和其他更奇特的东西。
But even in Python, too, can you generate not just ASCII art,
但是即使在 Python 中，你也不只是可以生成 ASCII 艺术，
but actual art and actual images.
还可以生成真实的艺术和图像。
And the note I thought we'd end on is doing one other library.
而我想用另一个库来结束这节课。
I'm going to go back into VS Code here.
我现在要回到 VS Code 中。
I'm going to close moo.py.
我要关闭 moo.py 文件。
I'm going to do pip install qrcode, which is the name of a library
我要执行 pip install qrcode 命令，qrcode 是一个库的名称
that I might want to install to generate QR codes automatically.
我可能想要安装它来自动生成二维码。
And QR codes are these two-dimensional bar codes.
二维码是二维条形码。
If you want to generate these things yourself,
如果你想自己生成这些东西，
you don't have to go to a website and type in a URL.
你不需要去网站输入一个 URL。
You can actually write this kind of code yourself.
你可以自己编写这种代码。
So how might I do this?
那么我应该怎么做呢？
Well, let me go into a new file called, say, qr.py.
好吧，让我创建一个新文件，比如叫 qr.py。
And let me do this.
让我来试试这个。
Let me go ahead and import this library called qrcode.
让我导入这个叫做 qrcode 的库。
Let me go ahead and create a variable called image, or anything else.
让我创建一个名为 image 的变量，或者任何其他名称。
Let me set it equal to this library's qrcodes function called
让我将其设置为该库的 qrcodes 函数，该函数叫做
make-- no relationship to C. It's just called make
make，与 C 无关。它就是叫做 make
because you want to make a QR code.
因为你想创建一个二维码。
Let me type in, maybe, the URL of a lecture video here on YouTube--
让我输入一个 YouTube 上的讲座视频的 URL——
so, like, youtu.be/xvFZjo5PgG0, quote unquote.
例如，youtu.be/xvFZjo5PgG0，引号内的内容。
And then I can go ahead and do img.save because inside of this image variable,
然后我可以继续执行 img.save 命令，因为在这个 image 变量中，
which is a different data type that this library gave me--
它是一个不同类型的变量，这个库给了我——
it doesn't come with Python per se--
它本身并不属于 Python——
I can save a file like qr.png, And I can save it in the PNG format, the Portable
我可以保存一个像 qr.png 这样的文件，而且我可以将其保存为 PNG 格式，即可移植
Network Graphic.
网络图形。
And so just to be clear, what this should hopefully
所以，为了更清楚地说明，我希望这
do for me is create a QR code containing that particular URL,
能为我做的是创建一个包含该特定 URL 的二维码，
but not as text, but rather as an actual image that I can send,
但不是文本形式，而是我可以发送的实际图像，
I can post online, or, in our case, generate into my code space,
我可以将其发布到网上，或者在我们的例子中，将其生成到我的代码空间中，
and then open.
然后打开它。
And so, with all that said, we've seen a bunch of new syntax
所以，综上所述，我们今天看到了很多新的语法
today, a bunch of new features.
以及很多新的功能。
But the ideas underlying Python are exactly the same as they've been in C.
但是 Python 的底层思想与 C 中的思想完全相同。
It's just that you don't have to do nearly as much heavy lifting yourself.
只是你不需要自己做那么多繁重的任务。
And here, for instance, in just three lines of code,
例如，在这里，只需要三行代码，
can you generate a massive QR code that people can scan,
你就可以生成一个巨大的二维码供人们扫描，
as you can in a moment with your phones, and actually
就像你可以在瞬间用你的手机做到一样，并且实际上
link to something like a CS50 class.
链接到像 CS50 这样的课程。
So let me go ahead and run python of qr.py.
所以让我运行 python qr.py 命令。
It seems to have run.
它似乎运行成功了。
Let me run code of qr.png, which is the file I created.
让我运行 code qr.png 命令，这是我创建的文件。
I'll close my terminal window, allow you an opportunity
我会关闭我的终端窗口，给你一个机会
to scan this here very CS50 lecture.
来扫描这个 CS50 讲座。
And-- and-- is someone's volume up?
还有——还有——谁的音量开着？
[RICK ASTLEY, "NEVER GONNA GIVE YOU UP"]
[瑞克·阿斯特利，"永远不会让你失望"]
There we go.
好了。
What a perfect ending.
多么完美的结局。
All right.
好的。
That was CS50.
这就是 CS50。
We'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]